MY NAME IS WESLEY SUMPTER.
I'VE ARRANGED FOR THIS VIDEO
TO BE RELEASED
ONLY IN THE EVENT OF MY DEMISE.
SO IF YOU ARE WATCHING THIS,
THEN I HAVE ALREADY
BEEN KILLED.
I WAS LOOKING
INTO THE SUSPICIOUS DEATHS
OF SENATOR TED PAULSON,
SOFTWARE ENGINEER
BRIAN WILLINGHAM,
AND CHICAGO STAR-HERALD
REPORTER DAVID ALCOTT.
THESE MEN WERE ALL KILLED
AS PART OF A CONSPIRACY
TO INFLUENCE THE ENERGY POLICY
OF THE UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT.
ANYTIME I ASKED
TOO MANY QUESTIONS,
I WAS STONEWALLED, THREATENED.
I WENT TO THE ONLY PERSON
I KNEW WHO COULD HELP ME --
A FRIEND WITH CLOSE CONNECTIONS
TO THE FBI --
AND ASKED HIM TO LAUNCH
AN OFFICIAL INVESTIGATION.
IF HIS EXPERIENCES HAVE BEEN
ANYTHING LIKE MINE,
PEOPLE HAVE ALSO
DISMISSED HIS CLAIMS.
MY DEATH IS PROOF
NOT ONLY THAT MY FRIEND AND I
ARE TELLING THE TRUTH,
BUT THAT THESE CONSPIRATORS
WILL GO TO ANY EXTREME
FOR THIS TRUTH
NOT TO COME OUT!
SO YOU'RE TRYING
TO TELL ME
THAT THIS GUY ACTUALLY PREDICTED
HIS OWN MURDER?
WE HAVEN'T FOUND A BODY.
SO, AS FAR AS YOU KNOW,
THIS COULD ALL BE ONE BIG HOAX.
WE HAVE A WITNESS WHO SAYS
THAT HE SAW WESLEY KILLED,
AND THE SHAKY CAMERA WORK
TELLS US
THAT SOMEBODY SHOT THE VIDEO,
AND IT COULD BE THAT SAME
SOMEBODY WHO POSTED IT ONLINE.
WE WANT A C.A.R.T. UNIT TO TRACE
THE I.P. ADDRESS.
MORETTI...
WHY IS THIS
SO IMPORTANT TO YOU?
BECAUSE OUR WITNESS,
THE "FRIEND" THAT WESLEY
MENTIONS IN THE VIDEO,
IS MY FRIEND DANIEL PIERCE,
AND I OWE IT TO HIM
TO PROVE TO EVERYONE
THAT HE'S NOT AS CRAZY
AS EVERYBODY THINKS.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
Doctor: HELLO?
HELLO?
THE FOOD IN THIS PLACE
IS INEDIBLE.
IF I'M STILL SEEING YOU,
THEN THE DRUGS ARE LOUSY, TOO.
THERE'S NOT MUCH I CAN DO
ABOUT THE FOOD, I'M AFRAID,
BUT IF THE MEDS
AREN'T WORKING,
I CAN SEE ABOUT TWEAKING
YOUR DOSAGE.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
NATALIE,
WHAT'S WITH THE GETUP?
IT'S NOT LIKE
YOU HAVE TO BLEND IN.
No one else can see you.
WHO'S NATALIE?
I'M CAROLINE NEWSOME.
I'M A PSYCHIATRIST.
YOU'RE AT HUBBARD
MEMORIAL CENTER.
W-W-WAIT.
WHY ARE YOU
MESSING WITH ME?
NO ONE'S MESSING WITH YOU,
DR. PIERCE.
YOU CHECKED YOURSELF IN
TWO DAYS AGO,
PRESENTING WITH ACUTE SYMPTOMS
OF PARANOID SCHIZOPHRENIA.
I KNOW MY [BLEEP] DIAGNOSIS.
I'VE BEEN LIVING WITH IT
FOR 25 YEARS.
I KNOW THIS IS DIFFICULT
FOR YOU.
I'M JUST TRYING TO HELP.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
YOU'RE PRETENDING
TO BE SOMEBODY ELSE...
SO THAT I'LL REALIZE THAT --
THAT NONE OF THIS IS REAL.
THIS WHOLE THING'S
A DELUSION.
DR. PIERCE?
Shh!
DR. PIERCE!
[ PANTING ]
LEWICKI.
LEWICKI!
DOC. WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TELL ME WHERE I AM.
DR. PIERCE,
COME BACK TO YOUR ROOM.
YOU'RE IN THE HOSPITAL,
DOC, OKAY?
I JUST BROUGHT YOU
SOME PUZZLES.
ARE THERE
OTHER PEOPLE HERE?
YES, THERE'S A BUNCH
OF PEOPLE.
T-THERE'S ORDERLIES AND NURSES
AND THE DOCTOR HERE.
YOU CAN SEE HER?
YES, I CAN SEE HER.
DESCRIBE HER TWHAT?
TELL ME
WHAT SHE LOOKS LIKE!
Caroline:
20cc OF VALIUM, STAT.
OKAY, THE DOCTOR HERE
I-I-IS BLONDE WITH BLUE EYES --
NO, NO, NO.
NO. NO.
IF YOU CAN SEE HER,
THEN THAT MEANS
YOU'RE NOT REAL, EITHER.
NONE OF THIS IS REAL!
I'M SORRY.
I HAD TO DO THAT.
BUT THIS IS WHAT YOU HIRED ME
FOR, REMEMBER, DOC?
TO KEEP YOU STRAIGHT.
TO TELL YOU WHAT IS REAL
AND WHAT ISN'T.
NOW, I'M TELLING YOU, DOC,
YOU'RE IN THE HOSPITAL,
AND YOU'RE HAVING
A ROUGH TIME.
BUT THE LADY HERE
IS GONNA MAKE YOU BETTER.
OKAY?
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
YOU A GONNA BE ABLE
TO HELP HIM, AREN'T YOU?
HE SHOULD IMPROVE ONCE
THE ANTI-PSYCHOTICS KICK IN.
HE THOUGHT THAT I WAS SOMEONE
NAMED NATALIE.
DO YOU KNOW WHO THAT IS?
[ SIGHS ]
NATALIE IS ONE OF
DOC'S HALLUCINATIONS.
HE TALKS TO HER ALL THE TIME
ABOUT HIS PROBLEMS,
HIS CASES.
AS WEIRD AS IT SOUNDS,
SHE'S HIS BEST FRIEND.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
EXCUSE ME, DR. NEWSOME.
THERE'S A WOMAN HERE
WITH THE FBI.
SHE INSISTS ON SEEING
DR. PIERCE.
HE'S RESTING NOW.
I'M HOPING HE'LL BE READY FOR
VISITORS IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
NOPE.
I NEED TO SEE HIM TODAY.
I'M SURE YOU'RE JUST TRYING
TO DO YOUR JOB,
BUT MY JOB IS TO TAKE CARE
OF MY PATIENT.
LISTEN, I FOUND OUT
THAT THE BIG DELUSION
THAT LANDED DANIEL
IN THIS PLACE
MIGHT NOT HAVE BEEN A DELUSION
AFTER ALL.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
DANIEL CLAIMED TO HAVE
WITNESSED A MURDER,
BUT NOBODY BELIEVED HIM
BECAUSE THERE WAS NO EVIDENCE
OF A CRIME,
BUT NOW WE HAVE
STRONG INDICATIONS
THAT WHAT DANIEL SAW
WAS REAL.
HE NEEDS TO KNOW THAT.
WITNESSING
SUCH A VIOLENT ACT
MAY BE THE REASON
HE DECOMPENSATED SO QUICKLY.
RELIVING THAT INCIDENT RIGHT NOW
WOULDN'T BE GOOD FOR HIM.
DUE RESPECT,
YOU DON'T KNOW DANIEL --
I DO.
KNOWING THAT WHAT HE SAW
WAS REAL
MIGHT HELP HIM
GET HIS DIGNITY BACK.
IT MIGHT HELP HIM
START TO GET BETTER.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN,
BUT I'M HIS DOCTOR,
AND I'LL DECIDE
WHEN HE'S STABLE ENOUGH
TO TALK ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
MORETTI.
GOT THE I.P. ADDRESS.
VIDEO WAS POSTED FROM
AN INTERNET CAFé IN EVANSTON.
Well, so,
anybody could've sent it.
I CHECKED CREDIT-CARD PURCHASES
AT THE CAFé.
SOMEONE NAMED ALEX WILLINGHAM
BOUGHT A DECAF MOCHA
10 MINUTES BEFORE THE VIDEO
WAS UPLOADED.
THAT'S THE SAME LAST NAME
AS THE SOFTWARE ENGINEER
WHO COMMITTED SUICIDE.
I RAN A SEARCH.
GOT A PRETTY GOOD IDEA
OF WHERE WE CAN FIND HIM.
[ SCHOOL BELL RINGS,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
THANK YOU.
ALEX?
ALEX WILLINGHAM?
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
WHERE YOU GOING
IN SUCH A HURRY, KID, HUH?
I'M AGENT MORETTI.
THIS IS AGENT PROBERT, FBI.
WE JUST WANT TO ASK YOU
A COUPLE QUESTIONS.
I DIDN'T WANT TO DO IT.
DIDN'T WANT TO DO WHAT?
I KILLED WESLEY.
ME AND MY DAD,
I MEAN, IT WAS JUST US
AFTER MY MOM LEFT LAST YEAR.
Kate:
THAT MUST'VE BEEN TOUGH.
YEAH.
THEN HE STARTED
HAVING TROUBLE AT WORK.
WHAT KIND OF TROUBLE?
HE WOULDN'T TELL ME.
BUT HE WAS NERVOUS
ALL THE TIME.
ACTING FUNNY.
THEY SAID
THAT HE KILLED HIMSELF,
BUT I KNEW THAT
HE WOULD NEVER DO THAT.
YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT?
SOMEBODY KILLED HIM.
BECAUSE OF WHATEVER WAS GOING ON
AT HIS WORK.
BESIDES YOUR DAD'S
UNUSUAL BEHAVIOR,
DO YOU HAVE REASON
TO BELIEVE
THAT ANYONE AT HIS WORK
COULD'VE BEEN INVOLVED
IN HIS DEATH?
WELL, I STARTED
GOOGLING VERTERON,
AND I FOUND THESE BLOG POSTS
FROM SOMEONE CALLED
"TRUTH BOMB."
AND HE SAID THAT VERTERON
HAD MESSED WITH THE SOFTWARE
IN THE SENATOR'S PLANE
TO MAKE IT CRASH
AND THAT MY DAD WAS KILLED
BECAUSE HE FOUND OUT.
TRUTH BOMB WAS WESLEY.
YEAH.
I MEAN, HE TOLD ME THAT MY DAD
DIDN'T KILL HIMSELF,
THAT HE WAS A HERO,
AND HE WAS GONNA EXPOSE
ALL THESE BAD PEOPLE.
WE JUST NEEDED TO FIND EVIDENCE
TO PROVE IT.
AND DID YOU?
WE GOT THIS REPORTER
TO HELP US.
BUT THEN HE DIED
IN A CAR WRECK,
SO WESLEY GOT THIS IDEA
TO TALK WITH SOME GUY
THAT WORKED WITH THE FBI.
DANIEL PIERCE.
WESLEY TOLD ME
THAT IF HE WAS MURDERED,
IT WOULD CONVINCE
THIS PIERCE GUY
THAT THERE REALLY WAS
SOME BIG CONSPIRACY.
THE FBI WOULD HAVE TO
INVESTIGATE IT.
I MEAN,
I TOLD HIM "NO WAY."
I COULDN'T KILL ANYBODY...
ESPECIALLY NOT HIM.
THIS GUY WAS MY FRIEND.
[ BREATHES SHAKILY ]
HE SAID IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
TO BRING JUSTICE
FOR MY DAD.
LISTEN, ALEX,
I UNDERSTAND.
[ SNIFFLES ]
OKAY?
I KNOW THAT YOU DID THIS
FOR YOUR DAD.
[ CRYING ]
NOW IT'S TIME TO TELL ME
HOW YOU PULLED IT OFF.
WESLEY GOT THIS GUY TO THE SPOT
WE PICKED OUT.
MY DAD HAD THIS CROSSBOW
FOR DEER HUNTING,
AND WESLEY SAID THE ARROW
WOULDN'T LEAVE ANY BLOOD.
SO I SHOT HIM.
I SHOT AGAIN.
I SCARED
THE OTHER GUY AWAY.
THEN I GOT RID
OF THE SECOND ARROW.
WHAT ABOUT THE BODY?
WESLEY GOT THIS IDEA...
TO BURY A TARP
UNDER THE DIRT...
[ SNIFFLES ]
SO ALL I WOULD HAVE TO DO
WAS ROLL UP WESLEY...
DRAG THE BODY AWAY.
[ CRIES ] PLEASE...
PLEASE...
YOU HAVE TO FIND THE TRUTH
ABOUT WHAT REALLY HAPPENED
TO MY DAD.
OTHERWISE...
...I KILLED WESLEY
FOR NOTHING.
Caroline:
GOOD MORNING.
HEY.
DO YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
YOU'RE NOT NATALIE.
I GET IT, OKAY?
GOOD.
WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS?
CAROLINE NEWSOME.
AND WE NEVER MET
AT A CONFERENCE OR...
I'D HAVE REMEMBERED.
I'M VERY FAMILIAR
WITH YOUR WORK.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO GETTING TO KNOW YOU.
NOW THAT YOUR MEDS
SEEM TO BE WORKING,
I'D LIKE TO START YOU
ON SOME INDIVIDUAL COUNSELING,
AS WELL AS GROUP.
[ SCOFFS ] OKAY, LET'S GET
SOMETHING STRAIGHT --
UH, I'M NOT HERE TO GET IN TOUCH
WITH MY FEELINGS.
I'M HERE FOR THE MEDS
AND TO GET STABLE,
AND THEN I'M GETTING
THE [BLEEP] OUT,
WHICH IS EXACTLY WHAT YOU CAN DO
RIGHT NOW.
I'LDON'T COME BACK.R.
YOU HEAR ME?
DON'T COME BACK!
I DON'T WANT
TO TALK TO YOU!
MR. LEWICKI.
YOU WOULDN'T BE TRYING
TO DUCK ME, WOULD YOU?
NO. NO, SIR.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
THEN WHY HAVEN'T YOU RETURNED
MY PHONE CALLS?
YOU WOULDN'T BE ATTEMPTING
TO COVER UP THE REASON
PROFESSOR PIERCE HAS
CANCELED CLASSES TWO DAYS
IN A ROW, WOULD YOU?
Y-YOU SEE, UH, SIR,
P-PROFESSOR PIERCE
HAD TO TAKE A LITTLE TRIP.
MR. LEWICKI,
I ADMIRE YOUR LOYALTY
TO MY FRIEND DANIEL PIERCE,
BUT I HAVE KNOWN HIM
SINCE YOU WERE WEARING HUGGIES.
NOW TELL ME WHERE HE IS.
I'M AFRAID DR. PIERCE
IS REFUSING ALL VISITORS.
[ SIGHS ]
STUBBORN [BLEEP]
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
LIKE THIS.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
KNOWN HIM?
WE WERE
COLLEGE ROOMMATES.
HE'S BEEN PRETTY RESISTANT
TO THERAPY.
WOULD YOU MIND ANSWERING
SOME QUESTIONS?
NOT AT ALL.
DOES HE HAVE A FRIEND
NAMED NATALIE?
YEAH. SHE WAS DANIEL'S
GIRLFRIEND BACK IN THE DAY.
MM.
WHAT WAS SHE LIKE?
[ Chuckling ] YOU KNOW,
FUNNY ENOUGH, I NEVER MET HER.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I THOUGHT --
SEE [CHUCKLES]
DANIEL AND I TAKE
THIS ROAD TRIP, OKAY,
OUR JUNIOR YEAR TO
THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN.
THEIR SPRING FLING?
[ Chuckling ]
A REAL RAGER.
SUNDAY AFTERNOON, I WAKE UP
ON THE FLOOR OF SOME SORORITY,
AND DANIEL IS THERE.
HE'S ALL EXCITED.
HE HAS MET THE GIRL OF
HIS DREAMS AT SOME OTHER PARTY,
BUT, YOU KNOW,
WE HAD FINALS COMING UP,
SO WE HAD TO GET BACK.
BUT HE STARTED A RELATIONSHIP
WITH THIS NATALIE?
MM-HMM.
A REAL LONG-DISTANCE THING.
HE TALKED TO HER FOR HOURS
ON THE PHONE.
HE'D VISIT HER
ON THE WEEKENDS.
BUT THEN HE, UH --
HE STARTED SHOWING SYMPTOMS.
THEN ENDED UP
IN THE HOSPITAL.
THANK YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY HELPFUL.
I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
NOT TO COME BACK.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO HEAR
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY.
OH, I DOUBT THAT
VERY MUCH.
I AM NATALIE.
WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS THIS?
FIRST YOU INSIST
YOU'RE NOT NATALIE,
NOW YOU CLAIM YOU ARE?
I-I-IF THIS IS SOME SORT OF
THERAPEUTIC TECHNIQUE,
YOU DON'T KNOW VERY MUCH
ABOUT TREATING SCHIZOPHRENICS.
I SPOKE TO YOUR FRIEND
PAUL HALEY.
I DON'T WANT YOU TALKING
TO MY FRIENDS.
HE TOLD ME ABOUT A ROAD TRIP
THE TWO OF YOU TOOK
TO THE UNIVERSITY
OF MSO?IGAN.
I WENT TO MICHIGAN.
I THINK
YOU MUST'VE SEEN ME.
YES.
I GOT SEPARATED FROM PAUL,
AND I ENDED UP
AT THIS FRATERNITY
WITH THIS BUNCH
OF IDIOTS.
THEY WERE --
THEY WERE PLAYING QUARTERS
AND ACTING LIKE [BLEEP]
SO I WENT OUTSIDE...
AND I SAW YOU.
YOU WERE STANDING THERE
ALL BY YOURSELF
AND NURSING A BEER
IN A PLASTIC CUP.
YOU BRUSHED THIS LOOSE STRAND
OF HAIR BEHIND YOUR EAR,
AND I THOUGHT,
"THAT'S THE MOST BEAUTIFUL GIRL
I'VE EVER SEEN."
AND I ALMOST WALKED AWAY,
BUT THEN...
THIS VOICE IN MY HEAD
KEPT TELLING ME,
"DANIEL,
DON'T BE AN IDIOT.
"YOU'LL NEVER SEE
THIS GIRL AGAIN,
AND YOU'LL REGRET IT FOR THE
REST OF YOUR PATHETIC LIFE."
SO -- SO I WALKED --
[LAUGHS]
I WALKED OVER THERE,
AND -- AND -- AND I COULD
BARELY GET MY NAME OUT,
AND YOU LAUGHED AND MADE
SOME JOKE ABOUT ENGLISH
BEING MY SECOND LANGUAGE,
AND -- AND WE -- WE ENDED UP
OUT ON THE GREEN,
JUST -- JUST TALKING A-AND
LAUGHING AND HOLDING HANDS,
TALKING ABOUT RILKE
AND THE SMITHS.
REMEMBER?
TILL --
TILL THE SUN CAME UP.
I WAS AT THAT PARTY.
BUT I NEVER MET YOU.
HOW COULD YOU FORGET?
I DIDN'T FORGET.
I WAS TOO SCARED
TO TALK TO YOU.
SO THAT VOICE IN MY HEAD
WAS THE BEGINNING.
I WAS LOSING MY MIND
EARLIER THAN I THOUGHT.
I'M SORRY.
I'D LIKE TO BE ALONE NOW.
OKAY. THANKS.
HENDERSON, FROM
THE WHITE-COLLAR TASK FORCE.
TURNS OUT THERE WAS
AN INVESTIGATION
OF ILLEGAL ACTIVITY
AT VERTERON.
SO MAYBE THE KID WAS RIGHT
ABOUT HIS FATHER.
WHY DO YOU LOOK LIKE SOMEBODY
JUST KILLED YOUR CAT?
BECAUSE ALEX'S FATHER DIDN'T
STUMBLE ONTO SOME CONSPIRACY
TO RIG AN ELECTION --
HE WAS THE TARGET
OF AN INVESTIGATION.
TURNS OUT HE WAS
SELLING SOFTWARE CODE
TO VERTERON'S COMPETITORS,
AND ON THE DAY HE DIED,
HE WAS FIRED
AND TOLD THAT
HE WAS GONNA BE PROSECUTED.
WHICH EXPLAINS
WHY HE OFFED HIMSELF.
DO YOU HAVE
THE ACCIDENT REPORT?
YEAH.
THEY FOUND A DENT
AND PAINT TRANSFER
ON THE REAR BUMPER
OF THE REPORTER'S CAR.
SO MAYBE SOMEBODY WAS TRYING
TO RUN HIM OFF THE ROAD.
KEEP READING.
THE GUY'S GIRLFRIEND
TOLD THE COPS
THAT SHE BACKED IT UP
INTO A STANCHION
AT THE SUPERMARKET
THE WEEK BEFORE.
DID YOU CORROBORATE THAT?
KATE, WE'RE FBI AGENTS.
WE ARE NOT TRAFFIC COPS.
[ SIGHS ]
LOOK, I KNOW YOU CARE
ABOUT PIERCE,
BUT...I CARE ABOUT YOU,
AND I'M STARTING TO WORRY
THAT HE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE
THAT NEEDS
A MENTAL-HEALTH DAY.
MAYBE I AM
A LITTLE OBSESSED.
SO, YOU KNOW,
LET'S KNOCK OFF.
GET A COUPLE OF BEERS
AND SOME BURGERS.
YOU GO AHEAD.
I'LL, UH, I'LL CATCH UP.
YOU'RE GONNA CALL
THE GUY'S GIRLFRIEND
THE SECOOH, YEAH.E, RIGHT?
MISS CRANE,
WE'RE VERY SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT DAVID WAS
WORKING ON BEFORE HE DIED?
HE WAS PARANOID
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
PARANOID IN WHAT WAY?
HE THOUGHT PEOPLE
WERE AFTER HIM.
WHAT PEOPLE?
I DON'T KNOW.
MISS CRANE,
THE POLICE HAVE RULED
YOUR BOYFRIEND'S DEATH
AN ACCIDENT,
BUT IF YOU HAVE REASON
TO BELIEVE OTHERWISE
AND YOU DON'T TELL US,
YOU CAN BE CHARGED
WITH OBSTRUCTION
AND ACCESSORY
AFTER THE FACT.
I'M NOT SAYING
IT'S TRUE, OKAY?
BUT IF I DID SOMETHING BAD
TO HELP DAVID
AND THAT SOMETHING BAD
GOT HIM KILLED
[Voice breaking] CAN YOU,
YOU KNOW...PROTECT ME?
MISS CRANE, IF YOU HAVE
KNOWLEDGE OF A CRIME
THAT PUTS YOU IN DANGER,
WE WIL KEEP YOU SAFE.
I WORK...
FOR THE PHONE COMPANY,
AND DAVID WANTED THE ACCESS CODE
TO SOME GUY'S VOICEMAIL
SO HE COULD LISTEN
TO HIS MESSAGES.
DAVID SAID
THAT THIS WAS THE STORY
THAT COULD MAKE HIS CAREER,
SO I GAVE HIM THE CODE,
AND WHATEVER HE HEARD
GOT HIM DRIVEN OFF THE ROAD.
WHY DID YOU TELL THE POLICE
THAT YOU WERE THE ONE
THAT DENTED THE CAR?
BECAUSE WHOEVER IS OUT THERE
THAT KILLED DAVID,
IF THEY FIND OUT WHAT I DID,
THEY MIGHT KILL ME, TOO.
LAURA...WHOSE VOICEMAIL
DID DAVID LISTEN TO?
A MAN NAMED LEO ATTINGER.
LEO ATTINGER IS THE NEW
SENATOR'S CHIEF OF STAFF.
Leo:
SO, WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH A STAR-HERALD REPORTER
NAMED DAVID ALCOTT --
HE DIED RECENTLY
IN A CAR ACCIDENT?
YEAH, I HEARD ABOUT THAT.
WE'RE INVESTIGATING
ALLEGATIONS
THAT HE WAS
HACKING CELLPHONES,
AND WE BELIEVE THAT
YOU MAY HAVE BEEN A VICTIM.
SO THAT EXPLAINS IT.
EXPLAINS WHAT?
AFTER THE PLANE CRASH,
THERE WAS SPECULATION
THAT THE GOVERNOR
WOULD APPOINT HELEN PAULSON,
THE SENATOR'S WIDOW,
TO SERVE OUT HIS TERM,
BUT SHE CALLED
A PRESS CONFERENCE
AND ANNOUNCED THAT SHE WOULDN'T
ACCEPT THE APPOINTMENT.
AND ENDORSED RYLAND,
RIGHT?
WELL, THE NIGHT BEFORE
MRS. PAULSON MADE
THAT ANNOUNCEMENT,
SHE LEFT ME A VERY STRANGE
VOICEMAIL MESSAGE.
SAYING WHAT?
SHE SAID SHE'D GOTTEN
THE FILTHY PACKAGE I'D SENT
AND SHE WAS GONNA WITHDRAW
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION.
DID YOU SEND HER A PACKAGE?
I HAD NO IDEA WHAT SHE WAS
TALKING ABOUT,
BUT HER HUSBAND
WAS RYLAND'S MENTOR,
SO I ASKED RYLAND AND THE REST
OF THE CAMPAIGN STAFF
IF ANYBODY KNEW ANYTHING
ABOUT IT, AND NOBODY DID.
AND YOU THINK DAVID ALCOTT
HEARD THIS VOICEMAIL MESSAGE?
HE CAME TO ME,
INSINUATING THAT
I HAD BLACKMAILED MRS. PAULSON
INTO DROPPING OUT
SO THAT I COULD GET
SENATOR RYLAND ELECTED.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHERE THE [BLEEP]
HE WAS GETTING THAT FROM.
NOW I DO.
YEAH, WELL,
YOU GOT TO ADMIT,
THINGS TURNED OUT PRETTY WELL
FOR YOU AND YOUR CANDIDATE.
WELL...
I'M NOT GONNA LIE TO YOU,
AGENT MORETTI.
IN THE WORLD OF
BARE-KNUCKLED ILLINOIS POLITICS,
STRONG-ARMING A WIDOW OUT
OF ACCEPTING HER HUSBAND'S SEAT
SO THAT I CAN GET
MY GUY THE JOB?
THAT'D BE QUITE A COUP.
BUT...I HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH IT.
WANT A JELLYBEAN?
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
JUST PEACHY, THANKS.
I HAVE TO ADMIT,
I'M CURIOUS.
I WOULD'VE THOUGHT, AFTER
YOU GOT OUT OF THE HOSPITAL,
YOU WOULD'VE GONE LOOKING
FOR NATALIE
AND FOUND OUT
SHE WASN'T REAL.
I KNEW MY PROGNOSIS.
NO CURE,
INEVITABLE RELAPSES,
TERRIBLE SIDE EFFECTS FROM
PRIMITIVE SOUL-SUCKING MEDS.
THE NATALIE I KNEW WOULD'VE
TRIED TO TAKE CARE OF ME.
I COULDN'T STAND
THE THOUGHT OF THAT,
SO I DECIDED IT WAS BETTER
TO HAVE NO CONTACT AT ALL.
BUT YOU DID SEE HER AGAIN.
I'M A CLASSIC CASE.
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
I GOT MY DEGREES.
I WAS TEACHING AND WRITING.
I THOUGHT, "HEY,
I'VE BEATEN THIS THING."
SO YOU WEANED YOURSELF
OFF THE MEDS.
THEN ONE DAY,
THERE'S A KNOCK ON THE DOOR,
AND IT'S NATALIE.
AND SHE SAID, "HEY, YOU.
GUESS WHO JUST GOT
A TEACHING JOB AT CLMU."
[ SCOFFS ]
AND I WAS OVER THE MOON.
BUT AT SOME POINT,
YOU REALIZED THAT
SHE WASN'T REALLY THERE.
WE WERE
AT THE FIELD MUSEUM,
AND I WAS LAUGHING MY [BLEEP]
OFF AT SOMETHING FUNNY
SHE SAID ABOUT
THE PACHYDERM DIORAMA,
AND THIS
LITTLE KID TAPS ME.
HE SAYS, "HEY, MISTER.
WHY ARE YOU TALKING
TO YOURSELF?"
AND I LOOKED AROUND,
AND I...REALIZED THAT EVERYBODY
WAS STARING AT ME
INSTEAD OF THE ELEPHANTS.
THAT MUST'VE BEEN PAINFUL.
I LIKED
HAVING HER AROUND.
EVEN IF IT MEANT GETTING
STARED AT ONCE IN A WHILE.
WHEN THINGS GOT REALLY BAD,
I TRIED THE LATEST DRUG,
AND NATALIE AND THE OTHER
LESS-PLEASANT VISITORS
WOULD GO AWAY.
OR AT LEAST THEY WOULDN'T
COME AROUND AS OFTEN.
AND I'D THINK,
"OKAY, THIS TIME --
THIS TIME
I'VE GOT IT LICKED."
AND THEN THE CYCLE
WOULD START AGAIN.
BUT I ALWAYS BELIEVED
THERE WAS THIS ONE
BEAUTIFUL SUMMER,
BEFORE I BECAME
A COMPLETE WACKO,
WHERE I HAD
WHAT NORMAL PEOPLE HAVE --
SOMEONE TO LOVE.
SOMETHING REAL.
AND NOW I LOOK AT YOU,
THE MOST FAMILIAR STRANGER
I'VE EVER MET...
...AND I KNOW
I NEVER HAD IT AT ALL.
I'M SORRY...
THAT I'M NOT THE PERSON
YOU THOUGHT I WAS.
TRULY.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
TELL ME, DOCTOR,
IN YOUR
PROFESSIONAL OPINION,
WHAT'S MORE SERIOUS --
HALLUCINATING A LIFELONG
FRIENDSHIP THAT NEVER EXISTED
OR WITNESSING A BRUTAL BUT
COMPLETELY IMAGINARY MURDER?
YOUR FRIEND FROM THE FBI CAME BY
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO.
IT TURNS OUT THAT THE CRIME
YOU WITNESSED
ACTUALLY DID HAPPEN.
YOU KNEW THIS,
AND YOU DIDN'T TELL ME?
I DIDN'T WANT
TO SET YOU BACK.
WELL, YOU BLEW THAT GOAL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
DR. PIERCE?
I'M GETTING THE [BLEEP]
OUT OF HERE.
IF YOU LEAVE,
THE CYCLE WILL START AGAIN.
YOU'LL BE BACK,
MAYBE IN A COUPLE OF DAYS,
MAYBE IN SIX MONTHS.
ARE YOU THREATENING TO HAVE ME
LEGALLY COMMITTED?
BECAUSE OTHERWISE,
I'M CALLING A CAB.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
DANIEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I-I WANT BACK IN
ON THIS CASE.
SHOULDN'T YOU BE
IN THE HOSPITAL?
NO, I'M DOING BETTER.
THE MEDS ARE WORKING,
BUT I KNOW MYSELF.
THE BEST TREATMENT
FOR ME RIGHT NOW
IS TO HELP YOU
SOLVE THIS THING.
I DON'T KNOW
IF PLEASE, KATE. --
I NEED YOU
TO LET ME DO THIS.
OKAY.
[ CHUCKLES LIGHTLY ]
COME ON IN.
I'LL MAKE YOU A CUP OF TEA.
Kate: MRS. PAULSON,
LEO ATTINGER SAYS THAT YOU
LEFT HIM AN ANGRY VOICEMAIL
IMPLYING THAT HE'D SENT YOU
SOME SORT OF A PACKAGE
THAT CAUSED YOU TO TURN DOWN
YOUR HUSBAND'S SENATE SEAT?
LEO ATTINGER IS
A REPREHENSIBLE HUMAN BEING
WHO WOULD STEP ON HIS OWN MOTHER
TO ADVANCE HIS CAREER.
I ASSUME THAT WHATEVER
WAS IN THIS PACKAGE
WAS INCRIMINATING
OR EMBARRASSING.
OTHERWISE, YOU WOULD'VE
ALERTED THE AUTHORITIES?
I'M SORRY, AGENT MORETTI.
I CAN'T CONTINUE
THIS CONVERSATION.
MA'AM, IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT DAVID ALCOTT,
A REPORTER
FOR THE STAR-HERALD,
WAS MURDERED FOR PURSUING
A STORY ABOUT THIS.
NOW, PLEASE TELL ME
WHAT YOU KNOW.
[ SIGHS ]
I GOT AN ENVELOPE
IN THE MAIL.
IT HAD A FLASH-DRIVE THING
AND A NOTE.
"IT WOULD BE BETTER
FOR THE PEOPLE OF ILLINOIS
"AND YOUR LATE HUSBAND
"IF YOU TURNED DOWN
THE APPOINTMENT...
AND YOU ENDORSED
SCOTT RYLAND."
WHAT WAS
ON THE FLASH DRIVE?
A VIDEO.
OF TED IN HIS OFFICE...
WITH A WOMAN.
DO YOU KNOW
WHO THE WOMAN WAS?
VICTORIA RYLAND.
THE WIFE
OF THE NEW SENATOR?
Victoria:
LET GO OF ME!
LET GO OF ME!.
ALL RIGHT.
I THOUGHT YOU WANTED TO.
YOU THOUGHT WRONG.
OKAY. OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, BUT NOBODY ELSE
HAS TO KNOW ABOUT THIS, RIGHT?
WHERE DID YOU GET THIS?
Kate:
HELEN PAULSON.
SOMEBODY SENT IT TO HER
TO BLACKMAIL HER
INTO TURNING DOWN
HER HUSBAND'S SENATE SEAT
SO THAT YOUR HUSBAND
COULD RUN IN HIS PLACE.
ARE YOU IMPLYING THAT I HAD
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THAT?
THE MAN TRIED TO RAPE ME.
BUT YOU NEVER REPORTED IT.
[ SCOFFS ]
HE WAS A SENATOR...
AND MY HUSBAND'S HERO.
AND THEN HE DIED
IN A PLANE CRASH.
WHAT WOULD'VE BEEN THE POINT
OF RUINING HIS REPUTATION?
WHAT WERE YOU DOING IN HIS
OFFICE THAT LATE AT NIGHT?
I HAD BEEN TRYING TO GET
A MEETING WITH HIM FOR WEEKS
TO DISCUSS FUNDING
FOR A LITERACY PROGRAM.
WHEN I FINALLY GOT IN
TO SEE HIM,
I-I STARTED TO TALK TO HIM
ABOUT THE PROGRAM.
HE CAME OVER, SAT NEXT TO ME
ON THE COUCH, AND JUST...
POUNCED ON ME.
I-I GOT OUT
AS FAST AS I COULD.
DID ANYBODY
SEE YOU LEAVE?
UH...
LEO ATTINGER.
YOUR HUSBAND'S
CHIEF OF STAFF?
W-WHAT WAS HE DOING THERE?
UM, BEFORE LEO WORKED
FOR SCOTT,
HE WAS AN AIDE
TO SENATOR PAULSON.
WHEN DID YOUR HUSBAND
HIRE HIM?
RIGHT AFTER
SENATOR PAULSON DIED.
EVERYONE THOUGHT
THAT THE GOVERNOR
WAS GOING TO APPOINT
MRS. PAULSON,
BUT LEO CAME TO SCOTT,
SAID HE COULD
GET HIM ELECTED.
UH-HUH.
MR. ATTINGER!
WE WERE JUST HOPING TO ASK YOU
A FEW MORE QUESTIONS,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
I'M A LITTLE BUSY.
WE WANT TO KNOW WHETHER OR NOT
YOU HAD ACCESS
TO ANY OF THE SECURITY TAPES
RECORDED AT
SENATOR PAULSON'S OFFICE
FROM WHEN YOU WORKED THERE.
[ Chuckling ] I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Man: LEO?
HI, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR COMING.
SENATOR, TELL ME.
WERE YOU COMPLICIT IN STEALING
YOUR CONGRESSIONAL SEAT,
OR ARE YOU JUST A PUPPET
FOR THE REAL POWER BROKERS?
I-I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A WALK.
[ SCOFFS ]
I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT,
SENATOR.
LISTEN, UM...
SEND SOMEBODY OUT
TO GET ME A BURGER.
YOU KNOW,
THEY'RE SERVING SALMON.
YOU KNOW
I CAN'T EAT SALMON.
STAY ON SUPPOSED TO HAVE
TOPPEDDANIEL?THINGS.
SENATOR,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[ MUTTERING ]
NO, HE'S NOT ALL RIGHT.
HE'S HAVING A STROKE.
WHAT? NO. SENATOR!
CALL AN AMBULANCE.
Daniel:
RYLAND DIDN'T MAKE IT.
LET'S GIVE THE FAMILY
SOME PRIVACY.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
CAN I HELP YOU?
I'M DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
I WAS THE ONE WHO FIRST NOTICED
THE SENATOR STROKING OUT.
YOU WERE
HIS PERSMM-HMM.YSICIAN?
DID HE HAVE ANY HISTORY
OF STROKENO. CLOTTING?
NOW,
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
ORDER AN AUTOPSY.
TELL THEM TO TEST
FOR CLOTTING AGENTS
THAT COULD'VE CAUSED
A STROKE.
WHY?
YOU DON'T THINK SOMEBODY --
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I'M THINKING.
THERE ARE TOO MANY
BODIES DROPPING
FOR THIS
TO BE A COINCIDENCE.
DANIEL,
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE.
THAT'S WHY WE NEED
A TOX SCREEN, KATE.
I'M TELLING YOU,
SOMEBODY KILLED HIM!
WHAT!?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?!
JUST PLEASE STAY CALM.
Get your crackpot friend
out of here, Agent Moretti.
OF COURSE YOU WANT ME
OUT OF HERE, ATTINGER.
OF COURSE YOU DO!
YOU CAN'T HIDE
THE TRUTH FOREVER!
I'M ONTO YOU, ATTINGER!
DOC, LET ME MAKE YOU
A CUP OF TEA.
I DON'T WANT TEA, LEWICKI.
I WANT ANSWERS!
[ BEEP ]
WELL,
I GOT SOME FOR YOU.
TOX SCREEN CAME BACK NEGATIVE
FOR CLOTTING AGENTS.
THE SENATOR DIED
OF NATURAL CAUSES.
THEY NEED TO CHECK AGAIN.
THIS MORNING, YOU WERE ACCUSING
RYLAND AND HIS AIDES
OF SOME HOMICIDAL CONSPIRACY
TO PUT HIM IN OFFICE.
NOW, IF THAT WAS TRUE,
WHY WOULD SOMEONE TURN AROUND
AND TRY TO KILL HIM?
I DON'T KNOW.
JUST -- SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
DOC...
MAYBE YOU NEED TO GO BACK
TO THE HOSPITAL.
YOU'RE RIGHT, MAX.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I NEED TO DO.
DR. NEWSOME.
I'M GLAD YOU DECIDED
TO COME BACK.
YEAH.
I-I'M NOT CHECKING IN.
I NEED YOU TO BE NATALIE
FOR A WHILE.
HAVE YOU TAKEN
YOUR MEDS TODAY?
YES, I'M TAKING YOUR [BLEEP]
MEDS, WHICH IS IRONIC,
BECAUSE IF I WASN'T
TAKING THEM,
I WOULDN'T BE BACK
IN THE LOONEY BIN.
YOU'RE NOT MAKING
ANY SENSE.
I'M MAKING PERFECT SENSE.
I HAVE A PUZZLE
THAT I CAN'T SOLVE.
NOW, NORMALLY, I WOULD WORK IT
OUT WITH NATALIE,
BUT SHE'S GONE,
SO I NEED YOU TO BE HER.
I'M YOUR DOCTOR.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S ADVISABLE.
PLEASE!
I NEED TO KNOW THAT
MY [BLEEP] BRAIN STILL WORKS,
EVEN WHEN I'M ON THE MEDS.
OTHERWISE, I DON'T --
I DON'T KNOW IF I CAN DO THIS.
THE C.E.O. OF VERTERON
WANTED RYLAND IN,
SO THEY MANIPULATED THE AVIONICS
TO CRASH PAULSON'S PLANE,
THEN, TO TIE UP LOOSE ENDS,
THEY GOT RID OF A REPORTER
AND AN ENGINEER
WHO WERE ONTO THE PLOT.
THEN THE GOVERNOR DECIDES
HE'S GOING TO APPOINT
THE SENATOR'S WIDOW,
SO THEY BLACKMAIL HER
INTO DROPPING OUT,
THEY GET RYLAND ELECTED.
THE ONE THING
I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
IS WHY THEY KILLED RYLAND
WHEN THEY'VE GONE TO ALL THIS
TROUBLE TO PUT HIM IN OFFICE.
THIS SOUNDS LIKE THE KIND
OF PARANOID CONSPIRACY THEORY
THAT LANDED YOU IN THE HOSPITAL
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
BUT I'M NOT DELUSIONAL NOW.
THEN SIMPLIFY
YOUR THINKING.
YOU WENT TO MED SCHOOL.
YOU KNOW OCCAM'S RAZOR.
WHEN FACED
WITH COMPETING HYPOTHESES,
CHOOSE THE ONE THAT MAKES THE
FEWEST NEW ASSUMPTIONS. SO WHAT?
SO YOU'RE MAKING A LOT
OF ASSUMPTIONS
FOR WHICH
YOU HAVE NO EVIDENCE.
WHAT DID YOU ACTUALLY SEE
WITH YOUR OWN EYES?
SENATOR RYLAND, A MAN
WITH NO HISTORY OF CLOTTING,
SIT HAPPENS..
YEAH, BUT SOMETHING IS TELLING
ME IT WASN'T ACCIDENTAL.
A VOICE IN YOUR HEARD?
NO, NOT A VOICE --
NOT IN MY HEAD --
HIS VOICE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
RYLAND --
HE SAID HE COULDN'T EAT SALMON.
WELL, SOME PEOPLE
CAN'T EAT SALMON
BECAUSE OF ADVERSE
DRUG REACTIONS.
YES!
[ SNAPS FINGERS ] YES!
THAT'S GOOD. PEOPLE ON COUMADIN.
AND COUMADIN'S A BLOOD THINNER
USED TO PREVENT STROKES.
YOU SAID HE DIDN'T HAVE
A HISTORY OF CLOTTING.
JOHN KENNEDY COVERED UP
HIS ADDISON'S DISEASE.
RYLAND CERTAINLY WOULDN'T WANT
THE VOTERS KNOWING
THAT HE HAD
A LIFE-THREATENING CONDITION.
ANOTHER ASSUMPTION.
WOULD YOU GO
WITH ME ON THIS?
OKAY, FINE. RYLAND WAS
SECRETLY USING COUMADIN.
THEN HE SHOULDN'T
HAVE STROKED.
HE WOULDN'T BE THE
FIRST PATIENT TO GO OFF
HIS MEDS, WOULD HE?
IF HE WENT OFF HIS MEDS,
WHY WAS HE AVOIDING SALMON?
MAYBE HE DIDN'T KNOW
HE WAS OFF HIS MEDS.
MAYBE SOMEBODY
SWITCHED THEM OUT.
HE'D BE A TICKING
TIME BOMB.
WHO WOULD DO THAT?
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE NOT AS GOOD
AT THIS AS NATALIE...
BUT YOU ARE NOT HALF BAD.
Woman:
SOURCES CLOSE TO THE GOVERNOR
SAY HE INTENDS TO APPOINTMENT
VICTORIA RYLAND TO SERVE OUT
HER LATE HUSBAND'S TERM.
YOU SEE? I'M RIGHT.
I'M RIGHT!
SHE KILLED HER HUSBAND
TO GET HIS SENATE SEAT!
HOW COULD SHE EVEN BE SURE
THAT THEY GOVERNOR
WOULD APPOINT HER?
HE WAS GONNA APPOINT PAULSON'S
WIDOW WHEN HE DIED.
IT'S A LONG-STANDING
TRADITION.
OF THE 200 WOMEN THAT HAVE
EVER SERVED IN CONGRESS,
OVER 40 WERE
CONGRESSMEN'S WIDOWS.
DON'T TELL ME TO CALM DOWN.
I SEE IT NOW.
THIS WASN'T SOME --
SOME GRAND CONSPIRACY
TO MURDER PAULSON
AND RIG THE ELECTION.
THIS WAS THE WORK
OF ONE VERY CLEVER,
VERY AMBITIOUS WOMAN.
WHAT?
I JUST TALKED TO MY FRIEND
IN I.T.B.
SHE RAN A DISCREET CREDIT CHECK
ON VICTORIA RYLAND.
TURNS OUT SHE HAD THE FRONT
OF HER CAR REPAIRED
THE DAY AFTER THE REPORTER
WAS RUN OFF THE ROAD.
THAT'S -- THAT'S PROOF.
WHY DO YOU LOOK SO DEPRESSED?
BECAUSE IT'S CIRCUMSTANTIAL.
GET A WARRANT.
YOU WILL FIND
THAT THE RYLANDS
WERE BUYING COUMADIN
FROM MEXICO,
AND -- AND THAT LITTLE
PRESCRIPTION BOTTLE YOU FIND
WILL BE FILLED
WITH FAKE PILLS.
NO JUDGE IS GONNA GIVE ME
A FISHING LICENSE
TO GO AFTER A WOMAN
WHO'S ABOUT TO BE A SENATOR.
YOU'RE TELLING ME THERE'S A
WOMAN WHO MURDERED HER HUSBAND
TO GET A SEAT IN
THE UNITED STATES SENATE,
AND THERE'S NOTHING WE CAN DO
ABOUT IT?
I REFUSE TO ACCEPT THAT.
DANIEL, JUST PROMISE ME YOU'RE
NOT GONNA DO ANYTHING CRAZY.
[ SIGHS ]
I'D LIKE SPEAK
TO MRS. RYLAND, PLEASE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO MAKE
AN APPOINTMENT.
WILL YOU PLEASE TELL
THE SENATOR IN WAITING
THAT IF SHE CARES AT ALL
ABOUT HER POLITICAL FUTURE,
SHE'LL SEE ME NOW?
IT'S ALL RIGHT, JOHN.
SHOW DR. PIERCE
TO MY STUDY.
I'M SORRY ABOUT
YOUR HUSBAND'S DEATH.
THANK YOU.
BUT I KNOW
YOU KILLED HIM.
YOU WENT TO SENATOR PAULSON'S
OFFICE TO SEDUCE HIM.
WHEN HE RESPONDED, YOU ACTED
LIKE YOU WERE BEING RAPED.
WE ASSUMED IT WAS
SECURITY FOOTAGE,
BUT I'M BETTING YOU TAPED
THE WHOLE THING
ON YOUR CELLPHONE.
YOU WERE PROBABLY INTENDING
TO BLACKMAIL THE SENATOR
INTO NOT RUNNING
FOR RE-ELECTION,
BUT WHEN HIS PLANE CRASHED,
YOU SAW AN OPPORTUNITY.
YOU BLACKMAILED HIS WIFE INSTEAD
SO YOUR HUSBAND COULD RUN.
WHEN SOME REPORTER
STARTED ASKING QUESTIONS,
YOU RAN HIM OFF THE ROAD.
THEN, ONCE YOUR HUSBAND
GOT ELECTED,
YOU SWITCHED HIS COUMADIN
WITH SUGAR PILLS
AND WAITED FOR HIM
TO STROKE OUT.
IF I WASN'T IN MOURNING,
I MIGHT EVEN FIND THAT FUNNY.
THE FBI FOUND
YOUR CAR-REPAIR BILL.
AND IF THAT WERE EVIDENCE
OF A CRIME,
THE FBI WOULD BE HERE --
NOT YOU.
[ LAUGHS ] YEAH, WELL,
THAT'S TRUE. THAT'S TRUE.
EVERYBODY AT THE FBI THINKS
I'M CRAZY, WHICH I AM.
AND THEY WOULDN'T TOUCH
THIS ANYWAY.
IT'S A POLITICAL
MINE FIELD.
THEN WHY ARE YOU HERE?
BECAUSE I MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO SEND YOU TO PRISON,
BUT I CAN [BLEEP] WELL
STOP A MURDERER
FROM BECOMING A SENATOR.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
UNLESS YOU CALL
A PRESS CONFERENCE
ANNOUNCING YOUR INTENTION
TO TURN DOWN
THE GOVERNOR'S APPOINTMENT,
I'M GONNA GO TO THE STAR-HERALD
WITH MY OWN STORY.
"DR. DANIEL PIERCE
"IS RESIGNING HIS CONSULTING
POSITION WITH THE FBI
"BECAUSE THE BUREAU REFUSES
TO INVESTIGATE ALLEGATIONS
"THAT VICTORIA RYLAND
MURDERED HER HUSBAND
TO SECURE A SENATE SEAT."
NO PAPER WILL RUN
THREALLY?Y.
YOU CARE TO BET YOUR REPUTATION
AND YOUR CAREER ON THAT?
YOU KILLED ONE OF
THEIR OWN REPORTERS.
THEY MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO PIN A CRIME ON YOU,
BUT THEY'LL START ASKING
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE RAPE VIDEO
AND WHY YOU
AND YOUR HUSBAND
WERE BUYING COUMADIN
FROM MEXICO.
SO, YOU CAN BOW OUT
GRACEFULLY...
OR YOU CAN GET DRAGGED
THROUGH THE MUD.
I'M GONNA BE AT THE STAR-HERALD
AT 9:00 A.M.
IF YOU HAVEN'T SPOKEN TO
THE PRESS BY THEN, I WILL.
AND I'LL GIVE THEM
THE STORY OF THE DECADE.
I CAN SEE MYSELF OUT.
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ ENGINE REVS ]
[ SIREN WAILS ]
[ WAILING STOPS ]
OUT OF THE CAR!
HANDS WHERE I CAN SEE THEM!
YOU OKAY?
AHH.
YEAH, I'M GOOD.
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
WHAT DID YOU DO
TO MY BIKE?!
[ SIGHS ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
HOW'S IT GOING?
IF YOU'RE ASKING ME
IF I'M OFF MY ROCKER,
THE ANSWER IS...
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
WE SERVED A SEARCH WARRANT
ON VICTORIA.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
WE FOUND COUMADIN BOTTLES
FILLED WITH SUGAR PILLS.
U.S. ATTORNEY'S CHARGING HER
WITH BOTH MURDERS.
GREAT.
SO WE'LL HAVE ANOTHER
SPECIAL ELECTION,
AND WE'LL GET
SOME OTHER CRIMINAL
REPRESENTING US
IN WASHINGTON.
WELL,
IF IT WASN'T FOR YOU,
SHE WOULD'VE
GOTTEN AWAY WITH IT.
IT'S WESLEY
THAT DESERVES THE CREDIT.
IF HE DIDN'T COME TO ME
WITH HIS WILD CONSPIRACY THEORY,
NOBODY WOULD'VE EVER LOOKED
BEHIND THE CURTAIN.
SO MAYBE HE DIDN'T DIE
FOR NOTHING.
THANK YOU...
FOR NOT GIVING UP ON ME,
EVEN WHEN I WAS AT MY WORST.
YOU GAVE ME A SCARE,
YOU KNOW.
I KNOW.
I KNOW, AND EVEN THOUGH
I'M DOING BETTER,
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE THAT
MY SYMPTOMS WON'T COME BACK,
SO I-I UNDERSTAND IF YOU DON'T
WANT ME WORKING CASES.
LET'S MAKE A DEAL.
NO MORE SECRETS.
YOUR SYMPTOMS COME BACK,
YOU TELL ME.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ CLICK, MUSIC STOPS ]
DR. NEWSOME.
I'M ASSUMING YOUR FIRM GRASP
ON REALITY
MEANS THAT YOU'RE TAKING
YOUR MEDS.
YEAH,
I THOUGHT A PILL A DAY
WAS SUPPOSED TO KEEP
THE DOCTOR AWAY.
MAX TOLD ME
WHERE TO FIND YOU.
I CAME BY TO SAY
THAT THE MEDS AREN'T ENOUGH.
IF YOU WANT
TO STAY HEALTHY,
YOU'RE GONNA NEED
REGULAR TALK THERAPY.
AND APPARENTLY,
YOU MAKE HOUSE CALLS.
ACTUALLY,
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
GIVEN YOUR
LONG-STANDING...
RELATIONSHIP WITH NATALIE,
I DON'T THINK
IT'S APPROPRIATE
FOR ME TO CONTINUE TO BE
YOUR PSYCHIATRIST.
WELL, MAYBE YOU CAN
RECOMMEND SOMEBODY
WHO'S NOT
AN INSUFFERABLE BORE.
JUST BECAUSE I CAN'T BE
YOUR DOCTOR
DOESN'T MEAN
I CAN'T BE YOUR FRIEND.
IF YOU NEED ONE.
I CAN'T HELP WONDERING...
IF I HAD ACTUALLY
HAD THE NERVE
TO APPROACH YOU
ALL THOSE YEARS AGO,
WOULD YOU HAVE GIVEN ME
THE TIME OF DAY?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT ONE THING YOU'LL FIND OUT
PRETTY QUICK
IS THAT I'M NOBODY'S
FANTASY GIRL.
47 ACROSS -- PARASOL.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
UM, IF WE'RE
GONNA BE FRIENDS,
ONE THING YOU'LL FIGURE OUT
PRETTY QUICK
IS THAT I MAY NEED HELP
ONCE IN A WHILE,
BUT I REALLY HATE IT WHEN PEOPLE
GIVE ME THE ANSWERS.
SOMETIMES
THE BILLIONS OF NEURONS
FIRING IN OUR BRAINS HELP US
CONCOCT ELABORATE SCENARIOS.
WE IMAGINE OURSELVES
WITH A DREAM GIRL
OR LANDING A DREAM JOB --
AN ASTRONAUT, ROCK STAR,
EVEN A UNITED STATES SENATOR.
BUT FANTASIES CAN TURN DARK.
WE START TO BELIEVE
THERE'S A MONSTER UNDER THE BED
OR THAT EVIL FORCES ARE ALIGNING
THEMSELVES AGAINST US.
ALL THESE FANTASIES --
GOOD AND BAD --
STEM FROM
AN EVOLUTIONARY IMPERATIVE.
OUR BRAINS ARE EXPLORING
POTENTIAL OUTCOMES
THAT MIGHT HELP US ACHIEVE
OUR GOALS OR AVOID DANGER.
BUT IF WE ALLOW FANTASY
TO OVERTAKE OUR THINKING...
...WE CAN MISS THE REALITY
THAT'S RIGHT IN FRONT OF US.
AND SOMETIMES...
REALITY'S NOT SO BAD.