Daniel: ONE DAY OF THE WEEK
I HAVE NO LECTURES,
NO OFFICE HOURS,
NO OBLIGATIONS OF ANY KIND...
...THE ONE DAY THAT I-I GET
A LITTLE SOLITUDE, YOU KNOW,
A LITTLE "ME" TIME, A CHANCE
TO DO SOME ACTUAL WRITING.
HALEY TWISTED MY ARM.
YOUR ARM IS MINE TO TWIST,
NOT HALEY'S.
DID HE EVEN SAY
WHAT THIS WAS ABOUT?
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING ]
DANIEL, IT IS MY HONOR
TO INFORM YOU
THAT YOU HAVE BEEN AWARDED
THIS YEAR'S DAVENPORT PRIZE
FOR EXPLORATION IN SCIENCE.
I-I SWEAR,
I KNEW NOTHING ABOUT THIS.
AND, AS I'M SURE
YOU ARE AWARE,
THIS AWARD IS NOT JUST
ABOUT THE LAURELS
YOU BRING TO YOURSELF
AND THE UNIVERSITY.
IT'S ALSO ABOUT THE $50,000
CHECK THAT GOES ALONG WITH IT.
TO DANIEL PIERCE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CORK POPS ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS ]
DANIEL.
HOW COULD YOU
BLINDSIDE ME LIKE THAT?
YOU ARE MAKING ME LOOK BAD
IN FRONT OF THE CHANCELLOR.
THE MAN PUT YOU UP FOR THIS
PRIZE, FOR GOODNESS SAKES.
JUST ONE HANDSHAKE.
THAT'S ALL I'M ASKING.
KATE.
PLEASE TELL ME
YOU'RE HERE ABOUT A CASE.
YEPaul: MS. MORETTI,--
I AGREED TO ALLOW DANIEL
TO CONSULT WITH THE FBI
SO LONG AS IT DIDN'T INTERFERE
WITH HIS ACADEMIC DUTIES.
AND RIGHT NOW YOU ARE
INTERFERING WITH --
ACTUALLY, I'M HERE
TO TALK TO YOU.
TO ME?
YEAH, LISTEN, A JOGGER
WAS FOUND SHOT IN THE BACK
IN THE NATIONAL FOREST
PRESERVE.
WE'RE HAVING TROUBLE
MAKING AN I.D.
THERE'S NO WALLET ON HIM,
NO MATCH ON THE FINGERPRINTS.
WHAT HAS THIS GOT TO DO
WITH HIM?
ALL WE'VE GOT TO GO ON
ARE SOME TATTOOS
ON THE BODY
WHICH APPEAR TO BE
RELIGIOUS IN NATURE,
AND DEAN HALEY'S COURSE
ON SPIRITUAL ICONOGRAPHY
WAS ONE OF THE BEST CLASSES
I EVER TOOK.
I'M FLATTERED
YOU REMEMBER.
ANYHOW, I'M HOPING YOU COULD
TAKE A LOOK AT THE TATTOOS,
LET ME KNOW IF THERE'S
ANYTHING ABOUT THEM
THAT COULD HELP ME
I.D. THE VICTIM.
I CONFESS I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
SOMETHING
OF AN ARMCHAIR DETECTIVE.
PAUL, YOU COULDN'T POSSIBLY.
THE CHANCELLOR.
I JUST TELL HIM THAT
IT'S A MURDER
INVESTIGATION, RIGHT?
COME ON, DANIEL.
YOU'LL NEED TO KEEP HIM
ENTERTAINED WHILE I'M GONE.
Help me.
WH-- UH, DEAN HALEY, UH,
ACTUALLY,
OUR VICTIM MAY HAVE SUFFERED
SOME HEAD INJURIES,
SO I DO NEED A BRAIN SPECIALIST
TO REVIEW THE X-RAYS.
YOU COULDN'T POSSIBLY SPARE
DANIEL, UH, JUST FOR AN HOUR?
I'M SURE THE CHANCELLOR
WILL UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS VERY EXCITING.
[ RETCHING ]
[ SPITTING ]
OH.
[ SNIFFS ]
PROBABLY A LITTLE
TOO MUCH BUBBLY
AT THE RECEPTION,
I THINK.
OKAY. UM, LET'S SEE
WHAT WE'VE GOT HERE.
WELL, THE ANGEL APPEARS TO DRAW
FROM CHRISTIAN INFLUENCES,
BUT THESE EIGHT WINGS
PROBABLY REPRESENT
THE EIGHT ARMS OF SHIVA,
THE HINDU GOD
OF DESTRUCTION.
AH. UH-HUH.
WHICH WOULD MAKE
THIS SIMIAN FIGURE
REPRESENTATIVE OF HANUMAN,
THE HINDU MONKEY GOD.
AND I'D SAY THESE NUMBERS
REPRESENT
THE BOOK OF RUTH,
CHAPTER 1, VERSE 16.
"THY PEOPLE
SHALL BE MY PEOPLE."
THE WORDS NAOMI SPOKE
WHEN CONVERTING TO THE FAITH
OF HER MOTHER-IN-LAW.
SO, YOU PROBABLY
WANT TO MAKE INQUIRIES
AT A LOCAL HINDU TEMPLE
FREQUENTED BY CONVERTS FROM
THE JUDEO-CHRISTIAN TRADITION.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO INQUIRE
AT A LOCAL METHADONE CLINIC.
WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
I THINK IT'S A PRETTY SAFE BET
YOUR VICTIM HERE WAS A JUNKIE.
"MONKEY ON MY BACK," IS A COMMON
TERM FOR HEROIN ADDICTION.
1:16 IS PROBABLY
A SOBRIETY DATE,
WHICH A LOT OF ADDICTS
TATTOO ON THEIR BODIES.
IF HE GOT SOBER
WITH THE HELP OF METHADONE,
MAYBE SOMEBODY AT A CLINIC
WOULD RECOGNIZE HIM.
OF COURSE, I DON'T WANT TO...
CONTRADICT THE EXPERT.
[ RETCHES ]
Kate: I'M HERE ABOUT YOUR SON,
MRS. BAKER.
WHAT'S JARED DONE NOW?
WELL, HE'S LISTED YOU
AS HIS EMERGENCY CONTACT
ON HIS INTAKE FORM AT
THE 7th STREET METHADONE CLINIC.
YOUR SON'S BODY
WAS FOUND YESTERDAY
IN THE FOREST PRESERVE.
IT APPEARS HE WAS MURDERED.
I'M...VERY SORRY.
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING ME
THE NEWS IN PERSON.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT I WOULD GET A
CALL IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
YOU WERE
EXPECTING THIS?
I TRIED EVERYTHING --
THERAPISTS, REHAB,
A CLINIC IN SWITZERLAND.
BUT WHEN HE TURNED 21 AND CAME
INTO HIS GRANDFATHER'S TRUST,
HE HAD MONEY FOR ALL THE DRUGS
HE COULD POSSIBLY DESIRE.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
FOUR MONTHS AGO,
MAYBE FIVE.
OKAY.
AND DO YOU KNOW
WHERE HE WAS LIVING?
WITH SOME KIND
OF RELIGIOUS CULT.
IT BLED HIM
OF EVERY LAST CENT HE HAD LEFT.
[ Voice breaking ] HE SAID
HE FOUND THE VOICE OF GOD
AND WAS FINALLY
GETTING CLEAN.
SOME GOOD
THE VOICE OF GOD DID HIM.
Kate:
IT'S CALLED HAVEN HOUSE.
LOOKS LIKE
SOME SORT OF COMMUNE.
IT'S ALL CENTERED AROUND
THIS KID -- KYLE JENSEN.
16 YEARS OLD.
THEY SAY HE TALKS
DIRECTLY TO GOD.
AND YOUR VICTIM GAVE ALL
HIS MONEY TO THIS WACKO CULT?
ALMOST $500,000.
WHAT?!
THAT'S THE WAY IT WORKS.
EVERYONE WHO JOINS
GIVES EVERY DIME THEY HAVE.
[ LAUGHS ]
IT'S A HAVEN, ALL RIGHT --
FOR ANYBODY
WITH MONEY IN THE BANK
AND NO BRAIN
IN THEIR SKULL.
I SWEAR, IT -- IT --
IT -- IT STAGGERS ME.
MILLENNIUM
AFTER MILLENNIUM,
NO MATTER HOW MANY OF THESE
CHARLATANS ARE UNMASKED,
PEOPLE KEEP SHOVELING GOLD
INTO THE POCKETS
OF THE NEXT CROOK
WHO CLAIMS TO SPEAK
IN THE NAME OF SOME NONEXISTENT
SANTA CLAUS IN THE SKY.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
I THOUGHT
YOU'D BE INTERESTED.
DO YOU WANT TO
TAG ALONG?
TRY AND STOP ME.
[ ALARM CHIRPS ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HI. ARE YOU HERE
FOR KYLE?
HE'LL BE TALKING TO EVERYBODY
IN JUST A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
WE'RE WITH THE FBI.
THE FBI?
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG?
WE'D LIKE TO TALK
TO WHOEVER'S IN CHARGE.
WELL, NOBODY'S
REALLY IN CHARGE.
UM, THIS IS
TOM AND SANDY'S HOUSE,
BUT THEY'RE IN
WITH KYLE RIGHT NOW.
COULD THIS WAIT
TILL HE'S FINISHED?
H-HE REALLY LIKES TO TELL US
WHAT GOD SAID TO HIM
WHILE IT'S STILL FRESH
IN HIS HEAD.
ANY CHANCE
WE COULD LISTEN
TO THE WORD OF GOD
WHILE WE WAIT?
EVERYONE IS WELCOME.
Behave yourself,
Daniel.
Tom: IT'S WONDERFUL
TO SEE ALL OF YOU HERE.
SO MANY NEW FACES
HERE TODAY.
I'M TOM SHELBY, AND, UH,
THIS IS MY WIFE, SANDY.
HI, EVERYBODY.
AND, UH,
THESE ARE THE TWO BOYS
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH
TO GET IN THE PACKAGE DEAL
WHEN I MARRIED HER...
...GREG AND KYLE.
UH, NOW, AS MUCH AS I'D LIKE
TO BELIEVE OTHERWISE,
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T COME
TO HEAR ME FLAP MY JAW,
SO I'M GONNA SHUT UP
AND TURN THE FLOOR OVER TO KYLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
THANKS, TOM.
UM...GOD PICKS
THE CRAZIEST TIMES
TO TAP ME ON THE SHOULDER
AND START TALKING.
TODAY, IT WAS WHILE
I WAS DOING THE DISHES,
AND I WANT TO APOLOGIZE
TO MY MOM
FOR THE PITCHER I DROPPED
WHEN I CHECKED OUT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
TODAY, GOD TALKED TO ME
ABOUT DOUBT
AND HOW IMPORTANT IT IS
FOR US NOT TO BE SCARED OF IT.
HE SAID HE GAVE US DOUBT
SO THAT WE'D ALWAYS
BE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW THINGS REALLY WORK,
YOU KNOW, AND HOW WE CAN
MAKE THEM BETTER.
NOW, THERE ARE PEOPLE
IN THIS ROOM WHO HAVE NO DOUBT,
AND THAT IS
A BEAUTIFUL THING.
BUT GOD ALSO TALKED TO ME
ABOUT HOW BEING TOO SURE
OF ANYTHING CAN BE DANGEROUS.
AND THERE IS SOMEBODY HERE
WHO HAS ONLY DOUBT...
WHO DOESN'T BELIEVE
AT ALL.
BUT I'M REALLY GLAD
HE'S HERE.
[ SANDY SIGHS ]
JARED WAS SUCH
A BEAUTIFUL PERSON.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
ABOUT 6:00
JUST YESTERDAY MORNING.
HE -- HE WENT OUT
ON HIS JOG.
AND YOU DIDN'T WONDER WHY HE
DIDN'T COME HOME LAST NIGHT?
NO. EVERYBODY HERE
IS FREE TO COME AND GO.
Nikki:
I WAS WORRIED, ACTUALLY.
HE SAID HE'D BEEN SEEING
HIS OLD FRIENDS FROM K-TOWN,
WHERE HE USED TO SCORE.
I-I WAS SCARED THAT HE MIGHT BE
GOING BACK TO DRUGS.
DID HE MENTION ANY OF THESE
OLD FRIENDS BY NAME?
NO.
SHANE.
[ SIGHS ]
SHANE FLANNERY.
UM [CLEARS THROAT]
HE USED TO LIVE HERE.
WELL, TURNED OUT,
HE WAS KIND OF A FANATIC.
HE DIDN'T THINK WE WERE DOING
ENOUGH TO PROTECT KYLE.
HE THOUGHT WE WERE LETTING IN
THE SCUM OF THE EARTH --
ADDICTS AND PROSTITUTES
AND ALL KINDS OF SINNERS.
THAT'S WHO COMES
IN NEED OF GOD'S HEALING.
SHANE THREATENED TO BURN US
ALL ALIVE IN THE HOUSE.
JARED ASKED HIM TO LEAVE,
AND WHEN HE REFUSED,
JARED THREW HIM OUT.
YEAH, AND WHEN HE LEFT,
HE WAS RANTING ABOUT JARED
PAYING FOR HIS SINS.
OKAY. WELL,
WE'LL CERTAINLY LOOK INTO IT.
JARED BAKER SIGNED OVER
HIS ENTIRE TRUST FUND TO YOU.
HALF A MILLION DOLLARS.
WHAT'D YOU DO
WITH THE MONEY?
EVERYTHING WE TAKE IN
GOES TO THE SHELTER,
THE FOOD BANK,
OR THE SCHOOL IN AFGHANISTAN.
DID JARED EVER QUESTION HOW YOU
WERE SPENDING HIS INHERITANCE?
I-I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE INSINUATING.
IF YOU'RE IMPLYING THAT WE HAD
SOMETHING TO DO WITH --
TOM, IT'S OKAY.
PEOPLE GIVE US THEIR MONEY
BECAUSE OF THE FIRST THING
GOD EVER SAID TO ME.
"I ONLY ASK FOR ONE THING --
EVERYTHING.
BUT IN EXCHANGE,
I GIVE EVERYTHING."
Nikki:
I CAME HERE WITH NOTHING --
JUST A COKE HABIT
AND A LOT OF FEAR --
AND THESE PEOPLE TOOK ME IN
LIKE A DAUGHTER.
AND GOD KEPT HIS PROMISE.
HE GAVE ME EVERYTHING.
EVEN THE MAN
THAT I'M GOING TO MARRY.
Tom: YOU NEED TO
FIND SHANE FLANNERY.
IF HE DID KILL JARED BAKER,
HE MIGHT KILL SOMEBODY ELSE.
Kate: YES.
SHANE FLANNERY.
UH-HUH. I'M E-MAILING A PHOTO
AND A DESCRIPTION.
I WANT EVERY MAN ON IT
WE CAN SPARE.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
I'M GONNA STICK AROUND.
I WANT TO TALK TO KYLE.
ABOUT WHAT?
I'M JUST CURIOUS
ABOUT SOMETHING.
KYLE?
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE?
SURE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THAT I WAS A NONBELIEVER?
DID, UH,
GOD TELL YOU THAT?
[ CHUCKLES ]
I COULD JUST SEE IT
IN YOUR FACE.
IT TAKES WORK NOT TO BELIEVE
IN GOD, AND THE EFFORT SHOWS.
I THINK IT TAKES
A LOT MORE EFFORT
TO BELIEVE IN SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T SEE.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
HOW COULD ANYBODY LOOK
AT SOMETHING SO PERFECT
AND BEAUTIFUL AND DELICIOUS
AND THINK THAT IT GOT THAT WAY
BY ACCIDENT?
WELL, THERE'S A SCIENTIFIC
ANSWER TO THAT, KYLE.
EARLIER VERSIONS
OF THE RASPBERRY
WEREN'T SO BEAUTIFUL
AND DELICIOUS,
SO THEY COULDN'T ATTRACT
ENOUGH BIRDS
TO SPREAD THEIR SEEDS
AROUND.
I KNOW HOW EVOLUTION WORKS.
I LOVE DARWIN.
HE WAS THE FIRST PERSON
IN HISTORY
TO LOOK BEHIND THE CURTAIN
AND SEE HOW GOD
ACTUALLY MAKES IT ALL WORK.
WHEN DID GOD
FIRST START TALKING TO YOU?
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHEN I WAS 12.
BUT YOU'RE NOT FOOLING ME.
I KNOW YOU THINK
I'M EITHER TOTALLY FULL OF IT
OR JUST PLAIN CRAZY.
AND SO DID MY PARENTS,
AT FIRST.
W-WHAT DOES IT FEEL LIKE WHEN
YOU'RE HEARING GOD'S VOICE?
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
EVERYTHING
KIND OF DISAPPEARS.
IT'S LIKE I'M ASLEEP AND AWAKE
AT THE SAME TIME.
DO YOU GET HEADACHES
WHEN THAT HAPPENS?
FEEL NAUSEATED?
YEAH.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
JUST A HUNCH.
WELL, ANYWAY,
IT'S TOTALLY WORTH IT
'CAUSE I ALSO GET THIS AMAZING,
LIKE, EUPHORIA.
HMM.
HEADACHES, NAUSEA,
EUPHORIA, VOICES --
THESE ARE CLASSIC SYMPTOMS
OF TEMPORAL LOBE EPILEPSY,
WHICH COULD BE CAUSED
BY A TUMOR.
I-I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE HAS A CHECK-UP
EVERY YEAR,
AND HIS DOCTOR
HAS NEVER SAID ANYTHING.
DID YOU EVER TAKE HIM
TO A NEUROLOGIST?
THERE WAS NO REASON TO.
HE'S IN PERFECT HEALTH.
I'M SORRY, BUT HE'S NOT.
THIS KIND OF TUMOR
CAN ALSO PRESS ON NEIGHBORING
AREAS OF THE BRAIN.
IT CAN BE LIFE-THREATENING
IF IT'S NOT TREATED,
OF KYLE COULD HAVE A SEIZURE
WHILE HE'S DRIVING.
I'D LIKE TO BRING HIM IN
FOR SOME TESTS.
AND IF THEY SHOW
WHAT I THINK THEY'LL SHOW,
HE MAY NEED SURGERY.
WELL, I-I COULD BRING HIM IN
TOMORROW WHEN --
Kyle: MOM, WAIT.
ARE YOU SAYING THIS CONDITION
IS WHAT'S MAKING ME
HEAR GOD'S VOICE?
IT'S NOT GOD, KYLE.
IT'S A NEUROLOGICAL
ABNORMALITY.
WELL, IF IT IS,
GOD MUST HAVE GIVEN IT TO ME
SO HE COULD HAVE A WAY
TO TALK TO ME.
I'M NOT GETTING RID OF IT.
THIS COULD BE
A FATAL CONDITION.
BEING ALIVE
IS A FATAL CONDITION.
I'M NOT DOING IT, MOM.
MRS. SHELBY, I UNDERSTAND KYLE'S
COMMITMENT TO HIS BELIEFS,
BUT HE IS STILL A MINOR.
YOU CAN COMPEL HIM
TO GET TREATMENT.
DR. PIERCE, WE'LL DISCUSS
WHAT YOU'VE SAID.
WE'LL TALK TO KYLE
ABOUT IT.
BUT WE ARE NOT GONNA FORCE HIM
TO DO ANYTHING AGAINST HIS WILL.
Daniel:
THIS IS CHILD ABUSE!
THEY'RE NOT FORCING HIM
TO GET TESTED
BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT
THE GOOSE
TO STOP LAYING
THE GOLDEN EGGS.
[ Chuckling ] IT'S WHAT I'VE
ALWAYS SAID -- RELIGION.
AND, YOU KNOW, IF IT'S NOT
ABOUT BLOOD OR OPPRESSION,
IT'S ABOUT MONEY
IN THE BANK.
THAT IS A GROSS
GENERALIZATION,
NOT TO MENTION
TOTALLY OFFENSIVE.
I MEAN, WHAT ABOUT
THE DALAI LAMA OR --
OR MARTIN LUTHER KING?
OR THE INQUISITION
OR 9/11 OR GIORDANO BRUNO?
OH, THEY DIDN'T TEACH YOU
ABOUT HIM IN SUNDAY SCHOOL?
1592 -- GIORDANO BRUNO
MAKES THE WILD, SATANIC CLAIM
THAT THE EARTH
REVOLVES AROUND THE SUN,
SO THE HOLY FATHERS
PRAY TO GOD
AND ARE TOLD THAT
THIS WICKED MAN MUST DIE.
THEY CLAMP HIS TONGUE
TO THE ROOF OF HIS MOUTH,
AND THEY BURN HIM ALIVE,
WHICH MUST HAVE BEEN
THE RIGHT THING TO DO
'CAUSE GOD TOLD THEM
TO DO IT.
LOOK, YES,
THAT IS A HORRIBLE STORY,
BUT HAVEN HOUSE
ISN'T BURNING PEOPLE ALIVE.
YOU MADE A SNAP DIAGNOSIS
AFTER TALKING TO THAT KID
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
YOU DON'T THINK THAT
THAT MIGHT BE
YOUR PREJUDICE
AGAINST RELIGION TALKING?
I-I DIDN'T MAKE
THE CONDITION UP.
IT'S WHAT
JOAN WHAT?C HAD.
JOAN OF ARC HAD
TEMPORAL LOBE EPILEPSY.
IT'S WHY SHE THOUGHT
THAT ANGELS WERE TALKING TO HER.
OH, DID YOU EXAMINE HER,
TOO?
IT'S THE CONCLUSION
OF MEDICAL HISTORIANS
BASED ON HER DESCRIPTION
OF HER OWN EXPERIENCE.
AND WE ALL KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
YES. SHE BECAME A GREAT LEADER.
SHE LIBERATED FRANCE.
SHE WAS BURNED AT THE STAKE
AT AGE 19.
SHE WAS A DELUDED GIRL WHOSE
ILLNESS LED TO HER DISASTER.
SHE WAS A HERO.
AT A TIME WHEN WOMEN HAD
LESS POWER THAN FARM ANIMALS,
SHE LED AN ARMY.
I USED TO CARRY HER MEDAL
WHEN I WAS A KID,
AND I STILL LIGHT CANDLES
IN CHURCH FOR HER ON SUNDAY.
YOUYES, DANIEL, I DO.H?
AND I PRAY, TOO,
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW.
WHY?
BECAUSE I BELIEVE
IN GOD.
IT COMFORTS ME TO TALK TO HIM
ABOUT MY PROBLEMS.
AND DOES HE ANSWER YOU BACK
LIKE HE DOES WITH KYLE?
OKAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DO NOT HAVE TIME TO GET INTO
A THEOLOGICAL DEBATE WITH YOU.
I NEED TO FIND
SHANE FLANNERY.
WHICH IS EXACTLY WHAT
OUR FRIENDS AT HAVEN HOUSE
WANT YOU TO BE DOING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT JARED BAKER
DIDN'T JUST GET
[BLEEP] OFF ONE DAY
THAT HIS ENTIRE TRUST FUND
WAS GOING INTO THEIR POCKETS,
SO HE TRIED TO GET IT BACK,
AND THEY OFFED HIM FOR IT?
BECAUSE THE I.R.S.
IS ALL OVER PLACES LIKE THAT.
OH, AND NOTHING
EVER GETS PAST UNCLE SAM.
ALL RIGHT, FINE, IF IT WOULD
MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER,
I WILL PUT IN A CALL
TO THE I.R.S.,
BUT MY MONEY IS ON SHANE.
Ethan: I WAS EXACTLY
WHERE YOU ARE, DR. PIERCE.
I WAS POSITIVE A PLACE RAKING IN
THAT KIND OF CASH
HAD TO BE A SCAM,
BUT I'VE BEEN TEARING
THEIR BOOKS APART AT THE SEAMS
FOR TWO YEARS, AND I GOT TO
TELL YOU, IT'S LEGIT.
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT MILLIONS OF DOLLARS.
WHERE IS IT ALL GOING?
WELL, ABOUT 2% GOES
TO ADMINISTRATIVE EXPENSES,
WHICH IS AS LOW AS IT GETS
IN NONPROFIT-LAND,
AND SOME GOES
TO LOCAL CHARITIES --
FOOD BANK, MEALS ON WHEELS,
SHELTER.
BIGGEST CHUNK GOES
TO THE SCHOOL IN AFGHANISTAN.
[ CELLMORETTI.NGS ]
ISN'T IT POSSIBLE
THEY'RE FOOLING YOU?
THAT -- THAT
THEY'RE COOKING THE BOOKS?
I'D LIKE TO THINK,
AFTER 20 YEARS IN THIS PLACE,
THAT I'M A PRETTY HARD GUY
TO FOOL.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
CPD JUST FOUND
OUR SUSPECT.
THANK YOU.
Kate: MR. FLANNERY,
DID YOU THREATEN
TO BURN DOWN HAVEN HOUSE,
SEND ALL ITS RESIDENTS
TO HELL?
I SPOKE THE TRUTH.
I SAID THAT GOD WOULD BRING
THE FIRE OF HIS VENGEANCE
DOWN ON THAT HOUSE.
DID YOU SPECIFICALLY THREATEN
TO KILL JARED BAKER?
IT WAS GOD WHO DELIVERED
HIS JUDGMENT ON THAT HERETIC.
OKAY. WHERE WERE YOU
LAST TUESDAY MORNING?
ACROSS THE STREET
FROM HAVEN HOUSE,
GUARDING THE CHOSEN ONE --
I WAS THERE ALL NIGHT.
CAN ANYONE VERIFY THAT?
ONLY GOD, WHO WILL PURIFY
ALL THE SINNERS IN THAT HOUSE
WITH THE FIRES
OF HIS VENGEANCE...
STARTING WITH THOSE WHO TRAMPLE
ON THE SEVENTH COMMANDMENT.
OKAY, I'M A LITTLE RUSTY
ON MY COMMANDMENTS,
BUT I THINK I REMEMBER
WHICH ONE THE SEVENTH IS.
NOW, WHO IN THE HOUSE
WAS COMMITTING ADULTERY?
THAT LYING [BLEEP]
NIKKI.
SHE'S ENGAGED
TO KYLE'S BROTHER,
SO WHY WAS SHE RUTTING
LIKE A SOW WITH THE DEAD MAN?
OKAY, SO, YOU'RE SAYING
NIKKI WAS RUTTING LIKE A SOW
WITH JARED BAKER?
IT WAS AFTER MIDNIGHT.
I SAW THE LIGHT GO ON
IN HIS WINDOW.
SHE CAME INTO HIS ROOM
AND TOOK HIM IN HER ARMS.
MAYBE KYLE'S BROTHER
SAW WHAT I SAW.
MAYBE GOD ENTRUSTED HIM
WITH THE FIRE OF HIS VENGEANCE.
[ French accent ]
HE IS NOT THE KILLER.
HAVE YOU EVER MET
A HOLY WARRIOR
WHO SHOT HIS VICTIM
IN THE BACK?
NORMALLY, THEY BURN
THEIR VICTIMS OR CRUCIFY THEM
OR RITUALLY DRAIN
THEIR BLOOD.
SHE'S CHASING
THE WRONG CAT.
I WAS SENT TO HELP YOU
CATCH THE RIGHT ONE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "SENT"?
WHO SENT YOU?
GOD, OF COURSE.
MESSENGER OF GOD.
FRENCH ACCENT.
LATE MEDIEVAL,
HOMESPUN TUNIC.
GREAT.
I'M HALLUCINATING
JOAN OF ARC.
ENCHANTé.
EVIL IS IN THE EYE
OF THE BEHOLDER,
ESPECIALLY IF THAT BEHOLDER
IS SHANE FLANNERY.
SO, YOU ADMIT THAT YOU WERE
IN JARED'S ROOM THAT NIGHT?
YES, BUT NOT FOR ANYTHING
SINFUL.
JARED NEEDED MY HELP.
AT 2:00 IN THE MORNING?
MY ROOM IS
RIGHT NEXT DOOR TO HIS.
I WOKE UP.
I HEARD HIM CRYING.
I WAS WORRIED, SO I WENT
AND KNOCKED ON HIS DOOR.
DO YOU THINK
THAT YOUR FIANCé
MIGHT HAVE SEEN YOU
KNOCK ON HIS DOOR?
NO. GREG -- GREG'S ROOM
IS DOWNSTAIRS IN THE BACK.
JARED WAS
IN A TERRIBLE STATE.
HE TOLD ME HE HAD BEEN
SEEING HIS FRIENDS IN K-TOWN
AND THAT HE WAS WORRIED
HE MIGHT SLIP.
SO WE PRAYED TOGETHER.
I HELD HIM.
HE READ THAT THE WRONG WAY
AND MADE A PASS AT ME.
I TOLD HIM
I WOULD NEVER BETRAY GREG,
AND I WENT BACK
TO MY ROOM.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
ANY OF THIS BEFORE?
I TOLD YOU THAT I THOUGHT
JARED WAS HAVING A ROUGH TIME.
I DIDN'T TELL YOU THE REST
BECAUSE GREG LOVED JARED.
IT WOULD HAVE ONLY UPSET HIM,
AND FOR WHAT?
HEY.
I HEARD YOU GUYS WERE BACK.
DID YKate: YES.ANE?
BUT WE DON'T THINK
HDANIEL.T.
WE'RE NOT REALLY SUPPOSED TO
DISCUSS AN OPEN INVESTIGATION.
WELL, WHAT WERE YOU
TALKING TO NIKKI ABOUT?
DOES SHE KNOW
SOMETHING?
KYLE, I --
OKAY.
DR. PIERCE, CAN I TALK
TO YOU FOR A MINUTE?
NOT ABOUT THE CASE.
I'LL BE IN THE CAR.
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
A WHILE AGO,
GOD TOLD ME I WASN'T
GONNA BE ALIVE FOR VERY LONG.
I GUESS HE'S SAYING
THE SAME THING YOU ARE.
YOU KNOW I DON'T BELIEVE
IN GOD, KYLE.
BUT IF A GUT INSTINCT IS
TELLING YOU YOU'RE NOT WELL,
YOU SHOULD LISTEN TO IT
AND GET TREATMENT.
I'M NOT DOING THAT.
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
HOW LONG I HAVE
SO I CAN,
YOU KNOW, MAKE PLANS.
YOUR CONDITION
ISN'T ALWAYS FATAL.
AND THERE'S NO WAY TO PREDICT
HOW LONG IT'LL TAKE
ANY ILLNESS
TO CAUSE SOMEONE'S DEATH.
SO, SCIENCE DOESN'T HAVE
ALL THE ANSWERS?
I SUPPOSE NOT.
THAT'S OKAY.
NEITHER DOES GOD.
HE SPENDS MOST OF HIS TIME
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHY WE DO
THE CRAZY THINGS WE DO.
THAT'S WHY HE MADE
BRAIN SCIENTISTS LIKE YOU --
TO HELP HIM
FIGURE IT ALL OUT.
HEY.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT.
I NEED TO GET BACK
TO THE OFFICE.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
CPD found a witness
in K-Town
who said they saw a guy roughing
up Jared Baker a few days ago.
We're looking for him now.
LISTEN, UM...
CALL ME ANYTIME
ABOUT YOUR HEALTH
OR JUST TO TALK.
THANKS.
I'LL DO THAT.
[ BACH'S "PARTITA NO. 6
IN E MINOR" PLAYS ]
Daniel: HOW COULD SUCH
AN INTELLIGENT, LEVEL-HEADED KID
BE SO MEDIEVAL AT HEART?
NOT TO MENTION KATE.
DANIEL, THAT MAN
WHO'S MUSIC YOU'RE PLAYING
WAS A DEVOUT BELIEVER.
BACH LIVED 300 YEARS AGO.
SCIENCE WAS IN THE CRADLE.
ISN'T SCIENCE
JUST ANOTHER KIND OF FAITH
WITH ITS OWN SCRIPTURES
AND ITS OWN DOGMAS?
SCIENCE IS BASED ON FACT.
IT MUST BE EXHAUSTING
TO BE SO CYNICAL ALL THE TIME.
IT'S NOT CYNICISM --
IT'S REALITY.
AND, OF COURSE, WE ALL KNOW WHAT
A FIRM GRIP YOU HAVE ON REALITY.
OH, THAT'S VERY FUNNY.
I THINK YOU'RE JEALOUS
OF PEOPLE WITH FAITH.
YOU WISH YOU COULD FIND
THAT KIND OF SOLACE AND COMFORT.
[ MUSIC RESUMES ]
LISTEN TO THAT TREBLE.]
HMM? LIKE A CHICKEN
SCREAMING FOR ITS LIFE.
I'VE SEEN YOU LOOKING LONGINGLY
AT A SATIN-FINISH EBONY GRAND
IN THE STEINWAY SHOWROOM
DOWNTOWN.
YEAH, WELL, THAT PARTICULAR
SATIN-FINISH EBONY GRAND
COSTS AS MUCH
AS MOST CARS.
DANIEL, YOU JUST GOT A CHECK
FOR $50,000.
YOU CAN BUY ANYTHING
YOU WANT WITH IT.
THAT WOULD BE
AN INSANE INDULGENCE.
YOU'VE DONE
CRAZIER THINGS.
YOU REALLY THINK
I SHOULD BUY IT?
HEY, DOC. KYLE JENSEN'S MOTHER
IS ON THE PHONE.
SHE SOUNDS PRETTY UPSET.
Sandy: [ Voice breaking ]
KYLE RUNS UP AND DOWN THOSE
STAIRS 20 TIMES A DAY.
HE MUST HAVE GONE INTO ONE
OF HIS TRANCES AN[ SIGHS ]
WHY WOULD GOD CHOOSE
A MOMENT LIKE THAT?
Dr. Goldsby:
MR. AND MRS. SHELBY,
KYLE SUFFERED A MAJOR
HEAD TRAUMA IN THE FALL,
CAUSING HIS BRAIN
TO BLEED.
IN A WAY, THE FALL
MAY HAVE BEEN FORTUNATE
BECAUSE THE SCAN
REVEALED SOMETHING
WE MIGHT NOT HAVE CAUGHT
UNTIL IT WAS TOO LATE.
KYLE HAS AN INVASIVE TUMOR
IN HIS LEFT TEMPORAL LOBE.
IT'S POSSIBLE THE FALL
DISLODGED IT,
WHICH IS WHAT'S CAUSING
THE SEVERE BLEEDING.
LORD IN HEAVEN.
[ SIGHS ] THAT'S WHAT
YOU TOLD US YESTERDAY.
WE SHOULD HAVE
LISTENED TO YOU.
WE SHOULD HAVE -- WE SHOULD HAVE
BROUGHT HIM IN FOR TESTS.
I NEED TO OPERATE
IMMEDIATELY
TO RELIEVE THE PRESSURE
FROM THE BLEEDING.
IF WE CAN REMOVE THE TUMOR,
WE WILL.
KYLE MADE IT CLEAR THAT
HE DIDN'T WANT TO DO ANYTHING
THAT MIGHT CUT HIM OFF
FROM GOD.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE A DISLODGED
TUMOR INSIDE YOUR SON'S BRAIN.
I'M JUST THINKING
OF WHAT KYLE WOULD WANT.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
SHOOT HIM IN THE HEAD!
DANIEL.
Sandy:
DR. PIERCE IS RIGHT.
[ Crying ] I KNOW KYLE
MAY BE ANGRY WITH ME,
BUT I AM NOT GOING TO
LOSE MY SON.
WE'LL PREP HIM
FOR SURGERY.
DOCTOR, DID --
DID KYLE HAVE ELEVATED PROLACTIN
LEVELS WHEN HE CAME IN?
NO. THEY WERE NORMAL,
BUT NEED TO GET STARTED, SO...
WHAT WAS THAT ABOUT?
ELEVATED PROLACTIN WOULD MEAN
THAT KYLE HAD A SEIZURE
IN THE LAST COUPLE OF HOURS,
BUT HE DIDN'T.
SO HE DIDN'T FALL
BECAUSE HE WENT INTO A TRANCE.
MAYBE HE FIGURED OUT
WHO KILLED JARED.
AND SOMEONE PUSHED HIM.
Kate: DID ANY OF YOU
SEE KYLE FALL?
I WAS IN THE DEN,
READING, AND --
AND, UH, HEARD A CRASH
AND RAN INTO THE FOYER.
JAKE AND TINA CAME TO MY ROOM
AND TOLD ME WHAT HAPPENED.
I WAS MAKING DINNER,
AND I HEARD TOM YELL FOR HELP.
WHEN I SAW HIM ON THE GROUND,
ALL THAT BLOOD, I --
[ CELEXCUSE ME.GS ]
MORETTI.
WHY'S SHE ASKING
ALL THESE QUESTIONS?
NOBODY IN THE HOUSE
WOULD WANT TO HURT KYLE.
ARE YOU SURE ABOUT THAT?
Kate: DANIEL.
THEY FOUND THE GUY WHO
BEAT UP JARED IN K-TOWN.
WHAT ABOUT KYLE?
WELL, THE FAMILY WILL CALL US
IF THERE'S ANY NEWS.
NO, I MEAN
ABOUT PROTECTING HIM.
SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL HIM.
THEY MAY TRY AGAIN.
YOU -- YOU GOT TO PUT
A GUARD ON HIM.
DANIEL, I'M NOT GONNA BE ABLE
TO GET APPROVAL FOR A GUARD
ON A HOSPITAL ROOM 24/7
JUST BECAUSE WE HAVE
AN UNSUBSTANTIATED THEORY.
[ SIGHS ]
WELL, I'M STAYING.
ALL RIGHT.
Aaron: ARE YOU SAYING
THAT I KILLED JARED BAKER?
WITNESSES SAW YOU TWO
GET INTO A SHOVING MATCH
A FEW DAYS
BEFORE HE WAS MURDERED.
LOOK, I DO OUTREACH
FOR THE V.A.,
AND WE GET A LOT
OF THESE VETS
LIVING ON THE STREET
AROUND HERE,
SO, YEAH, IT [BLEEP] ME OFF
WHEN THESE [BLEEP] COME DOWN
AND TRY TO SCAM THESE GUYS
OUT OF THEIR SDI CHECKS.
JARED BAKER
WAS SCAMMING VETERANS?
PASSING OUT PAMPHLETS,
HAWKING SOME CHURCH
THAT'S ABOUT DONATING
EVERY CENT THEY GOT,
SO I TOSSED HIS PAMPHLETS
AND TOLD HIM
TO TAKE HIS SCAM ELSEWHERE.
AND THEN WHEN HE DIDN'T GET
THE MESSAGE, YOU GOT PHYSICAL.
AFTER HE TOOK OFF, I FELT BAD
ABOUT THE WHOLE THING,
SO I FISHED ONE OF THE PAMPHLETS
OUT OF THE TRASH
AND TOOK A LOOK.
AND GUESS WHAT --
I WAS RIGHT.
IT'S ALL A BIG FAKE --
AT LEAST THE SCHOOL
IN AFGHANISTAN IS.
THAT PLACE
DOES NOT EXIST.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
PICTURE IN THE PAMPHLET.
SCHOOLKIDS
IN FRONT OF A BIG LAKE?
SCHOOL'S SUPPOSED TO BE
IN MAIMANA.
I WAS STATIONED IN HERAT,
A STONE'S THROW FROM THERE.
THERE'S NO LAKE IN THAT VALLEY,
JUST SAND.
THIS PICTURE?
YEAH.
SEE THE WRITING
ON THE BLACKBOARD?
THAT'S FARSI.
IN MAIMANA,
THEY SPEAK ARABIC.
I CALLED A BUNCH OF GUYS
WHO SERVED OVER THERE.
NOBODY EVER HEARD
OF AN INTERNATIONAL GROUP
OPERATING A SCHOOL
ANYWHERE NEAR MAIMANA.
YOU REPORT THIS TO ANYONE?
JUST JARED BAKER.
WAIT. JARED KNEW?
NEXT TIME HE CAME DOWN
TO K-TOWN,
I TOLD HIM
EXACTLY WHAT I JUST TOLD YOU.
HOW DID HE TAKE IT?
IT SHOOK HIM UP.
HE SAID HE WANTED TO REPORT IT
TO SOMEBODY,
SO I TOLD HIM
HE SHOULD START WITH THE I.R.S.
THE I.R.S. GAVE HAVEN HOUSE
A CLEAN BILL OF HEALTH.
LAST-MINUTE VACATION,
ETHAN?
WE REMOVED THE TUMOR
AND STOPPED THE BLEEDING.
[ SIGHS ]
BUT THERE WERE
COMPLICATIONS.
KYLE SUFFERED
A RUPTURED ANEURYSM.
HE'S IN A COMA.
[ SOBS ]
OH, MY GOD.
THE SITUATION
WIDOESN'T LOOK GOOD.?
COULD HE DIE?
I THINK YOU NEED TO
PREPARE YOURSELVES
FOR THAT POSSIBILITY.
I'M SORRY.
[ CRYING ]
SURE.
I'LL TAKE YOU IN.
[ SIGHS ]
IT IS A PITY...
N'EST-CE PAS?
THEY CALL YOU
"THE MESSENGER," RIGHT?
WELL, I WANT YOU TO DELIVER
A MESSAGE TO GOD.
I THOUGHT YOU
DON'T BELIEVE IN HIM.
I DON'T.
BUT YOU DO, SO I WANT YOU
TO TELL HIM FROM ME
THAT I THINK
HE'S AN [BLEEP]
THAT IS BLASPHEMY, DANIEL.
IT IS A SIN.
NO. NO. NO.
A SIN -- A SIN
IS GIVING A BRAIN TUMOR
TO A -- TO A KID WHO'S NEVER
DONE A BAD THING IN HIS LIFE.
A SIN IS LETTING WHOEVER KILLED
JARED BAKER RUN FREE
WHILE THAT BOY LIES DYING.
DOES -- WHAT DOES --
DOES GOD ENJOY THIS?
WATCHING MOTHERS
SOBBING THEIR EYES OUT?
WHAT IS THAT, HIS THING?
IS THAT ENTERTAINING
TO HIM?
WHAT ARE WE?
IS THAT WHAT WE ARE --
SOME SORT
OF ENTERTAINMENT?
GIVE HIM THE MESSAGE.
T-TELL HIM.
GO ON. TELL HIM --
TELL HIM --
TELL HIM TO GO TO HELL.
Ethan: THAT AUDIT IS ACCURATE
TO THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR KNOWLEDGE
OF THE SEVEN CASH DEPOSITS
MADE INTO YOUR ACCOUNT,
EACH IN THE AMOUNT
OF $9,900,
JUST A SQUEAK BELOW
WHAT THE BANK
WOULD BE REQUIRED TO REPORT?
I WON THAT MONEY
PLAYING POKER.
I SEE.
AND WITH
YOUR POKER WINNINGS,
YOU DECIDED TO BUY YOURSELF A
ONE-WAY TICKET TO THE MALDIVES,
A COUNTRY THAT JUST HAPPENS
TO HAVE NO EXTRADITION TREATY
WITH THE UNITED STATES?
I ALWAYS WANTED
TO GO THERE.
JAIL IS NOTHING LIKE
THE MALDIVES, ETHAN.
THERE ARE NO CRYSTAL-CLEAR
WATERS, NO PALM TREES,
NO WAITERS FETCHING YOU
BRIGHTLY COLORED DRINKS.
I WANT FULL IMMUNITY.
THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
BUT IF YOU GIVE ME
THE NAME OF WHOEVER BRIBED YOU
TO FALSIFY THIS AUDIT,
I'LL ASK THE JUDGE
TO LET YOU PLEAD DOWN
TO RECEIVING
IMPROPER BENEFITS.
YOU'D GET OFF
WITH SIX MONTHS.
THIS OFFER EXPIRES
IN 10 SECONDS.
NINE...
EIGHT...
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
I TOOK A BRIBE.
WHO FROM?
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
MR. SHELBY, COULD I SPEAK
TO YOU IN THE HALLWAY?
Tom:
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
IT WOULD BE BEST
IF WE SPOKE OUTSIDE.
ANYTHING
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
YOU CAN SAY
IN FRONT OF MY FAMILY.
I'M PLACING YOU UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER OF JARED BAKER.
WHAT ARE YOU
THAT'S INSANE!
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
NO, LET GO OF HIM!
ANYTHING YOU SAY, CAN AND
WILL BE USED AGAINST YOU
SANDY, DON'T. LAW.
I'M COMING WITH YOU.
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO AN ATTORNEY.ITH KYLE.
I CAN STAY HERE WITH KYLE.
GREG, TAKE YOUR MOM.
NO, IF YOU CANNOT AFFORD
AN ATTORNEY,
GOD KNOWS THE TRUTH.
HE'LL SET EVERYTHING RIGHT.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THESE RIGHTS
AS THEY HAVE BEEN
READ TO YOU?
SO, HOW DO YOU --
HOW DO YOU KNOW TOM DID IT?
PICKED UP THE I.R.S. AUDITOR
ON HIS WAY TO THE AIRPORT
WITH A ONE-WAY TICKET
TO THE MALDIVES.
SAID TOM BRIBED HIM
FOR A CLEAN AUDIT.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
TOM WAS POCKETING ALL THE MONEY.
OKAY,
BUT WHY KILL JARED?
WELL, JARED
WAS ON TO THE SCAM.
TOM FOUND THAT OUT
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE MURDER.
LOOK,
WE GOT TO GET GOING.
I'LL TELL YOU ALL ABOUT IT
IN THE CAR.
W-W-- YOU'RE SURE THAT
NO ONE ELSE IS IN ON IT?
UNTIL YOU'RE SURE,
I'M STAYING WITH KYLE.
WHY WOULD I KILL JARED?
I LOVED HIM.
WE GOT A WARRANT TO SEARCH
YOUR HOUSE, INCLUDING YOUR SAFE,
AND WE FOUND RECORDS
OF THE CASH PAYMENTS
YOU MADE
TO THE I.R.S. AUDITOR.
I SWEAR TO GOD
I NEVER GAVE HIM ANYTHING.
HE TOLD US ABOUT HOW YOU DID
YOUR RESEARCH ON HIM
WHEN HE FIRST STARTED
THE AUDIT.
YOU KNEW THAT HE HAD ALIMONY,
GAMBLING DEBTS.
YOU KNEW THAT IF YOU OFFERED HIM
A BRIBE FOR A CLEAN AUDIT,
THAHE'S LYING. IT.
WE ALSO FOUND
THE INCORPORATION DOCUMENTS
FOR THE SHELL ORGANIZATION
THAT RUNS THE FAKE SCHOOL
IN AFGHANISTAN.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THE SCHOOL IS REAL.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT
HAS NO RECORD
OF A FOREIGN CHARITY OPERATING
A SCHOOL IN MAIMANA.
WE SEND THEM
ALMOST $1 MILLION A YEAR.
NO, YOU SEND
ALMOST $1 MILLION A YEAR
TO AN ACCOUNT IN YOUR NAME
AT THE BANK OF KABUL.
FROM KABUL,
IT'S TRANSFERRED
TO THE EVER-POPULAR
CAYMAN ISLANDS.
NOW I KNOW WHY YOU WERE SO EAGER
TO PUT US ONTO SHANE FLANNERY.
NO.
I WOULD NEVER DO THAT.
YOU WERE RAKING IT IN
LIKE CRAZY,
UNTIL JARED BAKER FOUND OUT
THAT THE SCHOOL WAS FAKE.
AND HE CALLED ETHAN
OVER AT THE I.R.S.
ETHAN CALLED YOU
AND SAID YOU HAD A PROBLEM.
AND THEN,
ACCORDING TO ETHAN,
YOUR EXACT WORDS WERE,
"I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT."
I GUESS YOU DID.
I NEED TO FIND TOM
A LAWYER.
SANDY, LET GREG
MAKE THE CALLS.
YOU NEED TO REST.
SHE'S RIGHT, MOM.
LET ME TAKE YOU HOME.
NO.
I CAN'T LEAVE KYLE.
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
I'LL CALL YOU
THE SECOND HE WAKES UP.
I'LL STAY, TOO.
THANK SURE.NIKKI.
AND THANK YOU,
DR. PIERCE.
DR. PIERCE,
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT...
I'D LIKE SOME TIME ALONE...
TO PRAY.
OF COURSE
SHE WANTS TIME ALONE...
BECAUSE AS SOON
AS YOU LEAVE THE ROOM,
SHE IS GOING TO KILL
THE BOY.
NIKKI, IF IT'S ALL THE SAME
TO YOU...
...I'M GONNA STAY.
LOOK AT HER.
THE SOUL OF PIETY
AND DEVOTION.
BUT DOESN'T IT
BOTHER YOU
HOW EAGER SHE HAS BEEN TO GET
EVERYBODY OUT OF THE ROOM?
THE BOY
WAS VERY CURIOUS
AS TO WHY
YOU WERE TALKING TO HER.
MAYBE HE HAD ASKED
TOO MANY QUESTIONS...
AND SHE PUSHED HIM.
AND THINK --
THINK OF THAT TAX MAN
FLYING OFF TO THE MALDIVES.
OF ALL THE COUNTRIES
IN THE WORLD,
WHY WOULD HE CHOOSE
A ROMANTIC TROPICAL ISLAND?
UNLESS HE WASN'T PLANNING
TO GO THERE ALONE.
YES, SHE IS
VERY BEAUTIFUL, NO?
JUST THE PERFECT TYPE
OF WOMAN
A LONELY TAX MAN WOULD DREAM
OF RUNNING AWAY WITH.
THAT'S STILL NOT PROOF.
WHAT?
N-NOTHING.
IT'S HARDLY ENOUGH TO GET HER
BURNED AT THE STAKE,
BUT IT'S MORE
THAN THE BRITISH HAD ON ME.
Nikki:
PLEASE, DR. PIERCE,
I'D REALLY LIKE
SOME TIME ALONE WITH KYLE.
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
[ BEEPING, FLATLINE ]
WHAT?
W-WHAT IS THAT?
WHY IS IT MAKING
THAT SOUND?
[ FLATLINE ]
HE'S GONE.
WH-- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
NO. HE'S BREATHING.
THIS MONITORS
NEUROELECTRICAL ACTIVITY.
KYLE'S BRAIN-DEAD.
OH, MY GOD.
I-I-I HAVE TO CALL
HIS PARENTS.
[ FLATLINE ]
OH, SORRY. I MUST HAVE, UH,
KNOCKED THIS OUT BY MISTAKE.
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
[ STAMMERS ]
[ BEEPING ]
Tom isn't the killer.
IT'WHAT?KI.
She says she loves Kyle.
BUT WHEN HE DIED,
SHE DIDN'T EVEN LOOK AT HIM.
She just took off
like a bat out of hell.
No, no, no, no.E DIED?
THAT WAS JUST PRETEND.
WHA-- DANIEL, WHAT ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
It was all Nikki --
KILLING JARED,
PUSHING KYLE DOWN THE STAIRS.
She's been waiting to get him
alone so she can finish the job.
YOU'VE GOT TO STOP HER
BEFORE SHE LEAVES THE COUNTRY.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY PROOF OF THIS?
N-N-Okay.UT --
THEN WE NEED TO PUT
A TAIL ON HER,
FIND OUT WHERE SHE'S HEADED
IN SUCH A HURRY.
RIGHT.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
HEY, NEED A HAND
WITH THOSE?
Ethan: I ALREADY TOLD YOU
THE WHOLE STORY.
THE PROBLEM IS
THAT NIKKI ATKINS
IS TELLING US
A DIFFERENT VERSION.
AND IN HERS, THE AFGHAN SCAM,
FRAMING TOM SHELBY,
MURDERING JARED BAKER --
THAT WAS ALL YOU.
SHE SAYS YOU BLACKMAILED HER
INTO GOING ALONG WITH IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU'RE MAKING THAT UP
TO TRAP ME.
WE PICKED HER UP AT A BANK
WITH TWO SACKS FULL OF CASH.
HER NEXT STOP
WAS THE AIRPORT.
SHE HAD HER BOARDING PASS
ALL PRINTED UP.
YEAH, SEE, EXCEPT SHE WAS
NOT GOING TO THE MALDIVES.
[ SIGHS ]
IT WAS ALL HER.
THE SCAM, EVERYTHING.
SHE KILLED JARED.
[ SIGHS ]
I MET HER WHEN I STARTED
THE AUDIT ON HAVEN HOUSE.
I ACTUALLY
LET MYSELF BELIEVE
IT WAS ABOUT
MORE THAN BUSINESS.
ONCE SHE WAS SURE
THAT SHE HAD ME,
SHE TOLD ME
ABOUT HER SCAM,
OFFERED TO CUT ME IN 50/50 IF
I MADE THE AUDIT COME OUT CLEAN.
HOW'D SHE GET THE CON GOING
TO BEGIN WITH?
SHE HEARD ABOUT THIS PLACE
WHERE MORONS
SIGNED OVER FORTUNES
AND DIDN'T ASK QUESTIONS.
SHE SHOWED UP, PRETENDING
TO BE A LOST LITTLE LAMB,
HOOKED UP WITH THE OLDER BROTHER
SO SHE COULD BE ON THE INSIDE.
WHAT ABOUT THE SCHOOL
IN AFGHANISTAN?
WHERE'D THAT COME FROM?
SHE SCANNED SOME PICTURES
FROM NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC,
PUT TOGETHER A WEBSITE,
AND E-MAILED TOM,
ASKING FOR HIS HELP.
SEEMED LIKE
WE PULLED IT OFF.
UNTIL JARED BAKER
STARTED ASKING QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE SCHOOL
IN AFGHANISTAN.
YEAH,
AFTER I TALKED TO JARED,
I CALLED UP NIKKI, AND I TOLD
HER WE HAD A PROBLEM.
NEXT DAY,
JARED TURNS UP DEAD.
I CALLED HER, AND I SAID,
"WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS GOING ON?
NO ONE'S
SUPPOSED TO GET HURT."
SHE TOLD ME TO KEEP QUIET
AND TO GET OUT OF TOWN.
SO I WENT HOME,
AND I GOT MY BAGS.
YOU GUYS PICKED ME UP.
AND THAT IS THE ENTIRE STORY.
I SWEAR.
JUST ONE PROBLEM --
IT'S YOUR WORD AGAINST HERS.
I MIGHT BE AN IDIOT,
BUT I AM NOT STUPID.
CHECK THE LINING
IN MY SUITCASE.
THERE'S A FLASH DRIVE
WITH SOME SOUND FILES ON IT.
ONE THING YOU LEARN
WHEN YOU WORK FOR THE I.R.S.,
YOUR WHOLE LIFE IS THE VALUE
OF KEEPING GOOD RECORDS.
NIKKI: They aren't buying
that Shane killed Jared.
Oh, baby, calm down.
Okay.
We're going to be all right.
I've got the room all booked
on the most beautiful beach
in the Maldives.
KYLE:
Nikki, what's going on?
Who are you talking to?
NIKKI:
Hey. I-I got to go.
No, I think Kyle heard me.
Okay.
I love you.
I'll see you at the airport.
KYLE WANTED TO KNOW
WHY YOU WERE TALKING TO US.
THAT'S WHY
HE KNOCKED ON YOUR DOOR.
Kate:
BUT HE OVERHEARD TOO MUCH,
AND THAT'S WHY YOU PUSHED HIM
DOWN THE STAIRS.
DO YOU THINK I DON'T KNOW
THAT A SOUND RECORDING
CAN BE MANIPULATED?
DO YOU EVEN KNOW THAT
YOU'RE DOING SATAN'S WORK?
PLEASE, GOD, I PRAY THAT YOU
WILL FORGIVE THESE PEOPLE
FOR THEIR BLINDNESS.
I PRAY THAT YOU WILL
SHOW THEM THE TRUTH.
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO ALSO PRAY
FOR A JUDGE WHO DOESN'T
BELIEVE IN THE DEATH PENALTY.
Dr. Goldsby:
IT'S A MIRACLE, REALLY.
KYLE'S AWAKE
AND EATING CHOCOLATE PUDDING
LIKE THERE'S NO TOMORROW.
HOW MUCH TISSUE DAMAGE?
SOME SWELLING.
HE'LL NEED TO TAKE IT EASY
FOR A WHILE,
BUT HE SHOULD MAKE
A GOOD RECOVERY.
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
THAT MESSAGE YOU SENT GOD
MUST HAVE DONE THE TRICK.
SOMETIMES HE NEEDS
A KICK IN THE PANTS.
PEOPLE MAKE AMAZING RECOVERIES
ALL THE TIME
WITH NO HELP
FROM SOME NONEXISTENT DEITY.
IF HE DOESN'T EXIST, THEN WHY
WOULD YOU SEND HIM A MESSAGE?
BECAUSE I'M A STARK,
RAVING LUNATIC.
LOOK, ARE CLOSING
HAVEN HOUSE,
BUT WE'RE KEEPING
THE BROKEN PROMISE,
OPENING A SCHOOL
IN AFGHANISTAN.
I KNOW IT'S WHAT GOD WANTS.
YOU'RE STILL HEARING A VOICE
EVEN AFTER THE OPERATION?
NOT AN ACTUAL VOICE IN MY HEAD
LIKE BEFORE.
BUT I STILL HEAR GOD
EVERY SECOND...
THE WAY ANYBODY CAN
IF THEY JUST LISTEN.
HERE.
MAYBE THIS WILL BUY A FEW BOOKS
FOR THE NEW SCHOOL.
WOW!
THAT'S A LOT OF BOOKS.
DOES THIS MEAN
YOU BELIEVE IN GOD NOW?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
BUT I BELIEVE IN YOU.
I GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOU, TOO.
KYLE, WHAT KIND
OF PRESENT IS THAT?
I THINK DR. PIERCE
WILL APPRECIATE IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]