DOES FREE WILL EXIST?
DO I EXERT CONSCIOUS CONTROL
OVER MY ACTIONS?
DID I DO THAT ON PURPOSE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
I'M PRETTY SURE YOU DID.
OR WAS I FORCED TO DO IT
BY SOME UNSEEN NEURAL PROCESS?
FACT IS, MOST OF THE
NEUROSCIENTIFIC DATA SUGGESTS
FREE WILL IS AN ILLUSION.
SO IF THAT'S TRUE,
ARE WE SIMPLY MEAT PUPPETS?
ALL OF OUR CHOICES MADE FOR US?
THE ANSWER TO THAT
CAN BE FOUND...
IN OUR NEXT CLASS.
[ STUDENTS GROAN ]
THAT'S BRILLIANT, DANIEL.
ENDING THE CLASS
ON A CLIFFHANGER
ALWAYS KEEPS THEM
COMING BACK FOR MORE.
THE ANTO WHAT?"NO."
TO WHATEVER IT IS
YOU'RE ABOUT TO ASK ME.
UNLESS I'M MISINTERPRETING
THE BLATANT EGO STROKING.
I SIMPLY WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU'RE PLANNING TO ATTEND
THE CHICAGO SCIENCE FOUNDATION
GALA ON FRIDAY.
AH,
YOU LOST ME AT "GALA."
I REALLY NEED YOU THERE,
DANIEL.
BECAUSE...
JONATHAN BANNISTER'S WIDOW
IS GONNA BE THERE.
I DON'CLASS OF '49.AT IS.
ANYWAY, I PLAYED GOLF WITH HIM
A COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO.
AND BY THE END
OF THE 8th HOLE,
I HAVE HIM
VERBALLY COMMITTED
TO FUNDING
THE NEW LIFE SCIENCES BUILDING.
BUT A COUPLE OF DAYS LATER,
BEFORE I CAN GET IT
IN WRITING,
THE GUY GOES AND DIES
OF A HEART ATTACK.
HOW INCONSIDERATE OF HIM.
I FEEL BADLY ABOUT IT,
OF COURSE,
BUT I AM HOPING
TO GET HIS WIDOW
TO HONOR
HER HUSBAND'S PROMISE.
I'M STILL WAITING TO HEAR
WHAT THIS HAS TO DO WITH ME.
WELL,
AS LUCK WOULD HAVE IT,
MRS. BANNISTER
IS A FAN OF YOURS.
NO. NO.
NO, NO, PAUL.
NO, NO, NO.G ]
I AM NOT GONNA LET YOU
PIMP ME OUT TO SOME BLUE HAIR
JUST SO THE UNDERGRADUATES
HAVE A SHINY NEW BUILDING
TO STORE THEIR MICE.
NO, I-I DON'T HAVE
TIME ANYWAY.
I'M RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF SOME
VERY IMPORTANT EXPERIMENTS.
WHAT EXPERIMENTS?
[ PIGEONS COOING ]
DANIEL?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DID YOU KNOW THAT PIGEONS'
BRAINS CONTAIN MAGNETITE?
I DID NOT KNOW THAT.
IT LETS THEM SENSE
THE EARTH'S MAGNETIC FIELD
AND ORIENTS THEM SO THEY CAN
GET WHERE THEY'RE GOING
WITHOUT GETTING LOST.
HERE'S THE THING --
PIGEONS MATE FOR LIFE.
SO I'M WONDERING,
AFTER A WHILE,
DOES THE FEMALE JUST FOLLOW
HER CHOSEN MALE,
OR DOES SHE STILL USE
THE MAGNETITE IN HER BRAIN
TO CHOOSE HER OWN ROUTE?
IT PROBABLY DEPENDS ON WHETHER
HE'S BUYING HER DINNER.
YOU DON'T THINK THEY'RE GONNA
FOLLOW MEHOME, DO YOU?
TO WHAT DO I OWE
THE PLEASURE?
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HELP THE FBI
BRING DOWN A BIG,
BAD INSURANCE COMPANY?
SEE, I KNEWTHIS WAS
GONNA BE A GOOD DAY.
WHAT'D THEY DO --
DENY SOMEBODY BENEFITS?
ACTUALLY, THEY MIGHT HAVE
COMMITTED MURDER.
SANJAY PATEL.
A COUPLE MONTHS AGO,
HE WAS ADMITTED TO THE E.R.
COMPLAINING OF SEVERE DEPRESSION
AND SUICIDAL THOUGHTS.
JAN STAR HEALTH WAS HIS
INSURANCE PROVIDER AT THE TIME.
THEY AUTHORIZED ONE DAY
OF HOSPITALIZATION.
THAT'S GENEROUS.
IT GETS WORSE.
AFTER HE'S DISCHARGED,
JAN STAR RECOMMENDED
OUTPATIENT TREATMENT
BY A PSYCHIATRIST,
DR. JULIAN CORVIS.
CORVIS TREATS SANJAY
FOR FOUR SESSIONS,
THEN STOPS TREATMENT,
SAYS SANJAY IS CURED.
OF SEVERE DEPRESSION?
IN FOUR SESSIONS. [BLEEP]
YEAH.
I'M SURE SANJAY'S MOTHER
SHARES YOUR SKEPTICISM.
THE NEXT MORNING, SHE FOUND HIM
HANGING IN HIS CLOSET.
[ SIGHS ] HOW DOES A DOCTOR
THAT INCOMPETENT
KEEP HIS MEDICAL LICENSE?
I DO NOT KNOW.
WHAT I DO KNOW IS THAT
HE WILL NEVER BE TREATING
PATIENTS AGAIN.
HE WAS FOUND DEAD
IN HIS OFFICE YESTERDAY --
SHOT IN THE FACE
BY A .38.
WALLET WAS STILL ON HIM,
SO ROBBERY'S OUT.
SAFE WAS OPEN, BUT THERE WERE
STILL VALUABLES INSIDE.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER OR NOT
ANYTHING WAS REMOVED.
SANJAY'S FAMILY
SEEKING PAYBACK?
THEY SEEM TO BE GOING THROUGH
THE PROPER CHANNELS.
THEY FILED A WRONGFUL-DEATH SUIT
AGAINST JAN STAR AND CORVIS
AND ALERTED
THE U.S. ATTORNEY'S OFFICE,
WHICH LAUNCHED
AN INVESTIGATION.
FBI APPROACHED CORVIS ABOUT
TESTIFYING AGAINST JAN STAR,
AND HE AGREED,
ON OIMMUNITY.ION.
THE TERMS OF WHICH WERE STILL
BEING NEGOTIATED
WHEN HE WAS KILLED.
SO YOU THINK JAN STAR HIRED
A HIT MAN TO SILENCE HIM.
I AM NOT ASSIGNED
TO INVESTIGATE THE MURDER.
BUT YOU SAID --
MY INVOLVEMENT
IN THIS CASE
IS LIMITED TO
THE WRONGFUL-DEATH SUIT.
I NEED TO FIND OUT
WHAT WAS IN CORVIS' FILES.
WELL, YOU CAN'T LOOK
AT MEDICAL FILES.
THEY'RE CONFIDENTIAL.
THAT'S WHY I NEED
A SPECIAL MASTER.
A SPECIAL WHAT?
A KNOWLEDGEABLE
AND IMPARTIAL THIRD PARTY
TO REVIEW THE FILES
AND REPORT ON WHAT CORVIS WAS
GONNA TELL THE U.S. ATTORNEY
WITHOUT REVEALING
ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION.
THAT'S WHY I CONVINCED THE
U.S. ATTORNEY TO APPOINT YOU.
AH.
WELL,
AS FLATTERED AS I AM
THAT YOU THINK I'M SPECIAL,
I KNOW YOU, KATE.
AND THERE'S NO WAY YOU'RE NOT
CURIOUS ABOUT WHO KILLED CORVIS.
I'VE BEEN IN SOME HOT WATER
WITH THE BOSS LATELY.
SAYS I KEEP STEPPING OUTSIDE
MY "CIRCLE OF RESPONSIBILITY."
SO THIS TIME, I AM STAYING
INSIDE THE CIRCLE.
SO, WHAT EXACTLY IS
THE DIAMETER OF THIS CIRCLE?
PRETTY SMALL.
HEMICHAEL.
LET ME GUESS -- YOU'RE HERE
TO TAKE ME TO LUNCH.
ACTUALLY,
I AM HERE TO SEE DANIEL.
SORRY, SORRY.
DO YOU TWOF COURSE.H OTHER?
I MEAN, HALF THE REASON
I JOINED THE FACULTY
WAS TO SAY THAT I'VE WORKED
WITH THE GREAT DR. PIERCE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU,
DANIEL.
SO, WHEN ARE WE
GETTING TOGETHER AGAIN?
WELL, UH, I DON'T KNOW.
I MIGHT HAVE THE --
WE HAVE SOMETHING
THAT WE'RE DOING.
YEAH, SORRY.
TOTALLY UNDERSTAND.
I'LL CALL YOU.
OKAY.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'REGOING?
I'M THE ONLY ONE WHO'S ALLOWED
TO LOOK AT THESE FILES.
I'M ONLY GOING UP
TO UNLOCK THE OFFICE.
JUST SO YOU REMEMBER.
YOU'RE THE SPECIAL MASTER.
I GOT IT.
[ VEHICLE APPROACHES ]
IT'S A FRESH CRIME SCENE.
THIS SEAL'S SUPPOSED
TO BE INTACT.
WAIT HERE.
[ WOMAN SOBBING ]
[ SNIFFLES ]
MRS. CORVIS?
Cheryl: IT WAS
OUR HONEYMOON IN BORA-BORA.
IT WAS THE HAPPIEST WEEK
OF MY LIFE.
THE FBI SHOULD HAVE
PROTECTED JULIAN.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
GET HER HOME.
YOU SURE?
I'LL BE FINE.
MRS. CORVIS, WE'RE GONNA
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO FIND THE PERSON
WHO DID THIS.
HOW IS SHE?
GETTING SOME REST.
YOU FIND ANYTHING?
APPARENTLY,
CORVIS WAS MIRACULOUSLY
CURING HIS JAN STAR PATIENTS
OF MAJOR DISORDERS
IN JUST A FEW SESSIONS.
FOR HIS PATIENTS
FROM OTHER CARRIERS,
SAME DISORDERS,
HE'D SEE 30 OR 40 TIMES.
SO YOU THINK JAN STAR
WAS GETTING CORVIS
TO CHURN THEIR PATIENTS
AND THYEAH.MP 'EM.
THEY PAID HIM
A MAJOR BONUS
EVERY TIME
HE CUT SOMEBODY LOOSE.
THEY'D SAVE A BUNDLE,
AND HE'D FILL HIS SCHEDULE
WITH PATIENTS
THAT WERE FROM OTHER CARRIERS
OR PAYING CASH.
NICE WORK, DANIEL.
YOU TESTIFY TO THIS,
THE U.S. ATTORNEY SHOULD
BE ABLE TO NAIL JAN STAR.
THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE.
LOOK AT THIS.
CORVIS WAS DIAGNOSING
A DISORDER CALLED
"TRANSFERENTIAL DOPAMINE
DEFICIENCY."
NEVER HEARD OF IT.
NEITHER HAVE I.
THAT'S NOT IN THE DIAGNOSTIC
STATISTICAL MANUAL.
YOU THINK IT'S RELATED
TO THE JANO.TAR SCAM?
EVERYONE WITH THIS DIAGNOSIS
WAS PAYING CASH.
SUSPICIOUS, RIGHT?
IF IT'S NOT RELATED TO JAN STAR,
IT'S OUTSIDE THE CIRCLE.
IT DOUTSIDE THE CIRCLE.SE --
[ SIGHS ]
YOU FOUND
THE SMOKING GUN.
I'LL BUY YOU A CELEBRATORY
SLICE OF PIZZA.
MALNATI'S?
DID YOU KNOW THAT HUMANS
ARE THE ONLY SPECIES
THAT DRINKS THE MILK
OF ANOTHER ANIMAL?
IT'S UNNATURAL --
ALL THE LACTOSE CHURNING AWAY,
OKAY, DANIEL.
WI AM NOT HUNGRY ANYMORE.
[ DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE ]
[ LAUGHTER IN DISTANCE ]
LEWICKI.
[ CHUCKLES ]
OH, HI,
PROFESSOR PIERCE.
[ High-pitched voice ]
COME OUT HERE?
YES?
WHAT IS THAT GIRL
DOING HERE?
UH, I'M KARYN'S
TEACHING ASSISTANT.
SHE ASKED ME FOR HELP,
AND I'M HELPING HER.
SIMPLE AS THAT.
OH, SO YOU COULDN'T HELP HER
AT THE DORM OR AT THE LIBRARY?
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
My point is that
that girl stalked me!
She almost got me fired,
now she's finagled her way
into my house!
SHOKAY, MAYBE SHE DOES.S.
OKAY, NOW THAT WE SEE EYE
TO EYE, GET HER OUT OF HERE.
EVER OCCUR TO YOU HER ULTERIOR
MOTIVE IS TO GET WITH ME?
HEY, MAX, I SHOULD GO.
IT'S GETTING LATE.
UM, OKAY. YEAH, I-I'LL WALK YOU
BACK TO YOUR DORM.
SEE YA,
PROFESSOR PIERCE.
Natalie: I THINK
YOU'RE JUST JEALOUS.
OF LEWICKI?!
THAT GIRL TOOK HER SHIRT OFF
IN YOUR OFFICE,
AND YOU DIDN'T FIND HER
THE LEAST BIT ATTRACTIVE?
I MAY BE CRAZY
FROM THE NECK UP.
BUT FROM THE WAIST DOWN,
I ASSURE YOU
I'M PERFECTLY HEALTHY.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU HAD A DATE?
IS THAT A PROPOSITION?
IN YOUR DREAMS.
HEY,
WE HAD FUN TOGETHER.
"HAD" -- PAST TENSE.
YOU NEED TO FIND SOMEBODY
IN THE HERE AND NOW.
LIKE YOUR FRIEND KATE IS DOING
WITH MICHAEL HATHAWAY.
OHH, THAT'S CALLED
SETTING THE BAR SO LOW
THAT ANYONE'S ACCEPTABLE.
AS OPPOSED TO SETTING THE BAR
SO UNREALISTICALLY HIGH
THAT YOU NEVER HAVE TO SHOW
ANOTHER PERSON THE REAL YOU?
ARE YOU FEELING OKAY?
I'M HAVING SOME SYMPTOMS,
BUT I KNOW
THEY'RE SYMPTOMS.
SUCH AS?
I'M BEING FOLLOWED
BY A GOVERNMENT AGENT
IN A BLACK S.U.V.
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S A HALLUCINATION?
BLACK S.U.V.?
MIRRORED SHADES?
STRAIGHT OUT OF
THE PARANOID SCHIZO HANDBOOK.
[ TV TURNS ON ]
I DROPPED KARYN OFF
AT HER DORM.
UH...I'M GONNA CRASH.
YOU NEED ANYTHING FIRST?
Woman:
DON'T FORGET YOUR UMBRELLAS,
OR OTHERWISE
YOU COULD GET ALL WET.
50% CHANCE OF RAIN.
HOW DOES THIS WOMAN
STAY EMPLOYED
WHEN HER FORECAST IS BASICALLY
"IT MIGHT RAIN OR IT MIGHT NOT"?
OH, I THINK SHE HAS OTHER ASSETS
THAT KEEP HER EMPLOYED, DOC.
...HIGH-PRESSURE WINDS CREEPING IN FROM NORTHWEST INDIANA.
CLEARLY, UNDERSTANDING
METEOROLOGY ISN'T ONE OF THEM.
THAT'S NOT A VERY NICE THING
TO SAY, DANIEL.
BY THE WEEKEND, IT LOOKS
LIKE MORE OF THE SAME.
SO, I MISS A TROPICAL
DEPRESSION ONCE IN A WHILE.
YOU CAN MISS A DEPRESSION,
TOO, CAN'T YOU?
BUT THE WEATHER SHOULD BE
IMPROVING LATER.
THE GOOD NEWS IS,G.
WE'RE NOT EXPECTING
ANY MORE RAIN ON THE HORIZON,
AND RIGHT NOW IT'S JUST
A LOVELY EVENING OUT THERE.
YOU OKAY, DOC?
GET THE CAR.
DANIEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO WAIT FOR ME.
I THINK I KNOW
WHO KILLED CORVIS.
WHO?
I CAN'T TWHY NOT?
'CAUSE IT'S OUTSIDE
THE CIRCLE.
YOUR SON WAS
DR. CORVIS' PATIENT.
HE JUST WENT THE ONE TIME.
WERE YOU AWARE THAT...
JUSTIN THREATENED TO KILL HIM?
NO.
NO, I WASN'T.
YOU DON'T THINK HE HAD ANYTHING
TO DO WITH --
AT THIS POINT,
WE JUST WANT TO TALK TO HIM.
DURING THE SESSION,
JUSTIN BECAME
AGGRESSIVE AND VIOLENT --
SO MUCH SO
THAT DR. CORVIS RECOMMENDED
HE FIND A NEW THERAPIST.
DID NO.
NO, HE CAME HOME THAT DAY
SHOUTING AND SCREAMING.
AND HE WAS ANGRY AT ME
FOR SENDING HIM TO SEE CORVIS.
AND THEN HE JUST...
THEN HE JUST TOOK OFF.
HIS MOTHER...
SHE KNEW HOW TO HANDLE JUSTIN
A LOT BETTER THAN I DID.
SHE DIED THREE YEARS AGO.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN VERY HARD
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
IS THAT WHY YOU THOUGHT
JUSTIN SHOULD SEE A THERAPIST?
NO, HE -- HE HANDLED
IT PRETTY WELL,
YOU KNOW --
ALL THINGS CONSIDERED.
HE LOVED HIS MUSIC.
HE HAD PLENTY
OF GOOD FRIENDS.
AND, UH...
AND THEN EVERYTHING
JUST CHANGED.
HOW?
TEENAGE STUFF, MOSTLY.
HE STARTED RUNNING AROUND
WITH THE WRONG CROWD,
AND I THOUGHT THAT CORVIS
COULD HELP HIM
GET BACK ON THE RIGHT TRACK,
YOU KNOW?
DR. CORVIS DIAGNOSED HIM
WITH SOMETHING CALLED
"TRANSFERENTIAL DOPAMINE
DEFICIENCY."
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS?
UM, I'M SORRY.
I DON'T.
AND YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE JUSTIN IS RIGHT NOW?
I HAVEN'T SEEN MY SON
SINCE HE LEFT THIS HOUSE.
IF YOU FIND HIM,
PLEASE, WILL YOU TELL HIM
THAT I AM SORRY?
ABOUT EVERYTHING?
Kate: THANKS.
[ BEEP ]
NO HITS ON JUSTIN REYCRAFT
WITH FBI OR CHICAGO P.D.
TIT'S HARD TO SAY.P?
SOMETIMES RUNAWAYS DO JUST
DROP OFF THE GRID COMPLETELY.
BUT WE'VE GOT
AN A.P.B. OUT.
SO, UH...
YOUR BOSS KNOWS YOU'VE DRIFTED
OUTSIDE THE CIRCLE?
YEAH, HE'S GIVING ME
A LITTLE LEEWAY.
WHAT'S UP?
NOTHING.
I'M JUST TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT THIS DIAGNOSIS MEANS.
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ CRASH ]
WHAT THE...
FEDERAL AGENT!
HANDS WHERE I CAN SEE 'EM!
OUT OF THE CAR!
YOU BETTER HAVE
ONE [BLEEP] OF A GOOD REASON
FOR FOLLOWING US AROUND
THE PAST COUPLE OF DAYS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
SECRET SERVICE GUY IN AVIATOR
SUNGLASSES AND A BLACK S.U.V.
WAS REALI KNOW.OWING US?
WHAT A CLICHé, RIGHT?
Kate: PULLED YOUR
PERSONNEL FILE, VINCENT.
NINE COMPLAINTS
OF EXCESSIVE FORCE,
DRINKING ON THE JOB.
YOU WANT TO TELL ME
WHAT A BURNOUT COP'S DOING
FOLLOWING AROUND THE FBI?
WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S GREAT ABOUT
NOT BEING ON THE JOB ANYMORE?
HMM?
I DON'T HAVE TO TALK TO PEOPLE
LIKE YOU.
WANT TO KNOW WHAT ELSE
IS GREAT
ABOUT YOU NOT BEING A COP
ANYMORE, VINCENT,
IS THAT NO ONE
WILL GIVE A RAT'S [BLEEP]
WHEN I SHIP YOU FOR ASSAULTING
A FEDERAL AGENT.
NEVER LAID A FINGER ON YOU.
IT'S TOO BAD YOU DIDN'T PAY
MORE ATTENTION IN THE ACADEMY,
BECAUSE
THEN YOU WOULD KNOW
THAT HITTING MY CAR
QUALIFIES AS ASSAULT.
A FELONY EVEN.
WORKING AS AN INVESTIGATOR
FOR JAN STAR. SO WHAT?
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
THEY FIND OUT CORVIS
WAS GONNA TESTIFY
SO THEY SENT YOU TO DIG UP
SOME DIRT TO BLACKMAIL HIM WITH?
OR MAYBE...
THEY SENT YOU TO SILENCE HIM
FOR GOOD.
I WAS JUST HIRED
TO FOLLOW HIM,
DIG UP DIRT,
LIKE YOU SAID.
WELL, IF YOU WERE FOLLOWING HIM,
MAYBE YOU SAW
WHO KILLED HIM.
[ SIGHS] I WAS AT AN
A.A. MEETING WHEN IT HAPPENED.
BY THE TIME I GOT BACK
TO HIS OFFICE,
IT WAS ALREADY
A CRIME SCENE.
COP IN ME WAS CURIOUS,
SO I HUNG AROUND.
AND WHEN YOU AND YOUR WEIRD PROFESSOR FRIEND SHOW UP,
I RUN A BACKGROUND,
FIND OUT WHO HE IS,
REPORT BACK TO JAN STAR
THAT MAYBE HE WAS GONNA TESTIFY IN CORVIS' PLACE.
SO THEY TOLD YOU
TO FOLLOW DR. PIERCE,
DIG UP SOME DIRT
ON HIM, TOO?
INSTEAD OF RIDING ME,
WHY AREN'T YOU LOOKING
FOR THE GUY
WHO THREATENED CORVIS
LAST WEEK?
KEEP TALKING.
HE GOES TO
SOME GIRL'S APARTMENT.
COMES OUT
ABOUT AN HOUR LATER.
SOME BIG GUY
IS WAITING FOR HIM,
THROWS CORVIS UP AGAINST A CAR,
THREATENS TO BREAK HIS HEAD.
GIVE ME A NAME.
I DIDN'T GET HIS NAME,
BUT I GOT THE GIRL'S.
I LOVED JULIAN.
BUT YOU KNEW
HE WAS MARRIED, MISTY.
I COULDN'T HELP MYSELF.
WE JUST HAD
THIS CRAZY CONNECTION.
[ Chuckling ] AND THE SEX WAS
ABSOLUTELY MIND-BLOWING.
I WOULD KNOW, TOO.
I'VE HAD LIKE A TON OF SEX.
OH.
BUT WITH JULIAN
IT WAS DIFFERENT.
HE WAS SO INTO EXPERIMENTING
AND EXPLORING.
SOUNDS AWESOME, MISTY,
BUT THIS IS A MURDER
INVESTIGATION.
NOW, A WITNESS SAYS
THEY SAW CORVIS
BEING THREATENED
OUTSIDE YOUR PLACE.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THAT?
IT WAS PROBABLY TOBY,
MY EX.
HE'S GOT
A REALLY BAD TEMPER.
AND HE WAS PRETTY UPSET
WHEN I STARTED SLEEPING
WITH JULIAN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
ALL RIGHT.
I NEED YOU TO WAIT IN THE CAR.
TOBY MULLIGAN?
[ SIGHS ]
WHO'S ASKING?
FBI. I GOT A COUPLE QUESTIONS
FOR YOU.
JUST LET ME
FINISH THIS SET.
ACTUALLY, I NEED TO TALK
TO YOU RIGHT NOW.
[ GRUNTS ]
OKAY, SURE.
WHAT?
I WAITED IN THE CAR.
YEAH, I GOT IN HIS FACE,
BUT I DIDN'T HURT HIM.
I WASN'T EVEN IN TOWN
LAST FRIDAY!
THEN WHY'D YOU RUN?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS ABOUT
THE STEROIDS.
I TOTALLY HAVE A PRESCRIPTION
FOR THOSE, BY THE WAY.
ADMIT IT, TOBY.
YOU WERE [BLEEP] OFF
BECAUSE SOME JOE SCHMO DOCTOR
HALF YOUR SIZE
WAS GIVING IT TO YOUR GIRL
AND SHE WAS LIKING IT.
SO YI TOLD YOU. PAY.
I DIDN'T KILL HIM.
WHEN'D YOU FIND OUT
SHE WAS SEEING HIM?
YOU MEAN SLEEPING TOGETHER
OR AS HIS PATIENT?
MISTY
WAS CORVIS' PATIENT?
SHE STARTED SEEING HIM
FOR HER SELF-ESTEEM ISSUES.
SHE SEEMED PRETTY CONFIDENT
TO ME.
MAYBE HE CURED HER.
HE GOT INSIDE HER HEAD --
TRICKED HER SOMEHOW.
THERE'S NO WAYSHE'D HAVE
CHEATED ON ME OTHERWISE.
I EVEN TOLD HIS WIFE
ABOUT IT.
I THOUGHT THAT WOULD END IT,
BUT IT DIDN'T.
Cheryl:
OF COURSE I KNEW.
I KNEW ABOUT
ALL MY HUSBAND'S AFFAIRS.
HOW MANY WERE THERE?
A FEW.
NOTHING OUT OF THE ORDINARY.
I LIKED THAT OTHER WOMEN
FOUND MY HUSBAND ATTRACTIVE.
IT MADE ME FEEL
LUCKY TO HAVE HIM.
WELL, YOU HAVE
A VERYPROGRESSIVE ATTITUDE
TOWARDS YOUR HUSBAND'S
EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES.
THAT'S JUST WHAT
NORMAL MEN DO.
Kate:
THAT WOMAN IS LYING.
EVERYONE HAS A DIFFERENT
ATTITUDE WHEN IT COMES TO SEX.
YOU GET CHEATED ON,
YOU FEEL ANGRY, BETRAYED.
YOU WANT SOMEONE TO PAY.
TRUST ME.
DOESN'T SOUND LIKE
YOU'RE BEING ENTIRELY OBJECTIVE,
AGENT MORETTI.
SORRY.
I'M JUST SAYING,
SHE MIGHT SEEM LIKE THE POSTER
CHILD FOR COOL RIGHT NOW,
BUT MAYBE WHEN SHE FOUND OUT
CORVIS WAS CHEATING ON HER,
SHE GOT JEALOUS
AND KILLED HIM.
BUT YOU DIDN'T
ACCUSE HER.
THAT'S 'CAUSE I DON'T HAVE
ANY EVIDENCE...
YET.
I GOT TO LOOK INTO HER MOVEMENTS
ON THE DAY OF THE MURDER.
DROP YOU BACK AT CAMPUS?
LOOK AT US -- JUST A COUPLE OF
HIGHER-ORDER PRIMATES
COMPETING
FOR A SEXUAL PARTNER.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
I'M TALKING ABOUT KATE,
OF COURSE.
AND, WELL,
I'LL JUST SAY IT --
I SENSE THAT
SHE'S VERY ATTRACTED TO ME.
BUT IF YOU'RE PLANNING
TO PLANT YOUR FLAG
IN THAT TERRA INCOGNITA,
THEN JUST SAY THE WORD
AND I'LL GRACEFULLY WITHDRAW.
LOOK, IF YOU'RE DONE
MANGLING METAPHORS,
I HAVE A CLASS.
SO, YOU DON'T MIND?
LEWICKI?!
LEWICKI!
LEWI--
WHERE THE [BLEEP] WERE YOU?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO BRING MY NOTES
FOR THE NEUROANATOMY SEMINAR --
I HAD TO CANCEL IT!
I'M SORRY, DOC.
I'M SORRY.
WHAT -- WHAT HAPPENED WAS
I HAD TO TAKE MY CLOTHES OFF...
TO DO THE LAUNDRY.
AND, UH, I PUT MY CLOTHES
IN THE WASH,
AND, UH, WHEN I CAME BACK
TO CHECK ON THEM,
THE WASHER
WAS SET ON DELICATES.
SO I HAD TO WASH THEM
ALL OVER AGAIN.
HEY, PROFESSOR PIERCE.
YEAH, I-I-I TOLD YOU
SHE WAS INTO ME.
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
UH, DR. PIERCE'S
RESIDENCE.
ONE SEC.
IT'S KATE.
HELLO?
CHICAGO P.D. PICKED UP
JUSTIN REYCRAFT --
you know, the kid
who was threatening Corvis.
HE WAS PANHANDLING
IN MILLENNIUM PARK.
THEY'RE BRINGING HIM IN
TO TALK TO ME.
You want to come say hi?
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW MUCH.
SO, THEN, YOU WON'T BE BACK
FOR A WHILE?!
Kate:
WHY'D YOU RUN AWAY, JUSTIN?
I DIDN'T.
MY DAD KICKED ME OUT.
WHY --
WHY'D HE DO THAT?
BECAUSE I WOULDN'T GO BACK
TO SEE THAT WEIRDO CORVIS.
MR. CORVIS SAYS HERE
IN HIS FILES
THAT YOU THREATENED HIM.
DID YOU KILL HIM?
NO, I DIDN'T KILL HIM.
WHAT MADE YOU SO ANGRY
AT HIM?
THAT GUY
WAS A TOTAL FREAK!
OKAY. WE JUST WANT TO HEAR
YOUR SIDE OF THE STORY.
MY DAD FORCED ME
TO GO SEE CORVIS.
AND THEN HE GIVES ME
SOME PILL.
WHAT KIND OF PILL?
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE ONE OF THOSE PILLS
THEY GIVE TO OLD MEN
TO MAKE THEM ALL
HOT AND BOTHERED.
I GUESS IT WAS SUPPOSED TO DO
THE SAME THING TO ME.
AND THEN HE MAKES ME
WATCH ALL THIS PORN.
IT WAS GIRLS
WITH OTHER GIRLS.
AND THEN HE WANTS ME TO...
YOU KNOW...
WHILE I'M WATCHING THE PORN
IN FRONT OF HIM.
HE SAID IT WOULD HELP
RE-TEACH MY BRAIN.
HE SAID IT WAS
"PART OF THE CURE."
THE CURE FOR WHAT?
THE CURE FOR BEING GAY.
THANK YOU.
WELL, JUSTIN'S ALIBI
CHECKS OUT.
HE WAS AT THE MERCY SHELTER
THE NIGHT CORVIS WAS KILLED.
OF COURSE
HE DIDN'T DO IT.
HE'S A SWEET KID
WHOSE PHILISTINE FATHER
CONVENIENTLY FAILS TO MENTION
THAT HE THREW HIS OWN SON
OUT OF THE HOUSE
FOR BEING GAY.
OR HOW DID HE PUT IT?
"HANGING
WITH THE WRONG CROWD."
HE SOUNDED PRETTY REMORSEFUL
WHEN I TALKED TO HIM
AND INCREDIBLY RELIEVED
THAT JUSTIN WAS OKAY.
YOU KNOW,
I THINK THERE'S A CHANCE
THAT THOSE TWO
COULD WORK THINGS OUT.
AT LEAST NOW WE KNOW WHAT
"TRANSFERENTIAL DOPAMINE
DEFICIENCY" IS.
IT'S CORVIS' CODE
FOR HOMOSEXUALITY.
IT'S SO SAD THAT SOMEONE COULD
BE SO ASHAMED OF WHO THEY ARE
THAT THEY'D GO TO SOME
QUACK DOCTOR TO CURE THEM.
YOU GROW UP IN A FAMILY THAT
TELLS YOU YOUR BASIC IMPULSES
ARE MORALLY REPUGNANT?
YOU MIGHT TRY ANYTHING TO MAKE
YOURSELF FEEL...NORMAL.
KIDS KILL THEMSELVES
BECAUSE OF IT.
OKAY, BUT IS IT RELEVANT
TO WHO KILLED CORVIS?
HE CREATES A DISORDER
THAT DOESN'T EXIST.
THEN HE COMES UP WITH
A TREATMENT REGIMEN FOR IT.
AND JUSTIN WAS PRETTY ANGRY
AT CORVIS
FOR PUTTING HIM
THROUGH IT,
SO MAYBE ONE OF HIS
OTHER PATIENTS IS ANGRY, TOO.
WE CAN'T INTERVIEW THEM
'CAUSE OF CONFIDENTIALITY.
YOUCAN'T, BUT ICAN.
BECAUSE I'M...
THE SPECIAL MASTER.
HOW COULD I FORGET?
THIS IS COMPLETELY
CONFIDENTIAL.
THE ONLY WAY
I'D DIVULGE ANYTHING
IS IF IT WERE RELEVANT
TO THE DOCTOR'S MURDER.
WE'LL DO
WHATEVER WE CAN TO HELP.
HOW DID YOU FIND
DR. CORVIS?
CHURCH.
A SUPPORT GROUP.
MY PASTOR RECOMMENDED HIM.
AND WHYDID YOU GO TO HIM?
I'D BEEN STRUGGLING
WITH THESE URGES FOR YEARS.
I'D TRIED EVERYTHING ALREADY --
SUPPORT GROUPS, COUNSELING.
NOTHING HELPED.
DR. CORVIS SAID
HIS TREATMENT WAS DIFFERENT.
DIFFERENT HOW?
HE SAID THE THING I'D STRUGGLED
WITH MY ENTIRE LIFE,
THE THING THAT HAS GIVEN ME
SO MUCH HEARTACHE
WASN'T MY FAULT.
IT WASN'T A CHOICE.
HE SAID IT WAS A DISEASE.
A NEUROCHEMICAL DISORDER,
AND HE COULD TREAT IT.
WHAT WAS
THE TREATMENT REGIMEN?
FIRST,
HE WOULD GIVE ME A PILL.
WE ONLY GOT IT
IN HIS OFFICE.
HE PROMISED US
IT WAS SAFE,
BUT HE SAID IT WASN'T APPROVED
FOR SALE YET OR SOMETHING.
BUT YOU TOOK IT ANYWAY?
I WAS DESPERATE.
I WAS WILLING
TO TRY ANYTHING.
Daniel: WHAT HAPPENED
AFTER YOU TOOK THE PILL?
I GOT THIS...
INCREDIBLE FEELING
OF LOVE.
IT GOT ME EXCITED.
I'D BECOME AROUSED.
AND WE MADE LOVE.
WE WOULD HAVE SEX.
IN FRONT OF HIM?
SOMETIMES HE WOULD
MAKE ME WATCH PORN.
OTHER TIMES HE BROUGHT IN
A SEXUAL SURROGATE.
HE FORCED YOU TO HAVE SEX
WITH NO.OMAN?
I WANTEDTO.
AND HOW DID
THE TREATMENT WORK?
WE HAVEN'T HAD A TREATMENT
IN ALMOST SIX WEEKS.
WE -- WE HAVEN'T
NEEDED IT.
DR. CORVIS
SAVED OUR MARRIAGE.
HE WAS A MIRACLE WORKER.
DR. CORVIS SAVED MY LIFE.
"THE SEX
WAS MIND-BLOWING."
WOW, THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
SOMEINTERVIEW.
NO,
IT'S WHAT MISTY SAID
ABOUT HER BEDROOM GYMNASTICS
WITH CORVIS, REMEMBER?
HE MUST HAVE BEEN GIVING HER
THE DRUG, TOO.
WHAT, VIAGRA?
NO, VIAGRA ONLY AFFECTS
BLOOD FLOW.
CORVIS TOLD HIS PATIENTS
THAT BEING GAY
IS A NEUROCHEMICAL
DISORDER.
AND SINCE THE FEELING
OF BEING IN LOVE ORIGINATES
IN THE PARAVENTRICULAR NUCLEUS
OF THE HYPOTHALAMUS...
[ Laughing ] OH, DANIEL,
YOU'RE SUCH A ROMANTIC.
...THE DRUG
MUST HAVE BEEN SOMETHING
THAT AFFECTED THE BRAIN.
I'M GUESSING SOME SORT OF
SELECTIVE DOPAMINE AGONIST
THAT PRODUCES THE SENSATION
OF BEING IN LOVE.
THEN CORVIS INCORPORATES
SOME COGNITIVE BEHAVIORAL
TECHNIQUES...
SO THE PATIENT EXPERIENCES
THOSE FEELINGS
WHILE HAVING SEX
WITH A FEMALE,
AND THAT BEHAVIOR
IMPRINTS ON THEM
AND CREATES A NEW NORMAL.
SOMEBODY PAID ATTENTION
IN CLASS.
WAIT, SO THIS TREATMENT
ACTUALLY WORKS?
TEMPORARILY, MAYBE, BUT IT'S
NOT SOPHISTICATED ENOUGH
TO CREATE THE KIND OF LASTING
NEUROBIOLOGICAL CHANGES
THAT COULD ACTUALLY ALTER
A PERSON'S SEXUALITY.
BUT IT'S POSSIBLE.
THEORETICALLY,
BUT ETHICALLY?
IF THE DRUG IS STILL IN ANY
OF THE PATIENTS' SYSTEMS,
WE TEST THEIR BLOOD,
WE FIND OUT EXACTLY WHAT IT IS.
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH PROBABLE
CAUSE TO GET A BLOOD ORDER.
PLUS, IT MIGHT BE
PRETTY DIFFICULT
TO GET PERMISSION
FROM THE PATIENTS.
IT'D BE AN ADMISSION THAT
THEY'RE DOING SOMETHING ILLEGAL.
Woman: SILLY DANIEL,
YOU DON'T NEED
ANYONE'S PERMISSION.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I'M JUST SAYING IT MIGHT BE
PRETTY DIFFICULT
TO GET THE PATIENTS
TO COOPERATE.
THAT'S TRUE,
BUT YOU CAN'T REFUSE
TO COOPERATE IF YOU'RE DEAD.
[ LAUGHS]
DID THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE
KEEP SAMPLES
OF CORVIS' BLOOD?
YEAH, OF COURSE.
WHY?
I THINK
WE'RE GONNA FIND TRACES
OF THE DRUG
IN HIS SYSTEM.
BECAUSE HE WANTED TO HAVE
MIND-BLOWING SEX,
JUST LIKE HIS PATIENTS.
I THINK
IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
I THINK HE WAS TRYING
TO CURE HIMSELF.
BECAUSE CORVIS WAS GAY.
THE M.E. TESTED YOUR HUSBAND'S
BLOOD, MRS. CORVIS.
TURNS OUT
HE WAS TREATING HIMSELF
WITH A DRUG CALLED ZR-121,
WHICH CAUSES FEELINGS
OF LOVE AND AROUSAL.
NOW, THE FDA
HASN'T APPROVED IT YET
BECAUSE OF PERVASIVE
SIDE EFFECTS
LIKE HYPERTENSION,
PTOSIS, DRY MOUTH.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
YOUR HUSBAND WAS TRYING TO
CURE HIMSELF OF BEING GAY.
HE DIDCURE HIMSELF.
JULIAN
WAS A REVOLUTIONARY.
HIS METHODS WERE SAVING
MARRIAGES -- SAVING LIVES.
EXCEPT BEING GAY
ISN'T A DISEASE.
CLEARLY,
THAT'S A MATTER OF OPINION.
MY HUSBAND OFFERED HOPE TO
PEOPLE WHO SHARED OUR BELIEFS.
EXCEPT HE NEVER ACTUALLY
CURED HIMSELF.
WE TRACKED
HIS CREDIT-CARD BILL
AND FOUND NUMEROUS CHARGES
TO A COMPANY CALLED C.K.L.
RESTAURANT AND LOUNGE GROUP.
SEEMS IT'S A HOLDING COMPANY
FOR A BAR IN BOYSTOWN.
WE SENT AN AGENT DOWN THERE
TO SEE IF ANYONE RECOGNIZED
YOUR HUSBAND.
AND TURNS OUT,
HE WAS A REGULAR.
I'M SURE HE WAS JUST OFFERING
TO HELP THOSE POOR MEN.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU WANTED YOUR HUSBAND
TO BE STRAIGHT
SO BADLY THAT
YOU EVEN ENCOURAGED HIM
TO CHEAT ON YOU
WITH OTHER WOMEN,
BECAUSE, AS YOU SAID, "THAT'S
JUST WHAT NORMAL MEN DO."
BUT WHEN YOU FOUND OUT
THAT IT WAS ALL A LIE,
THAT HE WAS NEVER GONNA BE
WHAT YOU CONSIDERED NORMAL,
YOU COULDN'T TAKE IT.
AND THAT'S WHEN
YOU KILLED HIM.
I'M NOT SAYING ANOTHER WORD
UNTIL I SPEAK WITH MY ATTORNEY.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
MORETTI.
OH, HEY, MAX.
HE SAYS
IT'S AN EMERGENCY.
LEWICKI?
[ SOBBING ]
SHE'S BEEN LIKE THAT
FOR HOURS.
SHE SAYS
SHE'LL ONLY TALK TO YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
GET HER SOME WATER.
OKAY.
[ SOBBING CONTINUES ]
UH...KARYN?
WHY DON'T YOU, UH...
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU'RE AN EXPERT
ON THE BRAIN, RIGHT?
[ SNIFFLES ]
AND WHY...
WHY PEOPLE DO THE THINGS
THAT THEY DO?
YES,
BUT TO BE HONEST,
HUMAN BEHAVIOR
CONTINUES TO MYSTIFY ME.
OH,
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME!
TELL ME WHY I DO IT.
DO WHAT?
I'VE...
I'VE BEEN
SLEEPING AROUND LATELY.
A LOT.
[ SOBS ]AY.
I HAVE THESE URGES,
AND -- AND I CAN'T CONTROL THEM.
BUT I GOT EXCITED WATCHING
THE GOLF CHANNEL THE OTHER DAY.
IT JUST --
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE!
LIKE SLEEPING WITH MAX --
HE'S A REALLY NICE GUY...
BUT I'M NOT
THAT INTO HIM.
GOD...I WOULD -- I WOULD KILL
FOR A CIGARETTE.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU SMOKED.
WELL, I'VE BEEN
TRYING TO QUIT.
[ SNIFFLES ]
ARE YOU TAKING A PRESCRIPTION
TO HELP YOU WITH THAT?
[ SNIFFLES ]
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
KARYN,
ONE OF THE SIDE EFFECTS
OF SOME OF THOSE ANTI-SMOKING
DRUGS IS HYPERSEXUALITY.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO YOU.
YOU THINK?
[ SIGHS ]
I KNOW THE HEAD OF COUNSELING
AT THE STUDENT HEALTH CENTER.
SHE CAN TALK TO YOU ABOUT
YOUR MEDS AND YOUR OTHER...
ISSUES.
SO WHY DON'T I TAKE YOU
TO SEE HER?
[ SNIFFLES ]
OH, THANK YOU,
PROFESSOR PIERCE!
[ SOBBING, LAUGHING ]
YOU'RE...WELCOME.
DEAN HALEY.
UH, DR. PIERCE
SHOULD BE BACK ANY MINUTE.
NO, I'M ACTUALLY HERE
TO SEE YOU,MR. LEWICKI.
LOOK, LOOK,
I-I-IF IT'S ABOUT THAT GIRL,
I CAN TOTALLY EXPLAIN.
IT'S ABOUT THE CHICAGO
SCIENCE FOUNDATION BENEFIT.
OH...
RIGHT, O-OF COURSE.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
IT WOULD BEHOOVE THE UNIVERSITY
GREATLY, MR. LEWICKI,
IF DR. PIERCE WERE THERE
THIS EVENING ON TIME,
WEARING A TUX...
ANDA SMILE.
THE PROBLEM IS, SIR,
DR. PIERCE WOULD RATHER EAT A
PLATE OF WARM MAYONNAISE THAN --
YEAH, BUT YOU SEE,
TONIGHT COULD MEAN
A LOT OF FUNDING
FOR VERY IMPORTANT PROGRAMS
AT THE SCHOOL,
INCLUDING
TEACHER ASSISTANTSHIPS
IN THE NEUROSCIENCE
DEPARTMENT.
BUT ON THE OTHER HAND,
IF THAT FUNDING SHOULD...
COME UP SHORT...
DO WE UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER,
MR. LEWICKI?
PERFECTLY, SIR.
I'M SO GLAD.
YOU ENJOY THE REST OF YOUR DAY,
MR. LEWICKI.
I KNOW IWILL.
DANIEL.
HA!
WHAT WAS HE DOING HERE?
NOTHING.
HOW'S KARYN?
SHE'LL BE FINE.
SHE WAS PRETTY ASHAMED.
YEAH, ME TOO.
I'M KARYN'S T.A.,
AND I TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THAT.
I ABUSED MY AUTHORITY.
YOU ABUSED YOUR AUTHORITY.
GEEZ, DOC.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
RUB IT IN, OKAY?
I FEEL BAD ENOUGH.
DON'T BE A NARCISSIST, LEWICKI.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT YOU.
I NEED TO CALL KATE.
WHY?
BECAUSE I THINK CORVIS MIGHT
HAVE ABUSED HIS AUTHORITY, TOO.
AND I'M PRETTY SURE
IT'S WHAT GOT HIM KILLED.
Daniel:
THANK YOU FOR COMING BACK.
HI.
Kate:
HI, AGENT MORETTI, FBI.
I...DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY SHE'S HERE.
I THOUGHT EVERYTHING WE TALKED
ABOUT WAS CONFIDENTIAL.
IT IS...
UNLESS IT'S RELEVANT TO
THE CORVIS MURDER INVESTIGATION.
HELLO.
HI.
THOMAS, I NOTICED
YOUR EYE BEFORE.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
LIKE THAT?
THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
A COUPLE WEEKS, MAYBE.
WHY?
ONE OF THE SIDE EFFECTS
OF THE DRUG
CORVIS WAS GIVING YOU
IS PTOSIS,
OTHERWISE KNOWN
AS "DROOPING EYELID."
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
YOUR HUSBAND SHOULDN'T STILL
BE EXPERIENCING SIDE EFFECTS
FROM A DRUG HE SUPPOSEDLY
QUIT TAKING SIX WEEKS AGO.
LOOK, I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS
HAS TO DO WITH ANYTHING.
YOU TOLD DR. PIERCE THE LAST
TIME YOU TOOK THE DRUG
WAS AT YOUR LAST SESSION.
WHY ARE YOU LYING,
THOMAS?
I'M NOTTHOMAS?COFFS ]
OKAY, I WAS STILL TAKING IT,
THE DRUG,
BUT ONLY SO THAT
I COULD BE WITH YOU.
IT HELPS
WITH MY CONDITION.
WHERE'D YOU GET IT?
I HAD SOME LEFT OVER.
YOU BOTH SAID CORVIS INSISTED
YOU ONLY TAKE THE DRUG
IN HIS OFFICE.
I WAS HAVING A RELAPSE,
SO I WENT BACK TO SEE HIM
ON MY OWN.
I DIDN'T TELL YOU BECAUSE
I DIDN'T WANT YOU TO GET UPSET.
YEAH, BUT THAT'S NOT WHY
HE GAVE YOU THE PILLS, IS IT?
YOU AND CORVIS
WERE SLEEPING TOGETHER,
AND YOU WERE TAKING THE DRUGS
TO ENHANCE THE SEX.
THOMAS,
WHAT'S HE TALKING ABOUT?
THAT'S A PRETTY GOOD ACT,
MRS. AKERS.
BUT WE RAN A TRACE,
AND WE FOUND THE .38
THAT YOU REGISTERED IN COLLEGE.
POLICE ARE EXECUTING A SEARCH
WARRANT ON YOUR HOUSE RIGHT NOW,
AND THEY'RE GONNA FIND
THAT GUN.
MICHELLE --
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU FIND OUT HE WAS SLEEPING
WITH CORVIS, SO YOU SHOT HIM?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DID IT. I'M SORRY.
MICHELLE, DON'T.
DON'T.
[ Voice breaking ] I JUST WANTED
A REGULAR MARRIAGE...
LIKE THE KIND YOU SEE
IN THE MOVIES.
THAT'S WHY I FORCED THOMAS
TO GO SEE DR. CORVIS.
'CAUSE I THOUGHT
HE WOULD FIX OUR MARRIAGE.
BUT HE RUINED IT.
SO I GOT MY GUN,
AND I SHOT HIM.
I UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE DOING,
MRS. AKERS.
YOU PUSHED THOMAS
INTO THE TREATMENT.
YOU FEEL RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HANO. NO.
AND YOU LOVE HIM,
SO YOU WANT TO PROTECT HIM.
BUT YOU'RE NOT REALLY
GONNA LET YOUR WIFE
TAKE THE FALL FOR SOMETHING
YOU DID, ARE YOU, THOMAS?
THOMAS,
DON'T SAY ANYTHING.
NO.
NO, HE'S RIGHT.
DON'T...
HE'S RIGHT.
I'VE BEEN CARRYING THIS AROUND
FAR TOO LONG.
WHEN MICHELLE AND I FIRST
STARTED SEEING DR. CORVIS,
THE TREATMENT WAS WORKING.
I WOULD TAKE THE DRUG,
AND IT WOULD MAKE ME FEEL THINGS
FOR MY WIFE.
BUT AS THE SESSIONS CONTINUED,
I STARTED HAVING FEELINGS
FOR JULIAN.
SO HE CALLED ME,
AND HE ASKED ME TO COME IN
FOR A PRIVATE SESSION.
WE STARTED
TALKING ABOUT MY PROBLEM,
BUT WE COULDN'T HELP
OURSELVES.
BUT I HATED MYSELF.
MICHELLE AND I WENT TO JULIAN
SO THAT I COULD BE WITH HER,
BECAUSE I LOVE HER.
WHAT WE WERE DOING WAS WRONG.
SO I WENT BACK TO HIS OFFICE
TO GET THE PILLS SO I COULD USE
THEM WITH MY WIFE.
WHAT YOU AND I ARE, WHAT
WE WANT, IT'S NOT A DISEASE.
I REALIZE THAT NOW.
I-I'VE BEEN TRYING TO CONVINCE
MY PATIENTS, CONVINCE MYSELF!
BUT I'VE BEEN LIVING
A LIE.
I SEE THAT NNO.
WE CAN BE TOGETHER.
I WANT TO BE
WITH MY WIFE!
BUT...
[ Voice breaking ]
...I LOVE YOU.
AND I'M SORRY.
I AM SOSORRY.
Natalie: IT'S TRAGIC.
THREE PEOPLE'S LIVES
DESTROYED
BECAUSE THEY COULDN'T ACCEPT
WHO THEY REALLY WERE.
THE NOTION THAT SOME MAGIC PILL
COULD TAKE AWAY ALL THAT PAIN?
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
PRETTY TEMPTING.
THERE ARE PILLS
YOUCAN TAKE, DANIEL.
YOU KNOW THAT.
AIN'T NO PILL
GONNA CURE MY ILL.
IT WOULD PROBABLY HELP
WITH YOUR SYMPTOMS.
MAYBE MY SYMPTOMS
MAKE ME WHO I AM.
THAT'S A COP-OUT.
YOU KNOW YOU SHOULD BE
ON MEDS.
LET'S GO, DOC.
YOU'RE LATE.
[ GROANS ]
YOU THINK I SHOULD GO?
STOP AVOIDING
THIS CONVERSATION.
OKAY, EITHER YOU PUT IT ON,
OR I STUFF YOU IN IT.
YOU HEARD THE MAN.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
DANIEL!
[ Sighing ]
OH, KATE.
PLEASE TELL ME
YOU'VE GOT ANOTHER CASE
AND YOU'RE GETTING ME
THE [BLEEP] OUT OF HERE.
SO, SORRY. [ CHUCKLES ]
I WOULHI, DANIEL.
I HAD SOME TROUBLE FINDING
A PARKING SPOT. ALLOW ME.
YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL.
WELL, THANK YOU.
YOU CLEAN UP
PRETTY WELL YOURSELF.
AH.
WE WERE GONNA GO GRAB A DRINK.
CARE TO JORIGHT.
NO, I-I THINK I AM
GALA'D OUT TONIGHT.
[ Chuckling ] RIGHT,
WELL, SOME OTHER TIME THEN.
Kate:
SEE YOU, DANIEL.
DANIEL. THERE YOU ARE.
NO, OH...
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
COME ON!
PLEASE,
DON'T MAKE ME.
SHE'S A BIG FAN!
NO, NO, NO.
I JUST WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO ALLISON BANNISTER.
WOW.
YOU ARE NOT OLD.
[ LAUGHS ]
WELL, YOU ARE QUITE
THE OBSERVATIONAL SCIENTIST.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
MRS. BANNISTER, I'M TOLD
THAT I CAN BE, UH, OVERLY BLUNT,
SO FORGIVE ME IN ADVANCE
WHEN I SAY
THAT I AM
ONLY HERE TONIGHT
BECAUSE I'M INTERESTED
I-IN PROCURING SEX.
I MEAN,
MONEY...FOR A DONATION.
WHO KNOWS?
IF YOU PLAY YOUR CARDS RIGHT,
DR. PIERCE,
YOU MIGHT JUST GET BOTH.
WOW.
NICE WORK, HMM?
Daniel: IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG
WITH ME?
IT'S A QUESTION
WE ALL ASK OURSELVES.
WE ALL WONDER WHY WE DON'T
LOOK LIKE, ACT LIKE,
FEEL LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE.
EACH OF OUR BRAINS
HAS THE EXACT SAME PARTS --
CORTEX, HYPOTHALAMUS, FORNIX,
SEPTAL NUCLEUS, SO ON.
AND YET, NO TWO BRAINS
ARE EXACTLY ALIKE.
SO, BEING DIFFERENT...
...BEING UNIQUE...
...IS UNDENIABLY
A FUNDAMENTAL CHARACTERISTIC...
...OF BEING HUMAN.