Subs created by: David Coleman.
Does freewill exist?
Do I exert conscious
control over my actions?
Did I do that on purpose?
I'm pretty sure you did.
Or was I forced to do it by
some unseen neural process?
Fact is most of the neural-scientific
data suggests freewill..
Is an illusion.
Now if that's true.
Are we simply meat-puppets?
All of our choices made for us?
The answer to that can be found..
In our next class. Bye!
That's brilliant Daniel.
Ending the class on a cliff-hanger
always keeps them coming back for more.
- The answer is "no".
- To what?
To what ever it is you're about to ask me.
Unless I'm misinterpreting
the blatant ego stroking.
I simply want to make sure
you are planning to attend
the Chicago Science
Foundation Gala on Friday.
Ah. You lost me at gala.
I really need you there Daniel.
- Why?
- Because.
Johnathan Bannister's widow
is going to be there.
I don't know who that is.
Class of '49. Anyway I played golf
with him a couple of months ago..
And by the end of the eighth hole..
I had him verbally committed to funding
the new Life Sciences building.
But a couple of days later,
before I can get it in writing,
the guy goes and dies of a heart attack.
How inconsiderate of him.
I feel badly about it of course.
But I'm hoping to get his widow
to honor her husbands promise.
I'm still waiting to hear
what this has to do with me.
Well, as luck would have it Mrs.
Bannister..
Fan of yours.
No. No. No, I am not..
Going to let you pimp
me to some "blue-hair".
Just so the under graduates have a shiny
new building to store their mice.
No I don't have time
anyway, I'm right in the
middle of some very important experiments.
What experiments?
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Daniel?
What are you doing?
Did you know that pigeons
brains contain magnetite?
I did not know that.
Let's them sense the Earth's
magnetic field and orientates them
so can get where they're
going without getting lost.
Here's the thing pigeons mate for life.
I'm wondering, after a while does the
female just follow her chosen male..
Or does she still use the magnetite
in her brain to choose her own route?
Probably depends on whether
he's buying her dinner.
You don't think they are going
to follow me home do you?
To what do I owe the pleasure?
How would you like to help the FBI bring
down a big bad insurance company?
See I knew this was going to be a good day.
What did they do deny somebody benefits?
Actually they might have committed murder.
Sanjay Patel.
A couple of months ago he was admitted to
the ER complaining of severe depression.
Suicidal thoughts.
Janstar health was his insurance
provider at the time.
They authorized one day of hospitalization.
- That's generous.
- It gets worse.
After he's discharged Janstar recommended..
Out-patient treatment, by a psychiatrist.
Dr. Julian Corvis.
Corvis treats Sanjay for four sessions.
Then stops treatment, says Sanjay's cured.
Of severe depression, in four sessions?
Bullshit.
Yeah. I'm sure Sanjay's Mother
shares your skepticism.
Next morning she found him
hanging in his closet.
How does a Doctor that incompetent
keep his medical license?
I do not know.
What I do know is that he will
never be treating patients again.
He was found dead in his office yesterday.
Shot in the face by a thirty-eight.
Wallet was still on him, so robbery is out.
Safe was open, but there
were still valuables inside.
It's unclear whether or
not anything was removed.
Sanjay's family seeking payback?
They seem to be going through
the proper channels.
They filed a wrongful death suit
against Janstar and Corvis.
And alerted the U.S. Attorney's office,
which launched an investigation.
FBI approached Corvis about testifying
against Janstar and he
agreed on one condition.
Immunity.
The terms of which were still being
negotiated, when he was killed.
So you think Janstar hired
a hit man to silence..
I am not assigned to
investigate the murder.
- But you said..
- My involvement in this case
is limited to the wrongful death suit.
We need to find out what
was in Corvis's files.
You can't look at medical
files, they're confidential.
That's why I need a special master.
Special what?
A knowledgeable and impartial
third party to review the files.
And report on what Corvis was
going to tell the U.S. Attorney.
Without revealing any personal information.
That's why I convinced the
US Attorney to appoint you.
Ah.
Well as flattered as I am
that you think I'm special..
I know you Kate..
And there's no way you're not
curious about who killed Corvis.
I've been in some hot water
with the boss lately.
He says I keep stepping outside
my circle of responsibility.
So this time I am staying
inside the circle.
So what exactly is the
diameter of this circle?
Pretty small.
- Hey Kate.
- Michael.
Let me guess.
You're here to take me to lunch.
Actually I am here to see Daniel.
Uh, sorry.
Sorry do you two know each other?
Of course. I mean half the
reason I joined the faculty
was to say I have worked
with the great Dr. Pierce.
Good to see you Daniel.
So.. When are we getting together again?
Well, I don't know I might have..
We have something that we're doing.
Sorry.
Totally understand I'll call you.
Okay.
Where do you think you're going?
I'm the only one who's allowed
to look at these files.
I'm only going up to unlock the office.
Just so you remember.
You're the special master I got it.
It's a fresh crime scene this
seal is supposed to be intact.
Wait here.
Mrs. Corvis?
It was on our honeymoon Bora Bora.
It was the happiest week of my life.
The FBI should have protected Julian.
Maybe you should get her home.
You sure?
I'll be fine.
Mrs. Corvis..
We're going to do everything we can
to find the person who did this.
How is she?
Getting some rest.
You find anything?
Apparently Corvis was
miraculously curing his Janstar
patients of major disorders
in just a few sessions.
Where as patients from other
carriers, same disorders..
He'd see thirty of forty times.
So you think Janstar was getting Corvis
to turn their patients then dump them.
Yup. They paid him a major bonus
every time he cut somebody loose.
They'd save a bundle.
He'd fill his schedule with
patients that were from other
carriers or paying cash.
Nice work Daniel.
You testify to this, the U.S.
Attorney should be able to nail Janstar.
There's something else. Look at this.
Corvis was diagnosing a disorder called
Transformation Dopamine Deficiency.
- Never heard of it.
- Neither have I.
It's not in the Diagnostic
Statistical Manual.
Do you think it's related
to the Janstar scam?
No. Everyone with this
diagnosis was paying cash.
Suspicious, right?
If it's not related to Janstar
it's outside the circle.
- It doesn't make any sense..
- Outside the circle.
You found the smoking gun.
I'll Buy you a celebratory slice of pizza.
Malnati's?
Did you know that humans
are the only species
that drinks the milk of another animal?
It's.. It's unnatural, the
lactose turning away we..
Okay Daniel I am not hungry any more.
Lewicki..
Oh, hi Professor Pierce.
Got a sec?
Excuse me.
What is that girls doing here?
Uh, I'm Karen's teaching assistant.
She asked for my help and I'm helping her.
Oh, so you couldn't help her
at the dorm, or the library?
- What's your point?
- My point is, that girl stalked me.
She almost got me fired now shes
finagled her way in to my house.
- She has ulterior motives.
- Okay maybe she does.
Okay now that we see eye to eye.
Get out of here.
Ever occur to you that her
ulterior motive is to get with me?
Hey Max, I should go. It's getting late.
Um, okay yeah, I'll..
I'll walk you back to your dorm.
See ya Professor Pierce.
I think you're just jealous.
Of Lewicki?
That girl took her shirt
off in your office.
And you didn't find her
the least bit attractive?
I may be crazy from the neck up,
but from the waist down I assure
you I'm perfectly healthy.
When was the last time you had a date?
Is that a proposition?
In your dreams.
Hey we had fun together.
Had past tense. You need to find
somebody in the here and now.
Like your friend Kate is
doing with Michael Hathaway.
Oh..
That's called setting the bar so
low that anyone is acceptable.
As opposed to setting the
bar so unrealistically high
that you never have to show
another person the real you?
Are you feeling okay?
I'm having some symptoms, but
I know they're symptoms.
Such as?
I'm being followed by a Government
Agent in a black S.U.V.
Are you sure it's a hallucination?
Black S.U.V.? Mirrored shades.
Straight out of the
Paranoid Skitzo handbook.
I dropped Karen off at her dorm uh..
I'm gonna crash.
You need anything first?
Don't forget your umbrellas or
otherwise you could get all wet.
50 percent chance of rain.
How does this woman stay employed
when her forecast is basically..
It might rain or it might not.
Well I think she has other assets
that keep her employed Doc.
Winds creeping in from North-West Indiana.
Clearly understanding
meteorology isn't one of them.
That's not a very nice thing to say Daniel.
By the weekend, it looks
like more of the same.
So I miss a tropical
depression once in a while.
You can miss depression too. Can't you?
But the weather should be improving..
I missed something.
Good news is were not expecting
any more rain on the horizon.
And right now it's just a
lovely evening out there.
You okay Doc?
Get the car.
Daniel, what are you doing?
You're supposed to wait for me.
I think I know who killed Corvis.
- Who?
- I can't tell you.
Why not?
Because it's outside the circle.
Your son was Dr. Corvis's patient.
He just went the one time.
Were you aware that..
Justin threatened to kill him?
No.
No I wasn't.
You don't think he had
anything to do with..
At this point we just want to talk to him.
During his session Justin
became aggressive and violent.
So much so, that Doctor Corvis
recommended he find a new therapist.
- Did he?
- No.
No he came home that day
shouting and screaming and..
He was angry at me for
sending him to see Corvis.
And then he just..
Then he just took off.
His Mother..
She knew how to handle Justin
a lot better than I did.
She died three years ago.
Must have been very hard for both of you.
Is that why you thought Justin
should see a therapist?
No he..
He handled it pretty well, you
know all things considered.
He loved his music.
He had plenty of good friends. And uh..
And then everything just changed.
How?
Teenage stuff mostly.
He started running around
with the wrong crowd.
And I thought Corvis could help him get
back on the right track. You know?
Dr. Corvis diagnosed him with something
called Transformation Dopamine Deficiency.
Do you know what that means?
Uh, I'm sorry I don't.
And you have no idea where
Justin is right now?
I haven't seen my son
since he left this house.
If you find him. Please..
Will you tell him that I am sorry?
About everything.
Thanks.
No hits on Justin Reycraft
with FBI or Chicago P.D.
Think he'll turn up?
It's hard to say. Sometimes runaways
do just drop off the grid completely.
But we've got an APB out.
So uh..
Your boss knows you've
drifted outside the circle?
Yeah, he's giving me a little leeway.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
I was just trying to figure out
what this diagnosis means.
What the..
Federal Agent hands where I can see 'em.
Out of the car!
You better have one hell
of a good reason for
following us around the
past couple of days.
I don't believe it.
Secret Service guy in aviator sun glasses,
and a black S.U.V.
was really following us?
I know..
How cliche. Right?
Pulled you personnel file Vincent.
Nine complaints of excessive force.
Drinking on the job.
You want to tell me what a burn out cop
is doing following around the FBI?
You want to know what's great about
not being on the job any more?
Hmm?
I don't have to talk to people like you.
Want to know what else is great about
you not being a cop any more Vincent?
Is that no one will give a rats ass when I
ship you for assaulting a Federal Agent.
Never laid a finger on you.
It's too bad you didn't pay
more attention in the academy.
Because then you would
know that hitting my car..
Qualifies as assault.
A felony even.
I'm working as an investigator
for Janstar, so what.
So what happened?
They find out Corvis was gonna testify.
So they sent you to dig up some
dirt to blackmail him with?
Or maybe..
They sent you to silence him for good.
I was just hired to follow him.
Dig up dirt like you said.
Well if you were following him,
maybe you saw who killed him.
I was at an AA meeting when it happened.
By the time I got back to his office
it was already a crime scene.
The cop in me is curious, so I hung
around and when you and your..
Weird Professor friend..
Show up. I run a background
find out who he is.
Report back to Janstar that maybe
he's gonna testify in Corvis's place.
So they told you to follow Dr.
Pierce, dig up some dirt on him too?
Instead of riding me why aren't you looking
for the guy who threatened
Corvis last week?
Keep talking.
He goes to some girls apartment,
comes out about an hour later.
Some big guy's waiting
for him, throws Corvis
up against a car threatens
to break his head.
Give me a name.
I didn't get his name.
But I got the girls.
I loved Julian.
But you knew he was married Misty.
I couldn't help myself.
We just had this crazy connection.
And the sex was absolutely mind blowing.
I would know too, I've
had like a ton of sex.
Huh.
But with Julian it was different.
He was so in to experimenting
and exploring..
Sounds awesome Misty.
But this is a murder investigation.
Now a witness says they saw Corvis
being threatened outside your place.
What do you know about that?
It was probably Toby, my ex.
He's got a really bad temper.
And he was pretty upset when I
started sleeping with Julian.
Alright, I need you to wait in the car.
Toby Mulligan?
Who's asking?
FBI I've got a couple questions for you.
Just let me finish this set.
Actually I need to talk to you right now.
Okay sure.
What? I waited in the car.
Yeah, I got in his face.
But it didn't hurt him.
I wasn't even in town last Friday.
- Then why'd you run?
- I thought this was about the steroids.
I totally have a prescription
for those by the way.
Admit it Toby, you were pissed off
because some Joe shmoe Doctor
half your size was giving it to
your girl and she was liking it.
So you made him pay.
I told you I didn't kill him.
When did you find out she was seeing him?
You mean sleeping together as his patient?
Misty was Corvis's patient?
She started seeing him, for
her self esteem issues.
She seemed pretty confident to me.
Maybe he cured her.
He got inside her head.
Tricked her somehow.
There's no way she'd have
cheated on me otherwise.
I even told his wife about it.
Thought that would end it, but it didn't.
Of course I knew.
I knew about all of my husbands affairs.
How many were there?
A few. Nothing out of the ordinary.
Hm.
I liked that other women
found my husband attractive.
It made me feel lucky to have him.
Oh, you have a very progressive attitude
towards your husbands
extracurricular activity's.
That's just what normal men do.
Hm.
That woman is lying.
Everyone has a different
attitude, when it come to sex.
You get cheated on you
feel angry, betrayed.
You want someone to pay, trust me.
It doesn't sound like you're being
entirely objective Agent Moretti.
Sorry. Look, I'm just saying she might seem
like the poster child for cool right now.
But maybe when she found out
Corvis was cheating on her.
She got jealous and killed him.
But you didn't accuse her.
That's because I don't
have any evidence.. Yet.
I gotta look in to her movements
on the day of the murder.
Drop you back at campus?
Look at us. Just a couple of higher order
primates competing for a sexual partner.
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm talking about Kate of course.
And well I'll just say it..
I sense she's very attracted to me.
But if your planning to plant your
flag in that terra incognita..
Then just say the word and
I'll gracefully withdraw.
Look.. If your done mangling
metaphors I have a class.
So you don't mind?
Lewicki?
Lewicki!
Lewicki.
- Yea.
- Lewick..
Where the hell were you?
You were supposed to bring my
notes for the Neural Anatomy seminar.
I had to cancel.
Look I'm sorry Doc. I'm sorry. What..
What happened was I had
to take my clothes off..
To do the laundry and uh..
I put my clothes in the wash and uh..
When I came back to check on them
the washer was set on delicate.
So I had to wash them all over again.
Hey Professor Pierce.
Yeah. I.. I.. Told you she was in to me.
Uh, Dr. Pierce's residence.
One sec.
It's Kate.
Hello.
Chicago P.D. picked up Justin Reycraft.
You know the kid who was
threatening Corvis.
Panhandling in Millennium Park.
They're bringing him in to talk
to me, you want to come say hi?
You have no idea, how much.
So then you won't be back for awhile?
Why'd you run away Justin?
I didn't.
My Dad kicked me out.
Why.. Why did he do that?
Because I wouldn't go back
to see that weirdo Corvis.
Mr. Corvis says here in his
files that you threatened him.
- Did you kill him?
- No.
I didn't kill him.
What made you so angry at him?
That guy was a total freak.
Okay.
We just want to hear
your side of the story.
My Dad forced me to go see Corvis.
Then he gives me some pill.
What kind of pill?
I don't know.
Maybe one of those pills they give to old
men to make them all hot and bothered.
Guess it was supposed to
do the same thing to me.
Then he..
Makes me watch all this porn.
It was girls with other girls.
Then he wants me to..
You know.
While I'm watching the porn.
In front of him.
He said it would help re-teach my brain.
He said it was part of the cure.
Cure for what?
The cure for being gay.
Thank you.
Well, Justins alibi checks out.
He was at the Mercy Shelter
the night Corvis was killed.
Of course he didn't do it. He's a sweet
kid who's philistine Father conveniently
fails to mention that he threw his own
son out of the house for being gay.
Or how'd he put it?
Hanging with the wrong crowd.
He sounded pretty remorseful
when I talked to him.
And incredibly relived
that Justin was okay.
You know I think there's a chance
those two could work things out.
Well at least now we know what
Transformation Dopamine Deficiency is.
It's Corvis's code for homosexuality.
It's so sad that someone could
be so ashamed of who the are.
That they'd go to some
quack Doctor to cure them.
Grow up with a family that tells you that
your basic impulses are morally repugnant.
You might try anything to
make yourself feel normal.
Kids kill themselves because of it.
Okay, but is it relevant
to who killed Corvis?
He creates a disorder..
That doesn't exist. Then he comes up
with a treatment regiment for it.
And Justin was pretty angry at Corvis
for putting him through it so..
Maybe one of his other
patients is angry too.
We can't interview them
because of confidentially.
You cant..
But I can.
- Because I'm..
- The special master.
How could I forget?
This is completely confidential.
The only way I'd divulge anything is if
it were relevant to the Doctor's murder.
We'll do what ever we can to help.
How did you find Dr. Corvis?
Church.
A support group.
My pastor recommended him.
And why did you go to him?
I've been struggling with
these urges for years.
I tried everything already.
Support groups, counseling.
Nothing helped.
Dr. Corvis said his
treatment was different.
Different how?
He said that the thing that I
struggled with my entire life.
The thing that has given
me so much heartache.
Wasn't my fault.
It wasn't a choice.
He said it was disease.
A Neurochemical Disorder
and he could treat it.
What was the treatment regimen?
First he would give me a pill.
- What pill?
- We only got it in his office.
He promised us it was safe, but he said it
wasn't approved for sale yet or something.
But you took it anyway?
I was desperate.
I was willing to try anything.
What happened after you took the pill?
I got this..
Incredible feeling of love.
Got me excited.
I'd become aroused.
Then we made love.
We would have sex.
In front of him?
Sometimes he would make me watch porn.
Other time he brought
in a sexual surrogate.
He forced you to have sex with a woman?
No. I wanted to.
And how did the treatment work?
We haven't had a treatment
in almost six weeks.
We..
We haven't needed it.
Dr. Corvis saved our marriage.
He was the miracle worker.
Dr. Corvis saved my life.
The sex was mind blowing.
Wow that must have been some interview.
It's what Misty said about her bedroom
gymnastics with Corvis, remember?
He must have been giving her the drug too.
- What Viagra?
- No Viagra only affects blood flow.
Corvis told his patients that being
gay is a Neurochemical Disorder.
It's like the feeling of
being in love originates
in the paraventricular
nucleus of the hypothalamus.
Oh, Daniel you're such a romantic.
The drug must have been something
that affected the brain.
I'm guessing some kind of
selective dopamine agonist.
That produces the sensation
of being in love.
Then Corvis incorporates some
cognitive behavioral techniques.
So the patient experiences those feelings,
while having sex with a female
and that behavior imprints,
on them and creates a new normal.
Somebody paid attention in class.
Wait so this treatment actually works?
Temporarily maybe. But it's not
sophisticated enough to create the kind of
lasting neurobiological changes that could
actually alter a person's sexuality.
But it's possible?
Theoretically. But ethically?
If the drugs are still in any
of the patients systems..
We test their blood, we find
out exactly what it is.
We don't have enough probable
cause to get a blood order.
Plus it might be pretty difficult to
get permission from the patients.
It would be an admission that they
were doing something illegal.
Silly Daniel you don't
need anyone's permission.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying it might pretty difficult
to get the patients to cooperate.
That's true but you can't refuse
to cooperate if you're dead.
Did the medical examiner's office
keep samples of Corvis's blood?
Yeah, of course why?
I think we're going to find
traces of the drug in his system.
Because he wanted to have mind
blowing sex just like his patients.
I think it's more then that.
I think he was trying to cure himself.
Because Corvis was gay.
The M.E. tested your
husbands blood Mrs. Corvis.
Turns out he was treating himself with
a drug called ZR-121 which causes..
Feelings of love and arousal.
Now the FDA hasn't approved it yet
because of pervasive side effects.
Like Hypertension,
Ptosis, Dry Mouth.
What's your point?
Your husband was trying to cure himself..
Of being gay.
He did cure himself.
Julian was a revolutionary.
His methods were saving marriages.
Saving lives.
Except, being gay isn't a disease.
Clearly that's a matter of opinion.
My husband offered hope to
people who shared our beliefs.
Except he never actually cured himself.
We tracked his credit card
bill and found numerous..
Charges to a company called CKL
Restaurant & Lounge Group.
Seems it's a holding company
for a bar in boys town.
We sent an Agent down there to see
if anybody recognized your husband.
And turns out he was a regular.
I'm sure he was just offering
to help those poor men.
You wanted your husband to be straight.
So badly that you even encouraged him
to cheat on you with other women.
Because as you said that's
just what normal men do.
But when you found out
that it was all a lie..
That he was never going to be
what you considered normal..
You couldn't take it.
And that's when you killed him.
I'm not saying another word
until I speak with my attorney.
Moretti.
Oh hey Max.
He says it's an emergency.
Lewicki?
She's been like that for hours.
She says she'll only talk to you.
Alright. Get her some water.
Okay.
Uh.. Karen?
Why don't you uh..
Why don't you tell me what's wrong?
You're an expert on the brain right?
And why..
Why people do the things that they do?
Yes. But to be honest human
behaviour continues to mystify me.
That's why you just have to help me.
Tell me why I do it.
Do what?
I've..
I've been sleeping around lately.
- A lot.
- Okay, okay.
I have these urges and..
And I can't control them and..
I got excited watching the
golf channel the other day.
It just.. It doesn't make any sense.
Like sleeping with Max.
He's a really nice guy.
But I'm not that in to him.
I..
I would.. I would kill for a cigarette.
I didn't know you smoked.
Oh, I've been trying to quit.
Are you taking a prescription
to help you with that?
How did you know?
Karen one of the side effects of some of
those anti-smoking drugs
is hyper-sexuality.
Maybe that's what's happening to you.
You think?
I know the Head of Counseling
at the Student Health Center.
She can talk to you about
your meds and your other..
Issues. So why..
Why don't I take you to see her?
Oh thank you Professor Pierce.
You're welcome.
Dean Haley.. Uh, Dr.
Pierce should be back any minute.
No I'm actually here to
see you Mister Lewicki.
Look if it's about that girl,
I can totally explain.
Its about the Chicago
Science Foundation benefit.
Oh.
Right. Of.. Of course.
It would behoove the university greatly..
Mr. Lewicki if Doctor Pierce were
there this evening on time..
Wearing a tux. And a smile.
The problem is, Sir..
Dr. Pierce would rather eat a
plate of warm mayonnaise then..
Yeah, but you see tonight could mean..
A lot of funding for very
important programs..
At the school including
teacher assistant-ships
in the Neuroscience Department.
But on the other hand if
that funding should..
Come up short..
Do we understand each other Mister Lewicki?
Perfectly, Sir.
I'm so glad.
You enjoy the rest of your day.
Mr. Lewicki.. I know I will.
- Daniel.
- Huh.
- What was he doing here?
- Nothing.
How's Karen?
She'll be fine.
She was pretty ashamed.
Yeah, me too.
I'm Karen's T.A.
and I took advantage of that.
I abused my authority.
You abused your authority.
Geez Doc, you don't have
to rub it in, okay.
I feel bad enough.
Don't be a narcissist Lewicki,
this isn't about you.
I gotta call Kate.
Why?
Because I think Corvis might
have abused his authority too.
I'm pretty sure it's what got him killed.
Thank you for coming back.
- Hi.
- Hi Agent Moretti, FBI.
I don't understand why she's here.
I thought everything we talked
about was confidential.
It is.
Unless it's relevant to the
Corvis murder investigation.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Thomas, I noticed your eye before.
How long has it been like that?
This? I don't know.
Couple weeks maybe, why?
One of the side effects of the drug
Corvis was giving you is Ptosis.
Otherwise known as drooping eyelid.
What's this all about?
Your husband shouldn't still
be experiencing side effects,
from a drug he supposedly
quit taking six weeks ago.
I.. I.. Don't know what
this has to with any..
You told Dr. Pierce the last time you
took the drug was at your last session.
Why are you lying Thomas?
- I'm not..
- Thomas?
Okay I'm still taking it, the drug.
But only so that I could be with you.
It helps with my condition.
Where'd you get it?
I had some left over.
But you both said Corvis insisted you
only take the drug in his office.
I was having a relapse.
So I went back to see him on my own.
I didn't tell you because I
didn't want you to get upset.
Yeah, but that's not why he
gave you the pills, is it?
You and Corvis were
sleeping together and you
were taking the drugs to enhance the sex.
Thomas what's he talking about?
That's a pretty good act Mrs. Akers.
But we ran a trace and we found the
thirty-eight that you
registered in college.
Police are executing a search
warrant on your house right now.
And they're going to find that gun.
Michelle..
What happened?
You find out he was sleeping
with Corvis so you shot him?
That's not..
You're right. I did it I'm sorry.
Michelle, don't.
Don't.
I just wanted a regular marriage.
Like the kind you see in the movies.
That's why I forced Thomas
to go see Dr. Corvis.
Because I thought he
would fix our marriage.
But he ruined it.
So I got my gun, and I shot him.
I understand what you're doing Mrs. Akers.
You pushed Thomas in to the treatment.
You feel responsible for what happened.
- No. No.
- You love him so you want to protect him.
But you're not really going to let your
wife take the fall for something you did..
Are you Thomas?
Thomas, don't say anything.
- No. No he's right.
- Don't.
He's right I've been carrying
this around far too long.
When Michelle and I first
started seeing Dr. Corvis..
The treatment was working.
I would take the drug and it would
make me feel things for my wife. But..
As the sessions continued.
I started having feelings for Julian.
So he called me and asked me to
come in for a private session.
I started talking about my problem but..
We couldn't help ourselves.
I hated myself.
Michelle and I went to Julian
so that I could be with her.
Because I love her.
What we were doing was wrong.
So I went back to his
office to get the pills.
So I could use them with my wife.
What you and I are. What we want.
It's not a disease I realize that now.
I.. I've been trying to convince
my patients, convince myself..
But I've been living a lie.
- I see that now.
- No.
We can be together.
I want to be with my wife.
I love you.
And I'm sorry.
I am so.. Sorry.
It's tragic.
Three peoples lives destroyed because they
couldn't accept who they really were.
A notion that some magic pill
could take away all that pain.
Must have been pretty tempting.
There are pills you can
take Daniel, you know that.
Ain't no pill gonna cure my ill.
It would probably help with your symptoms.
Maybe my symptoms make me who I am.
That's a cop out.
You know you should be on meds.
Let's go Doc, you're late.
Ugh.
You think I should go?
Stop avoiding this conversation.
Okay either you put it on,
or I stuff you in it.
You heard the man.
Daniel.
Kate please tell me
you've got another case.
And you're getting me the hell out of here.
- I wouldn't say..
- So sorry.
Hi Daniel. I had some trouble
finding a parking spot.
Allow me.
You look beautiful.
Well thank you.
You clean up pretty well yourself.
Ha. Well..
We were going to grab a drink.
Care to join us?
No, I think I am..
Gala-ed out tonight.
Right, well some other time then.
Mm-hm.
See ya Daniel.
Daniel. There you are come on.
- No Paul.
- No, no, no come on.
- Don't make me..
- Shes a big fan.
No I just want to introduce
you to Allison Bannister.
Wow you are not old.
Well you are quite the
observational scientist.
Mrs. Bannister I'm told that I can be uh,
overly blunt so uh, forgive me in advance.
When I say that I am only here tonight.
Because I'm interested in procuring sex.
I mean money.
For a donation.
Who knows.. If you play your
cards right Dr. Pierce..
You might just get both.
Wow.
Nice work, huh?
Is there something wrong with me?
It's a question we all ask ourselves.
We all wonder why we don't look like,
act like, feel like everybody else.
Each of our brains has
the exact same parts.
The Cortex, Hypothalamus,
Fornix, Septal Nucleus so on..
And yet..
No two brains are exactly alike.
So being different..
Being unique..
Is undeniably a fundamental characteristic.
Of being human.
Subs created by: David Coleman.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org
www.tvsubtitles.net