HOW BAD DO YOU WANT IT?
WHETHER "IT" BE A 4.0 GPA,
A MILLION BUCKS,
OR JUST GETTING LAID.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AMBITION DRIVES US ALL --
WHAT WILLIAM JAMES CALLED
"THE WORSHIP
OF THE [BLEEP] GODDESS SUCCESS."
NOW, FREUD
WOULD HAVE US BELIEVE
THAT ALL DRIVES
STEM FROM THE LIBIDO.
SORRY, SIGMUND.
SUCCESS IS NEUROLOGICALLY
DETERMINED
BY ONE'S ABILITY TO STAY FOCUSED
ON A TASK,
AND PERSISTENCE IS A FUNCTION
OF AN ACTIVE LIMBIC SYSTEM.
TAKE, FOR INSTANCE,
GRIDIRON GUY HERE.
CLEARLY, HIS LIMBIC SYSTEM
ISN'T FIRING ON ALL CYLINDERS.
EITHER THAT, OR HIS AMBITION
TO WIN THE HEISMAN
SUPERCEDES HIS DESIRE...
TO PASS THIS CLASS!
SORRY.
MORNING, SUNSHINE.
SPEAKING OF PASSING THIS CLASS,
PLEASE PASS YOUR MIDTERM PAPERS
TO MR. LEWICKI HERE.
HIS AMBITION
IS TO READ THEM ALL...
TONIGHT.
[ SIGHS ]
I DON'T THINK ANY OF THEM EVEN
REMEMBERED TO SPELL-CHECK.
PERSISTENCE, LEWICKI.
ONCE IN A WHILE,
A STUDENT SURPRISES YOU.
ACTUALLY,
BRIAN CAHILL DID.
I DON'T KNOW
WHO THAT IS.
"GRIDIRON GUY"?
AH. SLEEPING BEAUTY.
MAYBE YOUR LECTURE
WASN'T INTERESTING ENOUGH
TO KEEP HIM AWAKE,
BUT HIS PAPER'S
ACTUALLY PRETTY GOOD.
TOO GOOD.
HIS PAPER IS OBVIOUSLY
PLAGIARIZED.
THERE'S NO WAY
THAT KID WROTE THIS.
I'M NOT SO SURE. CAHILL'S
BEEN GETTING PRETTY GOOD GRADES.
CLEARLY FROM TEACHERS
WHO TURN A BLIND EYE
TO THE SHORTCOMINGS
OF A "STUDENT-ATHLETE."
THERE'S AN OXYMORON
IF I'VE EVER HEARD ONE.
WELL, I'M NOT DAZZLED
BY HIS ATHLETIC PROWESS.
WE HAVE AN HONOR SYSTEM HERE.
HE SHOULD BE OUT.
YOU'RE GETTING AHEAD
OF YOURSELF, DANIEL.
NOW, FIRST OF ALL, THERE'S
NO PROOF THAT HE CHEATED.
AND LET ME GUESS -- SECOND
OF ALL, HE'S A FOOTBALL STAR.
I'M NOT GONNA DENY
HAVING AN ALL-AMERICAN
IS GOOD FOR RECRUITING,
NOT TO MENTION THE BOTTOM LINE.
LOOK, HAVE YOU ANY IDEA
HOW MUCH WE EARN
IN BROADCAST FEES ALONE?
IT'S NOT LIKE MY DEPARTMENT
SEES ANY OF THAT.
NO, BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO
EXPLAIN TO THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES
WHY YOU EXPELLED
A STAR LINEBACKER
AND SCREWED UP A SHOT
AT A BOWL BERTH.
GREAT. GREAT.
W-WE JETTISON OUR ACADEMIC
STANDARDS FOR FILTHY LUCRE.
WHAT'S NEXT,
AUTOMATIC GPA INFLATION
EVERY TIME SOME YAHOO
SCORES A TOUCHDOWN?
HANG ON. I'M GONNA HAVE TO
DEAL WITH THIS LATER.
SOMETHING'S COME UP.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT
THAN A CAMPUS CHEATING SCANDAL?
A CAMPUS MURDER.
Kate:
DINNER WAS AMAZING.
I GOT THE RECIPE FROM AN ANCIENT
BERBER WOMAN IN MARRAKECH.
OF COURSE,
TO BE TRULY AUTHENTIC,
I SHOULD HAVE MADE IT
WITH PIGEON,
BUT THE BUTCHER
AT WHOLE FOODS
WAS APPALLED
WHEN I ASKED FOR IT,
SO WE HAD TO SETTLE
FOR CHICKEN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WELL, IT WAS
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
THANK YOU.
I PULL MY OWN WARKA.
THE DOUGH.
OF COURSE.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
AAH. EXCUSE ME.
HELLO?
I'LL BE RIGHT OVER.
I HAVE TO GO.
I'M S-- IT'S DANIEL.
OF COURSE IT IS.
YOU LOOK LOVELY. I'M SORRY
IF WE RUINED A SPECIAL EVENING.
OH, NO.
NOT AT ALL.
THE MULTITALENTED
PROFESSOR HATHAWAY?
I UNDERSTAND YOU TWO
MIGHT BE QUITE AN ITEM.
W-WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME, UH,
MORE ABOUT THE MURDER?
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
WELL, CAMPUS SECURITY DISCOVERED
A BODY IN BROOKS HALL.
A JUNIOR,
CHRISTINA LAKE.
OKAY. DO THEY HAVE
A CAUSE OF DEATH?
A BROKEN NECK.
OOH. THAT'S AWFUL.
BUT I'M -- I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST --
I'M STILL A LITTLE CONFUSED
AS TO WHY I'M HERE.
I MEAN, CHICAGO P.D.
WILL CATCH THIS CASE.
WELL, THEY DID.
BUT I WANTED TO SEND A MESSAGE
TO THE PARENTS AND ALUMNI
THAT WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING
WE CAN TO KEEP THE CAMPUS SAFE.
SO I MADE A REQUEST
THAT THE FBI INVESTIGATE.
WELL, NOT TO BEAT
A DEAD CLICHé,
BUT THIS IS NOT EXACTLY
A FEDERAL CASE.
I MEAN, IT'S NOT TERRORISM
OR A SCHOOL SHOOTING.
SO I'LL TALK
TO THE INVESTIGATING OFFICER,
BUT HE MIGHT NOT LIKE
ME BUTTING IN.
ALSO, MY BOSS
MIGHT HAVE AN ISSUE WITH IT,
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
HMM. EXCUSE ME.
WOW.
SPEAK OF THE DEVIL.
MORETTI.
YES. I'M ON IT.
YOU CALLED REARDON?
I JUST...
WANTED TO REMIND HER
THE -- HOW MANY CASES
I'VE HELPED THE BUREAU CLOSE.
AND IT WOULD BE A SHAME
IF I GOT SO BUSY
THAT I COULDN'T KEEP...
HELPING.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER TO BE
SHOCKED OR IMPRESSED.
Daniel: WE SHOULD START
AT BROOKS HALL,
TALK TO CHRISTINA'S
FRIENDS.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA. THIS IS NOT
YOUR CASE. THERE'S NO "WE."
THERE'S NO NEUROLOGICAL
OR BEHAVIORAL ANGLE HERE.
WHAT?
SORRY.
ONE OF MY STUDENTS
HASN'T BEEN SHOWING UP TO CLASS.
I ASSUMED HE WAS SICK,
BUT CLEARLY
HE'S WELL ENOUGH
FOR A NIGHT OUT.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
GO DEAL WITH HIM?
THAT IS YOUR JOB. AFTER ALL,
YOU'RE A PROFESSOR, NOT A COP.
NICE TRY, AGENT MORETTI.
THIS MURDER HAPPENED
IN MY BACKYARD.
YOU'RE NOT
KICKING ME TO THE CURB.
SHALL WE?
Annie: MY ROOM
IS RIGHT BENEATH CHRISTINA'S,
SO I CAN HEAR EVERYTHING
THAT GOES ON UPSTAIRS.
HMM. DID YOU HEAR
ANYTHING TONIGHT?
SHE WAS CRANKING HER TUNES
AT FULL VOLUME.
I HAD BEEN CRAMMING
FOR MY MCATs FOR THREE DAYS,
AND IT WAS NONSTOP.
WAS CHRISTINA HAVING PROBLEMS
WITH ANYONE?
NO WAY.
SHE HAD TONS OF FRIENDS.
I MEAN,
YOU KNOW THE TYPE --
ALL THE GIRLS
WANT TO BE HER,
ALL THE GUYS
WANT TO BE WITH HER.
WAS CHRISTINA
DATING ANYONE?
SHE JUST BROKE UP
WITH BILLY MITCHELL.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHY.
HE'S SO FREAKING HOT.
SO, WHOSE IDEA
WAS THE BREAKUP?
WELL, CHRISTINA DUMPED HIM,
AND BILLY WAS NOT HAPPY.
THEY'D BEEN ARGUING
ABOUT IT ALL WEEK.
YOU COULD HEAR THE YELLING
ALL OVER THE DORM.
WERE THEY FIGHTING
TONIGHT?
ALL I COULD HEAR
WAS THE MUSIC.
BUT I-I DID PASS BILLY
IN THE HALL.
DOES BILLY LIVE
IN THE DORM?
NO, IN FARNSWORTH,
BUT I JUST SAW HIM
AT THE VIGIL
ON THE QUAD.
THAT'S BILLY.
BILLY MITCHELL?
FBI.
[ GRUNTS ]
BILLY MITCHELL,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
YOU'RE CRAZY IF YOU BELIEVED
I'D HURT CHRISTINA.
SHE'S BEEN MY GIRLFRIEND SINCE
FRESHMAN YEAR IN HIGH SCHOOL.
YEAH, WELL,
FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD,
THERE WAS TROUBLE
IN PARADISE.
WHAT WERE YOU KIDS
FIGHTING ABOUT?
I TOLD HER I WAS
GONNA TRANSFER TO M.I.T.
BECAUSE THEY HAVE
A BETTER CHEMISTRY PROGRAM.
SHE FREAKED OUT.
SHE BEGGED ME
NOT TO LEAVE CHICAGO.
SO TWO WEEKS AFTER I PROMISED
I'D STAY, SHE DUMPS ME.
WHY?
'CAUSE THAT PIECE OF EUROTRASH
MESSED WITH HER HEAD.
WHICH PIECE OF EUROTRASH
ARE WE TALKING ABOUT HERE?
THIS GUY KARL.
SOME PRUSSIAN PRINCE
OR SOMETHING.
THINKS, LIKE, A TITLE MAKES HIM
BETTER THAN THE REST OF US.
THIS GUY IS A JERK.
GOES THROUGH WOMEN
LIKE KLEENEX IN FLU SEASON.
GUY STOLE YOUR GIRL.
THAT'S GOT TO BE ROUGH.
NO, NO.
THIS GUY'S BAD NEWS.
I GOOGLED HIM,
FOUND OUT ALL SORTS OF DIRT.
THAT'S WHY
I WENT TO SEE CHRISTINA,
TO TELL HER NOT TO GET MIXED UP
WITH THE GUY.
AND THEN WHEN SHE DIDN'T LISTEN,
YOU GOT ANGRY.
YES, BUT...
BUT I DIDN'T KILL HER.
SHE WAS ALIVE
WHEN I LEFT.
ANYBODY SEE YOU GO?
YEAH. KARL.
TOLD ME
TO LEAVE CHRISTINA ALONE.
I HEARD HIM YELLING AT HER
WHEN I LEFT.
YOU KNOW,
MAYBE THAT CREEP KILLED HER.
YEAH,
MY MONEY'S STILL ON YOU.
I DIDN'T DO THIS.
THEN WHY'D YOU RUN?
BEC...
BECAUSE I HAD A JOINT
IN MY POCKET.
I WAS AFRAID
YOU WERE GONNA BUST ME,
SO I FLUSHED IT.
YOU SHOULD BE TALKING
TO KARL.
Kate: "PRINCE KARL
OF HESSE-BRANDENBERG.
THIRD SON OF A MINOR
GERMAN NOBLE FAMILY."
SO NO POWER LEFT,
JUST TITLES AND CASTLES.
ACCORDING TO "LIFESTYLES
OF THE RICH AND INFAMOUS,"
KARL IS
QUITE THE PROBLEM CHILD.
LOOKS LIKE
HE'S BEEN EXPELLED
FROM TWO BOARDING SCHOOLS
IN ENGLAND...
ACCUSED OF SLAPPING
A MODEL
IN A DISCOTHèQUE
IN MONTE CARLO...
ACCUSED OF THE RAPE
OF A HOTEL MAID IN IBIZA,
BUT NO CHARGES
WERE EVER FILED.
I'LL BET A VERY FAT CHECK
GOES A LONG WAY
TO CONVINCING A VICTIM
NOT TO PROSECUTE.
THE AGENT I SENT TO KARL'S CONDO
CALLED IN.
DOORMAN SAYS HE LEFT LAST NIGHT
FOR THE AIRPORT.
I'LL CALL TSA, HAVE THEM CHECK
AIRLINE MANIFESTS.
YOU THINK THE PLAYBOY
OF THE WESTERN WORLD
FLIES COMMERCIAL?
HE'S GOT A PRIVATE PLANE.
WELL, HE MUST HAVE FILED
A FLIGHT PLAN.
TO ST. LOUIS.
IT NEVER GOT THERE.
REACH OUT TO HOMELAND,
STATE, INTERPOL.
MAYBE SOMEBODY KNOWS
WHERE THIS PLANE REALLY WENT.
HMM.
HEY.
SMART GUY.
WE NEED TO TALK.
YEAH, I'M...
KIND OF BUSY.
THAT'S OKAY.
I'VE GOT TO GET SOME SLEEP.
I'LL CATCH UP
WITH YOU LATER.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
ARE YOU DOING?
EXCUSE ME?
YOU DON'T
COME TO CLASS,
YOU DON'T HAND IN YOUR PAPER,
IT'S 7:00 A.M., YOU --
HAVE YOU BEEN UP PARTYING
ALL NIGHT?
SINCE WHEN IS MY SOCIAL LIFE
YOUR BUSINESS?
YOU'RE ONE OF THE BRIGHTEST
STUDENTS AT THIS UNIVERSITY,
AND I CAN'T REMEMBER
THE LAST TIME I SAW YOU
AT ONE OF MY LECTURES.
YOU'RE BLOWING YOUR CHANCES
AT MED SCHOOL.
WHO SAYS
I WANT TO GO TO MED SCHOOL?
YOU'RE CHANGING
YOUR MAJOR?
MAN...
IT'S NOT ALL ABOUT MAJORS
AND CRAMMING FOR MIDTERMS.
I'VE GOT A BAND,
A GIRLFRIEND...
AND YOU'LL HAVE PLENTY OF TIME
FOR ALL OF THAT
ONCE YOU FLUNK OUT.
LOOK, I'M WORKING
ON THE PAPER.
WORK FASTER.
I'M GIVING YOU TILL
THE END OF THE DAY TOMORROW
TO TURN IN THAT PAPER,
OR I'M FAILING YOU.
NOW GET YOUR [BLEEP]
TO CLASS.
Daniel:
MR. LEWICKI HERE TELLS ME
THAT YOU'VE BEEN FALLING ASLEEP
IN SECTION ALL WEEK.
NO, SIR.ORING YOU?
THERE'S NO NEED
TO DENY IT.
I'M SURE A STUDENT
OF YOUR PERSPICACITY
MUST BE UNCHALLENGED
BY INTRO TO NEUROPSYCH.
Y-YOUR MIDTERM PAPER
DISPLAYS A BRILLIANT GRASP
OF THE SUBJECT.
I'D LOVE TO HEAR MORE
ABOUT YOUR ALTERNATIVE VIEW
OF THE MIND-BODY LINK.
YOU REMEMBER --
PAGE 12?
YOU DIDN'T WRITE THIS,
DID YOU?
NO, SIR.
I BOUGHT IT.
WHO FROM?
RUMOR IS
HE'S A GRAD STUDENT,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
THE DUDE'S NAME.
THEN HOW'D YOU
GET THE PAPER?
A GUY ON THE TEAM
GAVE ME AN E-MAIL ADDRESS.
I SENT THE ASSIGNMENT
AND 200 BUCKS THROUGH PayPal.
AND A COUPLE DAYS LATER, THE
ESSAY SHOWED UP IN MY E-MAIL.
I-I'M SORRY.
I-I'VE NEVER CHEATED BEFORE.
OH, COME ON.
I'VE SEEN YOUR GRADES.
YOU'VE BEEN GETTING A FREE PASS
AROUND HERE.
BUT NOT THIS TIME,
NOT FROM ME.
I SWEAR,
I USED TO BE A GOOD STUDENT.
I JUST...
[ SIGHS ]
I CAN'T CONCENTRATE
ANYMORE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
FEELING LIKE THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
PRETTY MUCH ALL SEMESTER.
LOOK ME
STRAIGHT IN THE EYE.
YOU SEE THIS?
SEE THE DISPARITY
IN PUPIL SIZE?
IT'S ANISCHORIA.
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
HAVE YOU BEEN HAVING
TROUBLE BREATHING?
A LITTLE.
HEADACHES?
YEAH.
HOW DID -- HOW'D YOU KNOW?
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN PLAYING FOOTBALL?
I MEAN, I STARTED PEE-WEE AT 8,
FULL CONTACT WHEN I WAS 9.
HAVE YOU BEEN HIT
HARDER THAN USUAL LATELY?
I MEAN, I ENDED UP
AT THE BOTTOM OF A DOG PILE
A COUPLE WEEKS AGO,
AND MY HELMET FLEW OFF.
I MEAN, BACK OF MY HEAD
GOT STOMPED PRETTY HARD.
WELL, AS I SUSPECTED,
YOU HAVE A SUBDURAL HEMATOMA.
A BRAIN BLEED.
AM I GONNA MISS THE GAME
ON SATURDAY?
YEAH. AND EVERY ONE
AFTER THAT.
I'M OUT FOR THE SEASON?
YOU'RE NOT GETTING IT.
YOU CAN'T PLAY FOOTBALL
EVER AGAIN.
IF I DON'T PLAY,
I'LL LOSE MY SCHOLARSHIP.
IT'S EITHER THAT,
OR RISK PERMANENT BRAIN DAMAGE.
YOUR CHOICE.
I FOUND KARL --
IN CABO SAN LUCAS.
AND THEY SAY
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS INTER-AGENCY
COOPERATION.
I'M GLAD
STATE CAME THROUGH.
THEY DIDN'T.
THEN WHO LOCATED HIM?
HOMELAND?
INTERPOL?
TMZ.
I NEED YOU TO SIGN OFF
ON A TRAVEL VOUCHER
SO I CAN GO DOWN
AND PICK HIM UP.
WE'RE ON
AN AUSTERITY BUDGET.
LET THE MEXICAN POLICE
PICK HIM UP.
LISTEN, THE FEDERALES
AREN'T EXACTLY KNOWN
FOR THEIR...INTEGRITY.
THE MONEY
GETS INTO THE RIGHT HANDS,
KARL'S OFF TO A COUNTRY
WHERE WE CAN'T EXTRADITE HIM.
SO, WHERE TO, CHICAS?
THE BEACH...
OR THE POOL?
ADULT SWIM'S OVER,
KARL.
PARDON ME, LADIES.
HE'S COMING WITH ME.
[ CELL DOOR OPENS ]
YOU'LL NEVER GET AWAY
WITH TREATING ME LIKE THIS!
IF I GET A SLAP ON THE WRIST,
IT'S WORTH IT,
BECAUSE I KNOW
THAT YOU MURDERED CHRISTINA.
I DIDN'T KILL HER!
OH, YEAH?
TELL ME ALL ABOUT IT.
I'M NOT A MORON.
I'M NOT SAYING ANYTHING ELSE
WITHOUT MY LAWYER.
THEN I GUESS
MY JOB HERE IS DONE.
OH. LOOK AT THAT.
RIGHT IN TIME
FOR THE 4:00 FLIGHT. HMM.
OKAY. ENJOY YOUR STAY.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
I COULD TAKE YOU WITH ME.
IF YOU JUST SIGN THIS LITTLE
WAIVER OF EXTRADITION,
WE COULD BE ON OUR WAY
TO THE AIRPORT.
YOU COULD CALL YOUR LAWYER
FROM THE PLANE.
D.J.: DR. PIERCE.
I FINISHED THE ESSAY
WITH A COUPLE HOURS
TO SPARE.
I'M SURPRISED YOU PUT
SO MUCH TIME INTO IT.
HEY, IT'S DONE,
SO SAVE THE LECTURE.
STAY.
I'LL READ IT NOW.
IS THIS A JOKE?
HEY, I BUSTED MY [BLEEP]
ON THAT PAPER.
THIS ISN'T YOUR WORK.
YESTERDAY YOU TOLD ME
THAT I WAS ONE OF
THE SMARTEST STUDENTS HERE,
SO YOU KNOW
I DON'T NEED TO CHEAT.
I WROTE THIS.
25 YEARS AGO, TO BE EXACT,
WHEN I WAS AN UNDERGRAD.
DID YOU THINK I WOULDN'T
RECOGNIZE MY OWN WORDS,
OR ARE YOU JUST
TRYING TO BE CUTE?
I'M TELLING YOU
I WROTE IT.
YOU'VE JUST DESTROYED
YOUR ACADEMIC FUTURE.
FINE.
YOU THINK I WANT TO SIT
IN A DUSTY, OLD OFFICE
ALL DAY, LIKE YOU?
NO FREAKING WAY.
YOUR LIFE
IS SAD AND PATHETIC...
OLD MAN.
WHO THE [BLEEP]
DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
OH, I'M -- I'M SORRY.
DID -- DID YOU FORGET MY NAME?
IT'S D.J.,
SHORT FOR
DANIEL J. PIERCE.
I'M YOU.
BEFORE YOU CRACKED UP
AND FORGOT HOW TO HAVE A LIFE.
Max:
HEY, DOC, WE'RE LATE.
ARE YOU OKAY?
Daniel: HOW COULD I
NOT RECOGNIZE MYSELF?
I DIDN'T MAKE THE CONNECTION
UNTIL HE TOLD ME HIS NAME.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER
ANY OF YOUR STUDENTS' NAMES.
IT'S ALWAYS "GRIDIRON GUY,"
"GOTH GIRL."
WHY DO YOU DO THAT?
OH, COME ON, DANIEL.
IT'S PSYCH 101.
IT'S A DEFENSE MECHANISM.
YOU KEEP YOUR STUDENTS
AT ARM'S LENGTH
BECAUSE YOU DON'T
WANT TO REMEMBER
WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO BE THEIR AGE.
THAT'S [BLEEP]
IS IT?
WHAT WERE YOU LIKE
AT 19?
INSUFFERABLY COCKY.
I THOUGHT I WAS SMARTER
THAN MOST OF MY TEACHERS,
DIDN'T CARE MUCH
ABOUT MY EDUCATION
'CAUSE IT ALL CAME
SO EASILY.
AND WHAT DID YOU WANT TO DO
WITH YOUR LIFE?
TRAVEL THE WORLD.
CLIMB KILIMANJARO.
TOUR WITH MY BAND.
YOU WANTED TO GO
TO MED SCHOOL.
NO.
THAT WAS JUST A FALLBACK,
IN CASE I DIDN'T MAKE THE COVER
OF ROLLING STONE
BY THE TIME I WAS 25.
YET FOR ALL THAT AMBITION
AND SUCH AN ACTIVE
LIMBIC SYSTEM,
NONE OF THAT
EVER HAPPENED.
YEAH.
A LITTLE THING CALLED
PARANOID SCHIZOPHRENIA
KIND OF GOT IN THE WAY.
SO YOU GOT DIAGNOSED,
AND YOUR DREAMS DIED.
NO WONDER
YOU DIDN'T RECOGNIZE D.J.
YOU WANTED TO FORGET
EVERYTHING THAT YOU'D LOST
WHEN YOU GOT SICK.
GEE, THANK YOU FOR MAKING ME
FEEL LIKE A COMPLETE FAILURE.
YOU'RE
MISSING THE POINT.
PLEASE,
SKEWER ME WITH IT.
LOOK AT WHAT
YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED
IN SPITE
OF YOUR DIAGNOSIS.
TOP OF YOUR CLASS
IN MED SCHOOL,
YOU'VE WRITTEN SEVEN BOOKS,
WON THE DAVENPORT PRIZE.
COMPARED TO WHERE
YOU COULD HAVE ENDED UP,
YOU'VE TRULY CLIMBED
KILIMANJARO.
SO I REPRESSED
MY TRAGIC PAST
RATHER THAN CONFRONT
MY SHORTCOMINGS.
HOW VERY FREUDIAN OF ME.
TELL ME, FRAU DOKTOR,
IN YOUR HALLUCINATORY OPINION,
WHY AM I BEING HAUNTED BY
THE GHOST OF CHRISTMAS PAST NOW?
BECAUSE YOUR
UNRESOLVED ISSUES
ARE KEEPING YOU FROM
DEALING WITH YOUR STUDENTS.
I DEAL WITH MY STUDENTS
EVERY DAY.
YOU LECTURE THEM.
BUT EMOTIONALLY,
YOU'RE TOTALLY DISENGAGED.
I'M A PROFESSOR,
NOT A WET NURSE.
NOW, WHAT ABOUT
BRIAN CAHILL?
HE HAD HIS FUTURE TAKEN AWAY
BECAUSE OF A BRAIN INJURY.
YOU OF ALL PEOPLE SHOULD
BE ABLE TO RELATE TO THAT.
BUT, NO, YOU JUST MADE
THE DIAGNOSIS AND WALKED AWAY.
HEY, I SAVED
THAT KID'S LIFE.
BUT WAS THE LIFE YOU SAVED
THE ONE HE WANTED?
Brian:
YOU ASKED TO SEE ME?
I JUST...
WANTED TO APOLOGIZE.
WHAT FOR?
I WAS A LITTLE PERFUNCTORY
ABOUT YOUR DIAGNOSIS.
I-I SHOULD HAVE
DONE MORE
TO HELP YOU ACCLIMATE
TO YOUR CONDITION.
HAVE YOU SPOKEN TO YOUR PARENTS?
I-I COULD CALL THEM.
AH, NO. IT'S OKAY.
I TOLD DEAN HALEY
THAT YOUR INJURY WAS SUSTAINED
ON THE FIELD,
SO YOUR SCHOLARSHIP
WON'T BE REVOKED.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO PLAY
TO STAY IN SCHOOL.
HERE'S A REFERRAL
TO A THERAPIST
WHO SPECIALIZES
IN NEUROLOGICAL ISSUES.
TALKING HELPS.
AND DON'T WORRY
ABOUT THE PAPER YOU BOUGHT.
WE'LL, UH...
WE'LL LET THAT SLIDE.
THANKS, DR. PIERCE.
I REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
Max: HEY, DOC.
OH. HEY, BRHEY.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT,
BUT, UM, KATE CALLED.
SHE'S BACK FROM MEXICO.
KARL DID NOT KILL
CHRISTINA.
WITNESSES PLACE HIM IN HER DORM
ROOM RIGHT BEFORE HER DEATH.
SHE WAS ALIVE
WHEN I TOOK OFF.
YEAH,
BUT YOU WERE ARGUING.
I WANTED HER TO COME WITH ME
TO A PARTY IN MEXICO,
BUT SHE THOUGHT A MIDTERM
IN SOCIOLOGY WAS MORE IMPORTANT.
SO I LEFT.
YEAH, AND YOU TOOK
SOME OF HER DNA WITH YOU.
WE SEARCHED
YOUR APARTMENT,
AND WE FOUND SMEARS
OF CHRISTINA'S BLOOD
ALL OVER YOUR FLOOR.
YOU MUST HAVE TRACKED IT IN
ON YOUR SHOES.
GIVE US A MOMENT,
WOULD YOU?
ATTAGIRL.
THANK YOU.
LAST WEEK, CHRISTINA
WAS OVER AT MY PLACE,
AND SHE HAD A NOSEBLEED.
WHY? OFFS ]
BECAUSE
YOU BACKHANDED HER?
I DON'T LIKE YOUR ATTITUDE,
AGENT MORETTI.
MY CLIENT
HAS NOTHING MORE TO SAY.
THAT'S FINE.
I'VE GOT ENOUGH TO HOLD HIM.
YEAH, JUST ONE
SMALL PROBLEM, THOUGH.
[ CHUCKLES ]
KARL HAS AN ALIBI.
I JUST GOT A TEXT
FROM MY INVESTIGATOR.
HE'S BRINGING
A WITNESS DOWN NOW
WHO CAN PROVE KARL
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
I WAS HEADING BACK
FROM THE LIBRARY,
AND I RAN INTO KARL
OUTSIDE THE DORM.
SO YOU TWO
KNOW EACH OTHER.
[ CHUCKLES ] WELL,
HE'S KIND OF HARD TO MISS.
HE --
HE DRIVES A FERRARI.
OKAY.
DID YOU TALK TO HIM?
HE LOOKED UPSET,
SO I ASKED HIM IF HE WAS OKAY,
AND HE SAID HE JUST HAD THIS
BIG FIGHT WITH HIS GIRLFRIEND.
DID HE SAY
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO. HE JUST GOT IN HIS CAR
AND DROVE OFF.
SO NOW YOU KNOW
HE DIDN'T DO IT, RIGHT?
NO.
I'M SORRY, SHANNON.
YOUR STORY DOES NOT PROVE
THAT KARL'S INNOCENT.
I MEAN, FOR ALL WE KNOW,
HE COULD HAVE LOOKED UPSET
BECAUSE HE HAD
JUST MURDERED CHRISTINA.
NO WAY.
SHE WAS STILL ALIVE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
I SAW HER YELLING OUT THE WINDOW
AT HIM AS HE DROVE OFF.
I SAW HER, SO KARL
COULDN'T HAVE KILLED HER.
I JUST DON'T BUY IT.
SHANNON POPS UP
OUT OF NOWHERE
WITH AN ALIBI THAT KARL
FORGOT TO MENTION IN MEXICO?
SO,
WHAT'S YOUR THEORY?
THE FIRST TIME
THE LAWYER MENTIONED A WITNESS
WAS RIGHT AFTER
HE GOT A TEXT,
SO I THINK HE
HAD HIS INVESTIGATOR GO OUT
AND FIND SOMEBODY WHO WAS
WILLING TO LIE FOR MONEY.
I MEAN, IT'S THE
HESSE-BRANDENBURG M.O.
SPREAD A LITTLE CASH AROUND,
MAKE THE CHARGES GO AWAY.
BREAK THE ALIBI, AGENT MORETTI,
OR YOUR BOY'S GONNA WALK.
[ SIGHS ]
OKAY.
IF YOU'VE GOT ONE OF YOUR
BRILLIANT DANIEL PIERCE IDEAS,
I'M ALL EARS.
SEARCH HER ROOM.
MY GUESS -- YOU'RE GONNA FIND
AN ENVELOPE FULL OF CASH.
BUT I-I DON'T HAVE GROUNDS
FOR A WARRANT.
I MEAN, WITHOUT ONE, I CAN'T
SO MUCH AS OPEN HER DOOR.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
DR. PIERCE!
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
OH, SORRY.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
SHANNON DUQUESNE'S ROOM.
I'M HER ROOMMATE.
AH. WELL, UM...
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
I LENT SHANNON A BOOK.
I DIDN'T KNOW
SHE WAS IN YOUR CLASS.
SHE ISN'T,
BUT, UH, SHE EXPRESSED INTEREST
IN TAKING IT NEXT TERM,
AND I SUGGESTED
SHE DO SOME READING FIRST,
BUT I-I NEED THE BOOK
FOR A LECTURE.
OH, WELL, THAT'S SHANNON'S DESK
OVER THERE.
I'D OFFER TO HELP,
BUT I'M LATE FOR STUDY GROUP.
I THINK I CAN MANAGE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WON'T BE A MINUTE.
THIS IS NUTS.
YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
Kate:
YOU'RE OBSESSED WITH KARL.
[ CHUCKLES ] I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
"MY PRINCE CHARMING"?
YOUR SCRAPBOOK?
THAT -- THAT IS PRIVATE.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT --
YOU LOST
THE RIGHT TO PRIVACY
WHEN YOU DECIDED TO LIE
TO THE FBI.
NOW TELL US THE TRUTH
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
THE NIGHT OF THE MURDER.
[ SIGHS ]
SHANNON,
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I-I HAD NO BUSINESS
LOOKING AT YOUR PRIVATE THINGS.
BUT IT DID MAKE ME REALIZE
HOW DEEPLY YOU CARE ABOUT KARL.
YOU'VE OBVIOUSLY FELT THAT WAY
FOR A LONG TIME.
DO YOU REMEMBER
H-HOW IT STARTED?
WELL, WHEN I WAS 12,
I SAW A PICTURE
OF HIM PLAYING POLO
IN PEOPLE MAGAZINE.
HE WAS ALL IN WHITE,
ON THIS GORGEOUS HORSE,
AND I JUST --
I KNEW HE WAS MY DESTINY.
SO YOU CAME HERE TO GO
TO SCHOOL, TO BE NEAR HIM.
WELL, I WAS NEVER GONNA MEET
KARL BACK HOME IN PITTSBURGH,
SO I SIGNED UP
FOR THE SAME CLASSES,
AND I GAVE HIM MY NOTES
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
HE DIDN'T REALLY
NOTICE ME.
UM, SO I...
I WENT TO THIS PARTY,
AND HE WAS THERE,
AND FINALLY...
IT HAPPENED.
YOU MEAN
YOU SLEPT WITH HIM.
IT WAS THE BEST NIGHT
OF MY LIFE.
BUT THEN...
THEN HE STARTED DATING
CHRISTINA LAKE.
I TRIED TO TELL HIM
HOW MUCH I LOVE HIM,
BUT HE SAID HE ONLY SLEPT
WITH ME BECAUSE HE WAS DRUNK.
I BEGGED HIM
TO GIVE ME A CHANCE.
I TOLD HIM THAT
I WOULD DO ANYTHING FOR HIM.
AND THEN
WHEN KARL GOT ARRESTED,
HE REMEMBERED WHAT YOU'D SAID
AND TOLD HIS LAWYER.
THE INVESTIGATOR SAID
THAT KARL WAS IN TROUBLE,
THAT IT WOULD REALLY
HELP HIM
IF I REMEMBERED
SEEING HIM DRIVE AWAY.
DO YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH TROUBLE YOU'RE IN
FOR LYING TO THE FBI?
IT'S WORTH IT.
NOW KARL WILL REALIZE
HOW MUCH I LOVE HIM.
Kate: KARL'S BACK ON THE HOOK
FOR THE MURDER.
HE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE.
YOU THINK SHANNON
COULD HAVE DONE IT?
THINK HARDER.
SHE IDOLIZES KARL.
AND HE ONLY HAS EYES
FOR CHRISTINA.
SO YOU THINK SHANNON
COULD HAVE KILLED CHRISTINA
TO GET HER
OUT OF THE WAY.
MM-HMM.
FROM NO SUSPECTS
TO A TWOFER.
YOU JUSTGOOD. MY DAY.
AND BECAUSE THEY CONSPIRED
TO LIE ABOUT KARL'S ALIBI,
I'VE GOT ENOUGH
TO HOLD BOTH OF THEM
WHILE I FIGURE OUT
WHO THE KILLER IS.
MORETTI.
WAIT. WAIT.
HEY. HOLD ON.
It's Max.
YEAH.
LEWICKI?
WHAT?
OKAY.
BAD NEWS?
ONE OF MY STUDENTS GOT INJURED
PLAYING FOOTBALL.
TRY MOVING YOUR TOES.
YOU'RE LUCKY.
AFTER THE CRANIOTOMY,
THE PARALYSIS DISAPPEARED.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
WERE YOU THINKING?
I TOLD YOU
I FIXED YOUR SCHOLARSHIP.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO PLAY.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHY WOULD YOU
TAKE A-A RISK LIKE THIS?
SINCE I WAS A LITTLE KID,
FOOTBALL'S BEEN MY LIFE.
IF I WASN'T PLAYING,
I WAS TRAINING.
I NEVER WANTED TO DO
ANYTHING ELSE.
SO WHAT
THE [BLEEP] AM I
IF I'M NOT
A FOOTBALL PLAYER?
Kate:
YOU TOLD SHANNON TO LIE.
Karl: I HAVEN'T
TOLD ANYBODY ANYTHING.
YEAH, BUT YOU TALKED
TO YOUR ATTORNEY.
AND EVERYTHING WE DISCUSSED
IS PRIVILEGED.
NOT IF IT CONSTITUTES
A CRIME.
AND MANIPULATING AN OBVIOUSLY
DISTURBED YOUNG WOMAN
INTO LYING TO FEDERAL AGENTS
CERTAINLY QUALIFIES --
IT'S OBSTRUCTION OF JUSTICE
AND WITNESS TAMPERING.
WE'VE ANSWERED
ALL OF YOUR QUESTIONS,
SOME OF THEM TWICE.
SO EITHER CHARGE MY CLIENT,
OR LET HIM GO.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
YOU'RE FREE TO LEAVE.
NICE KNOWING YOU.
NOT MY CALL.
U.S. ATTORNEY'S OFFICE
DECLINED TO FILE CHARGES.
I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
I DON'T LIKE IT
ANY MORE THAN YOU DO.
BUT STATE'S GETTING PRESSURE
FROM THE GERMAN AMBASSADOR.
THEY'RE AFRAID IT MIGHT LEAD
TO A DIPLOMATIC INCIDENT.
Daniel:
WHAT HAPPENS TO SHANNON?
I HAD TO LET HER GO,
TOO.
SHE LIED TO A FEDERAL AGENT.
THAT'S A CRIME.
YEAH,
BUT THE A.U.S.A.
DOESN'T WANT TO PROSECUTE
A LOVESICK GIRL
FOR PROTECTING A BOY WHO MAY
VERY WELL BE INNOCENT HIMSELF.
KARL'S NOT INNOCENT.
HE'S JUST RICH ENOUGH
TO AFFORD IMMUNITY.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
Michael: BONO ASKED ME
THE SAME QUESTION
AT THE U.N. SUMMIT ON AFRICA
LAST MONTH,
AND I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I TOLD HIM --
THAT WITHOUT A PARADIGM SHIFT,
WE WILL NEVER END THE FAMINES,
NO MATTER HOW MANY T-SHIRTS
WE SELL.
WHY ARE YOU HIDING
FROM PROFESSOR WONDERFUL?
HE'S SUCH A NICE GUY.
AND HE'S FUNNY...
AND HE'S...SMART,
AND HE COOKS.
I MEAN, HE'S PERFECT,
BUT I JUST --
I KEEP PUSHING HIM AWAY,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY.
D.J.: I DO.
BECAUSE SHE'S INTO YOU.
I-I MEAN, I JUST DON'T
KNOW, REALLY, HOW TO
HANDLE IT, YOU KNOW?
LISTEN --
TELL HER TO DUMP HIM.
I CARETHEN YOU CAN
BUT MAKE YOUR MOVE.
I JUST CAN'T
SEEM TO MAKE UP MY MIND...
HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA LET THIS GO ON FOR?
...IS WSHE CLEARLY WANTS YOU.
SHE DOESN'T WANT HATHAWAY.
STOP!
SNO.Y.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO MAKE YOU
UNCOMFORTABLE.G TO --
YOU DIDN'T.
I-I-I JUST MEANT YOU SHOULD --
YOU SHOULD
STOP TALKING TO ME,
AND -- AND YOU SHOULD
TELL HATHAWAY HOW YOU...
HOW YOU FEEL.
I-I GOT TO GO.
DOC, THERE YOU ARE.
I WAS LOOKING FOR YOU.
WHY? WHAT ARE YOU
SO CHIPPER ABOUT?
WELL,
I GOT TO WONDERING
ABOUT THE WHOLE
PAPER-SELLING BUSINESS.
CAHILL SAID
IT WAS A GRAD STUDENT,
SO I TOOK
A LITTLE INITIATIVE.
OH, YOU'RE PLAYING
JUNIOR DETECTIVE NOW?
I E-MAILED THE PAPER WRITER,
AND I TOLD HIM I NEEDED A PAPER
ANALYZING VIZNEVSKY'S
NEUROLOGICAL ANATOMY
OF PSYCHOPATHOLOGY.
THAT'S A TERRIBLE IDEA.
NOBODY WOULD EVER
DO A PAPER ON VIZNEVSKY.
HIS THINKING
IS TOTALLY OUTDATED.
I'M SURPRISED
THE BOOK'S EVEN IN PRINT.
IT'S NOT.
IT'S NOT EVEN ONLINE.
THAT'S THE GENIUS OF IT.
YOU KNEW HE'D HAVE TO GO
TO THE LIBRARY TO GET IT.
LEWICKI, YOU SLY DOG.
HE WALKED
RIGHT INTO MY LITTLE TRAP.
THE DUDE'S A PhD STUDENT
IN ENGLISH LIT.
HIS NAME'S ANDRE LUSTIG.
I'VE BEEN WORKING
ON MY PhD FOR SIX YEARS.
I'M $70,000 IN DEBT.
I HAVE NO IDEA
HOW I'M GONNA PAY THAT BACK.
MY SPECIALIZATION
IS IN LATE MEDIEVAL POETRY.
GIVE ME A LIST OF EVERY STUDENT
YOU WROTE A PAPER FOR,
AND I'LL ALLOW YOU
TO WITHDRAW FROM CLMU.
BUT NO OTHER SCHOOL
WILL TAKE ME.
I'LL NEVER FINISH
MY DOCTORATE.
YOUR M.A. MIGHT ALLOW YOU
TO GET A JOB AT A PREP SCHOOL.
NOW, I WANT A LIST
OF THOSE CUSTOMERS.
I DON'T REMEMBER
THEIR NAMES.
I'VE HAD LIKE 100 CLIENTS
THIS SEMESTER.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
I CHURN OUT
A COUPLE PAPERS A DAY.
D.J.: [BLEEP]
I WAS A GREAT STUDENT
BEFORE I TURNED INTO YOU,
AND EVEN I COULDN'T WRITE
TWO PAPERS A DAY.
THE PAPER YOU WROTE
FOR BRIAN CAHILL WAS GOOD.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
YOU WROTE THAT IN A DAY.
I DON'T SLEEP VERY MUCH.
WHAT DO YOU TAKE, ANDRE?
COCAINE? SPEED?
JUST A STUDY AID.
HELPS KEEPS ME AWAKE
AND MY BRAIN RAZOR-SHARP.
WHAT KIND
OF "STUDY AID"?
IT'S JUST SOME PILL
SOME BRAINIAC KID
IN THE CHEM DEPARTMENT MAKES.
OUR CHEM DEPARTMENT MIGHT NOT BE
AS GOOD AS M.I.T.'s,
BUT IT TURNS OUT
SOME HIGH-END PRODUCT.
ALL RIGHT.
WHO'S THE DEALER, ANDRE?
I DON'T KNOW HIS NAME.
I DO.
WHAT'S COOKING, BILLY?
WOULDN'T BE A BATCH
OF METHAMPHETAMINE, WOULD IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
YOU CLAIMED THAT YOU RAN FROM ME
TO FLUSH SOME MARIJUANA.
AND THEN I REMEMBERED,
YOU'RE A CHEMISTRY MAJOR.
YEAH? SO? WHAT'S THAT
GOT TO DO WITH ANYTHING?
WE ALL KNOW
ABOUT YOUR LITTLE SIDELINE.
YOUR MAGIC PILLS
ARE WHAT WENT DOWN THE DRAIN
IN THAT BATHROOM,
AM I RIGHT?
IT'S JUST A STUDY AID.
THE PILLS AREN'T EVEN ILLEGAL.
THEN WHY'D YOU RUN?
TRUST ME, BILLY. YOU DON'T
WANT TO SCREW WITH ME TWICE.
BECAUSE I STOLE
THE PILLS.
FROM WHO?
PROFESSOR EMMETT.
THEY'RE FROM AN EXPERIMENT
SHE'S BEEN WORKING ON.
Alison: THE DRUG
WAS A MAJOR BREAKTHROUGH.
THE RATS COULD RUN THE MAZE
FOR 36 HOURS STRAIGHT,
AND THEIR PROBLEM-SOLVING
ABILITIES SKYROCKETED.
ARE YOU IN FDA TRIALS?
IT WASN'T
FOR THE OPEN MARKET.
MY FUNDING CAME FROM
THE DEFENSE DEPARTMENT.
THEY WANTED A PILL
THAT WOULD KEEP A SOLDIER
AWAKE AND ALERT IN COMBAT
WITHOUT A NEGATIVE IMPACT
ON COGNITIVE ABILITY.
OUR GOVERNMENT
TRYING TO CREATE
CHEMICALLY ENHANCED
SUPER-SOLDIERS.
WHY AM I NOT SURPRISED?
OH, IT'S HISTORICAL FACT.
HITLER REVOLUTIONIZED
THE PRODUCTION OF CRYSTAL METH.
JAPANESE KAMIKAZE PILOTS
POPPED DEXEDRINE
SO THEY COULD FLY
IT'S TRUE.Y TO PEARL HARBOR.
STIMULANTS HAVE ALWAYS BEEN
A PART OF COMBAT,
BUT THE PROBLEM IS
THAT SLEEP DEPRIVATION
DIMINISHES A SOLDIER'S ABILITY
TO MAKE GOOD DECISIONS.
BUT YOUR RATS DIDN'T
DUMB DOWN. THE PENTAGON
MUST BE THRILLED.
AT FIRST,
THEY WERE OVER THE MOON.
BUT WE HAD TO TERMINATE
THE STUDY
WHEN WE DISCOVERED THE PILL
HAD SOME SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS.
WHICH WERE...
AFTER TWO DAYS,
ABOUT 20% OF THE RATS
STARTED TO ATTACK EACH OTHER
AND SELF-MUTILATE.
THAT'S ONE [BLEEP]
OF A SIDE EFFECT.
AND WHY WE ENDED
THE STUDY.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE PILLS?
THEY WERE DESTROYED
BY MY LAB ASSISTANT.
BILLY MITCHELL.
WE'RE LUCKY THE CAMPUS
ISN'T A BLOODBATH.
YEAH, BUT WHY ISN'T IT?
YOU SAID ONLY SOME OF THE RATS
BECAME VIOLENT?
WE ISOLATED
THE TRIGGER --
THE PILL MADE THE RATS
HYPERSENSITIVE TO LOUD NOISES.
AUDITORY STIMULATION
MADE THEM SNAP.
THE PILL WOULD NEVER HAVE WORKED
ON THE BATTLEFIELD.
KARL DIDN'T KILL CHRISTINA.
BUT I KNOW WHO DID.
HI.
CAN IYEAH. YOU?
WE JUST HAVE A FEW MORE
QUESTIONS TO ASK YOU, ANNIE.
UH, SURE.
I MEAN,
I'M KIND OF BUSY.
I HAVE MY BIOLOGY MIDTERM
TOMORROW,
AND I STILL HAVE
SIX CHAPTERS TO COVER.
THAT'S A LOT TO CRAM
IN ONE NIGHT.
WELL,
I HAVE TO GET IT DONE.
MED SCHOOLS
CHECK MIDTERM GRADES,
SO I HAVE TO,
YOU KNOW --
[ BOOK THUDS ]
SORRY.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
YOU'RE A LITTLE JUMPY.
GUESS I'M JUST
OVER-CAFFEINATED.
YOU'RE TAKING BILLY MITCHELL'S
STUDY AID, AREN'T YOU?
HE SAID THE PILLS
WERE LEGAL.
I DIDN'T
DO ANYTHING WRONG.
BUT BILLY DID, AND WE NEED
YOUR HELP TO NAIL HIM.
I NEEDED AN EDGE FOR THE MCATs,
AND BILLY SAID THAT THE PILLS
WOULD HELP ME STUDY
HARDER AND BETTER THAN EVER.
HE WAS RIGHT.
I STUDIED FOR DAYS AND
REMEMBERED EVERYTHING I READ.
WOW.
BUT DID YOU FIND THAT
LOUD NOISES BECAME UNPLEASANT,
LIKE -- LIKE
CHRISTINA'S MUSIC?
MM-HMM.
IT WAS DRIVING ME CRAZY.
I HAD -- I'D BEEN CRAMMING
FOR THREE DAYS.
AND THEN SHE STARTED BLASTING
HER TUNES. PRETTY INCONSIDERATE.
THANK YOU.
DID YOU ASK HER
TO TURN IT DOWN?
I WENT UP TO HER ROOM
TO TALK TO HER...
[ LOUD MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MOANING ]
YEAH?
COULD YOU PLEASE
TURN THE MUSIC DOWN?
I'M TRYING WHATEVER.
UGH.
YOU MUST HAVE BEEN UPSET.
OKAY. ALL SHE CARED ABOUT
WAS PARTYING.
IT DIDN'T BOTHER HER THAT
SHE WAS MESSING WITH MY LIFE.
AND SHE DIDN'T
TURN IT DOWN, DID SHE?
[ CHUCKLES ]
SHE TURNED IT UP.
[ LOUD MUSIC CONTINUES ]
NOT AGAIN.
STOP BEING
SUCH AN UPTIGHT [BLEEP]
...AND JOIN THE PARTY.
OH, THAT WOULD HAVE
[BLEEP] ME OFF.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WENT BACK TO MY ROOM
AND I PUT IN EARPLUGS.
AND THEY DIDN'T WORK,
I'M GUESSING.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
I FEEL FOR YOU, ANNIE.
I-I DO.
THERE YOU ARE, WORKING ON
THE BIGGEST TEST OF YOUR LIFE,
THE ONE THAT'S GONNA DETERMINE
YOUR FUTURE.
AND THERE'S CHRISTINA,
JUST SCREWING ANY CHANCE
YOU HAVE OF SUCCESS.
SOUNDS TO ME
LIKE SHE WAS THE [BLEEP]
YOU WERE WORKING
SO HARD,
THE MUSIC'S BLARING,
IT'S DRIVING YOU NUTS.
YOU CAN'T
LET HER WRECK YOUR LIFE.
I MEAN, YOU DID
WHAT YOU HAD TO DO.
OF COURSE.
OF COURSE YOU DID.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
I TOLD YOU
TO STOP BUGGING ME [BLEEP]
I WENT BACK UP.
KARL WAS GONE,
AND CHRISTINA WAS EVEN NASTIER.
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
I HOPE YOU GET AIDS
BANGING HOOKERS IN CABO!
AAH!
I TOOK THE WINDOW,
AND I SLAMMED IT ON HER NECK.
SHE KNEW I HAD THE MCATs,
AND SHE DIDN'T EVEN CARE.
WHAT DID YOU DO THEN?
I TURNED OFF THE MUSIC...
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
...WENT BACK TO MY ROOM,
AND STUDIED.
WITHOUT ALL THAT FREAKING NOISE,
I COULD GET A LOT DONE.
NOW I KNEW THAT I COULD TOTALLY
ACE THE MCATs.
AND I DID.
HER LAWYER IS ARGUING
THAT TAKING THE DRUGS CAUSED
"DIMINISHED CAPACITY."
DIMINISHED CAPACITY?
SHE NAILED THE MCATs,
PRACTICALLY GOT A PERFECT SCORE.
OKAY, SO THE DRUGS
HELPED HER NAIL A TEST,
BUT IS IT ALSO WHAT MADE HER
A STONE-COLD KILLER?
MAYBE. OR MAYBE
SHE'S JUST WIRED THAT WAY.
Michael: KATE!
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE
GONNA BE ABLE TO DUCK HIM.
IT'S OKAY.
I'M GONNA TAKE YOUR ADVICE.
I'M JUST GONNA --
GONNA TALK TO HIM.
GOOD LUCK.
HI.
I HEAR
YOU SOLVED THE CASE.
I WANT TO HEAR ALL ABOUT IT
OVER DINNER TONIGHT.
I FOUND THIS
AMAZING NEW SUSHI BAR.
THEY FLY IN THEIR UNI
STRAIGHT FROM THE TSUKIJI MARKET
IN TOKYO EVERY DAY --
IT'S AMAZING.
MICHAEL, UM...I DON'T THINK
IT'S GONNA WORK.
NOT THE SUSHI.
I MEAN THE WHOLE...US.
KATE...
MAYBE IT'S BECAUSE I'M
TECHNICALLY STILL MARRIED,
OR MAYBE BECAUSE
I'M KIND OF MARRIED TO MY JOB.
I DOKATE.NOW.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME.
IT'S JUST,
YOU'RE SO NICE,
YOU'RE SO SMART,
AND YOU'RE HANDSOME AND FUNNY.
I GET IT.
YOU DO?
OF COURSE.
BUT YOU KNOW
WHAT I THINK?
IT'S NOT THE JOB...
OR THE DIVORCE.
IT'S, UH...
IT'S JUST THAT
I'M NOT THE GUY FOR YOU.
TAKE CARE, KATE.
WHAT'S THIS?
UNIVERSITY CATALOG.
ASTRONOMY, MUSIC THEORY,
MODERN ART...
THE WORLD'S YOUR OYSTER.
I'M NOT SURE
I'M GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
LISTEN --
LISTEN TO ME, BRIAN.
WHEN I -- WHEN I WAS YOUR AGE,
SOMETHING HAPPENED TO ME...TOO.
I WAS --
I WAS LOCKED IN A HOSPITAL,
AND I THOUGHT MY LIFE WAS OVER.
ALL MY DREAMS
WENT OUT THE WINDOW.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
I FOUND A NEW DREAM.
CAME TO SAY GOODBYE.
MY HALLUCINATIONS DON'T USUALLY
HAVE SUCH GOOD MANNERS.
I'M GOING AWAY.
TIME TO TRAVEL, SEE THE WORLD.
FIRST STOP IS AFRICA,
TO CLIMB KILIMANJARO.
I'M SORRY YOU DIDN'T
GET TO GO.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
SOMETIMES PLAN "B"
TURNS OUT
PRETTY GOOD, TOO.
OUR AMBITIONS AND OUR DREAMS
GIVE US A GLIMPSE
OF A BEAUTIFUL SOMEDAY.
AND THEY CAN HELP US GET THROUGH
A SOMETIMES
LESS-THAN-BEAUTIFUL TODAY.
IT'S A TRICKY THING,
THOUGH, AMBITION.
IT CAN BLIND US
TO THE PRICE OF SUCCESS.
IT CAN CONSUME US,
LEADING TO DANGEROUS
OBSESSIONS...
OR EMPTY HEDONISM.
BUT NO MATTER
HOW MUCH WE'RE FUELED
BY THIS NATURAL
NEUROLOGICAL IMPULSE,
AMBITION ISN'T CARVED IN STONE.
DREAMS CHANGE.
AND EVEN IF WE DON'T
GET TO CLIMB MOUNTAINS...
THERE'S STILL A CHANCE
THAT WE CAN MOVE THEM.
IN THE WORDS OF THOSE
OLD ENGLISH POETS,
YOU CAN'T ALWAYS GET
WHAT YOU WANT.
BUT IF YOU TRY SOMETIME...
YOU MIGHT FIND
YOU GET WHAT YOU NEED.