What is reality?
Hippie guy.
The observable universe?
I suppose that answer might fly
in the physics department,
but this is neuroscience.
Who's got the brains to give me
an answer relating to the brain?
Ironic t-shirt.
Reality is exactly
what we see and hear,
instead of what we fantasize
about or dream
or, you know,
maybe hallucinate.
Ah. Hallucination.
That's an answer I would have
expected from hippie guy.
Sex, drugs,
and rock 'n' roll, right?
Okay. Now, here's something
that's really
gonna alter your consciousness.
Reality...
Is a figment
of your imagination.
Who here hasn't woken up
breathless from a nightmare
and thought, "oh,
thank God it's just a dream"?
That's because
the neurochemical impulses
fired when we're dreaming
or fantasizing
or hallucinating
are indistinguishable
from the ones banging around
inside our skulls
when we actually experience
those events.
So...
If what we perceive
is often wrong...
How can we ever know what's real
and what isn't?
All right.
Faculty meeting's at noon.
Rosenthal's at 2:00,
so I picked you up one of
the veggie wraps that you like.
You can scarf it down
in between.
You know how you get
when you don't eat.
Lewicki.
Yeah?
Room and board in exchange
for some light housekeeping
does not make you my mother.
Just trying to look out
for you, doc.
Do you have my puzzles?
Yeah. Times, chronicle, trib,
daily mail...
Professor Pierce?
I was wondering
if I could buy you a latte.
Uh, I don't drink coffee.
Oh, it doesn't
have to be coffee.
I just wanted to pick your brain
about my term-paper topic.
Oh.
Here's the thing, miss...
Karyn.
Karyn. Uh...
"Discussing your term paper"
is obviously code for sex.
And... and while we might both
enjoy that very much,
it could also get me fired,
so I'm afraid
I have to regretfully
and respectfully
decline your offer.
Daniel.
Kate Moretti.
You'd be a lot easier to find
if you carried a cellphone.
If I carried a cellphone,
the government could track me.
I am the government.
My point exactly.
I thought you were at Quantico.
Got my old desk back.
Isn't that a demotion?
Got a few minutes?
His name's Clark Weilman.
He's... well, he was
general counsel
of techsan pharmaceuticals.
Skull was fractured
in six places,
and his wife confessed
to detectives
from Chicago homicide.
Police have a confession.
Why am I looking
at these pretty pictures?
Wife makes Nicole Richie
look fat.
I don't know who that is.
I- I think the wife has anorexia
or bulimia. I don't know.
Either way,
she could not lift this trophy,
let alone bash her husband
over the head with it six times.
You think the confession
was coerced?
She has a vacant affect.
If she does have
an eating disorder,
it could be a symptom of a much
more serious mental illness.
You were always
one of my best students.
W- why is the FBI involved
in this anyway?
A couple of months ago,
techsan informed the bureau
that some of its top executives
were receiving death threats,
calling the pharmaceutical
industry
part of a vast
public/private conspiracy
to poison the American people.
Can't argue with that.
S.A.I.C. Says you gave up
the consulting gig.
Any particular reason?
Oh, uh...
After you left,
the fun went out of it.
Well, I'm back.
Why did you kill your husband,
Mrs. Weilman?
I, uh...
don't know.
You told the police you wanted
the insurance money.
Yes. That's... that's right,
And just what is
the point of this?
When did you and your husband
buy this policy?
I don't remember.
Was it last Thursday?
You met your husband for lunch,
and then you both went to
the insurance-company offices
and signed the papers?
Yeah. That's right.
It was... Yeah.
Two days ago,
when you went for a walk,
did you find a stray kitten?
You took her home?
You called her Millie?
How did you know about Millie?
She's innocent.
What are you talking about?
She signed a confession.
Korsa-what?
It's a neurological disorder
characterized
by anterograde amnesia,
extreme susceptibility to
suggestion, and confabulation.
I tell her she has a cat
named Millie,
she remembers
having a cat named Millie.
You tell her she bashed
her husband over the head
with a golf trophy,
and she remembers that.
Only there is no cat.
I made that up.
Just like you made up a story
about a murder plot
to collect life insurance,
which is a bit of a cliché,
isn't it, detective?
What the hell?
Hey, hold on a second!
Hey! Hey!
Listen,
we did a background check.
We found out about that policy,
and we asked her.
You're acting like I beat it out
of her with a rubber hose.
Either way,
it's a false confession.
She doesn't belong in jail.
She belongs in a hospital.
This is bullshit.
Can we go now?
Just give me a minute.
Okay?
I'm gonna recommend that
Ms. Weilman be transferred
to a psychiatric unit
for further evaluation.
Are you kidding me?!
She confessed to murder.
Look, if Dr. Pierce...
My lieutenant warned me
about you,
said you'd come in here,
flashing your FBI badge,
jacking our cases.
Screwing with one of mine now
because some nutjob
makes a drive-by diagnosis?
He's not a nutjob,
detective Hammond.
He literally wrote the book
on forensic neuropsychiatry...
four of them, actually.
Not a nutjob, huh?
Okay. So he's
a little eccentric.
to get the FBI's interest?
You'll have to forgive Alan,
Agent Moretti.
He and Clark were very close.
I just need access
to all litigation
filed against techsan
over the past five years.
Do you have any idea
how many frivolous claims
a company like ours
has to deal with?
Mm. I can imagine.
But we may be able to connect
the death threats
techsan received to someone
who brought a lawsuit
against the company.
And I would also like access
to Mr. Weilman's e-mail account
and a list of his current
and former colleagues...
really, anyone he came
into contact with.
Alan will get you everything
you need.
Thanks, Alan.
These are the anonymous e-mails
sent to Clark Weilman
and the other
techsan executives.
These death threats were routed
through servers
all over the world.
Whoever sent them knows
how to cover his tracks.
Anything you can tell us
about the psychology
of the letter writer
would help.
"Pharmaceutical industry
and the fda
are conspiring to keep
the American people sick. "
Well, that part's
certainly true.
Is he serious?
Restless leg syndrome?
You don't think
that's an invention
of the drug companies
to sell more pills?
"You scum need
a hearty reminder. "
That's repeated in each
of the e-mails.
You think it means something?
"You scum need
a hearty reminder. "
"Techsan... "
"... murdered... Irene may. "
It's an anagram.
Some domestic terrorist
goes to all this trouble
to disguise the source
of his e-mails,
and then he just
gives us a name?
He's trying to prove
he's smarter than we are.
Very good, Agent Moretti.
"May v. Techsan,
dismissed in summary judgment,
filed by a Timothy may on behalf
of his mother, Irene. "
Wait here.
Once it's clear, you can
come up, take a look around.
FBI! We'd like to talk
to you!
Open it.
Mr. may?
FBI! Stop!
Stairs!
Freeze, Mr. may!
Are you all right?!
Fine.
You want
my professional opinion,
jumping off
a second-story fire escape
is what we commonly
call "crazy. "
Guess that makes two of us.
It's against the law to make
terrorist threats.
And murder is kind of
a no-no, too.
I didn't kill anyone.
Then I will ask
you again...
where were you the night
that Clark Weilman died?
You think I'm gonna cooperate
with the beast better known
as the United States
federal government?
Herbal tea.
What?
No milk, no sugar.
No sugar?
Processed sugar...
that's an addictive drug
peddled by big agribusiness
to promote an epidemic
in type 2 diabetes.
And then their pals
in big pharma
can reap billions
marketing treatments.
And don't even get me started
on why they put hormones
in milk.
I- I'm not a fed,
by the way.
Then what are you doing here?
College Professor.
Sometimes they ask
for my expert opinion.
And I-I bill the beast for my...
for my time, believe me.
Figure as long as they're
gonna bleed me with taxes,
might as well get something
out of it, right?
Your mother had type 2 diabetes,
didn't she?
She was always sending me out
to pick her up soda, ice cream.
I should have told her no.
Well, she was your mom.
You wanted to make her happy.
And you...
you wanted to help her.
That's why you signed her up
for a drug trial.
Is that right?
Techsan's new miracle pill,
insulprin?
They said it would cure her.
Instead, she drops dead
of a heart attack.
You think the drug killed her?
It's poison.
And the big-shot lawyers
at techsan
have your suit thrown out.
They said it was frivolous.
Bastards wouldn't even pay
for the funeral.
That must have made you
pretty angry.
You got no idea.
Angry enough
to kill Clark Weilman?
Look at me, mister.
You really think I got it in me
to cave some guy's head in?
Drop you back at campus.
What about the case?
You helped us solve it.
Thank you.
You don't really believe
that poor guy killed anybody?
No. He's paranoid.
He's not violent. I agree.
And we have
no physical evidence
connecting him
to the crime scene.
W- wait... I'm told I can be
a little absentminded,
so maybe I'm missing
something here.
We were assigned to investigate
terrorist threats.
We have the man who made
those threats in custody.
But there was a murder!
Local police matter.
Oh, come on.
You dangle a puzzle like this
in front of me,
and you expect me to drop it
before it's solved?
Listen...
You were right, okay?
My transfer back to Chicago
was a demotion.
What'd you do?
Leap off one too many
tall buildings
in pursuit of fleeing suspects?
The deputy director said
that I had a tendency
to go beyond the scope of
my assigned investigations.
Well, you can try to be
a good little bureaucrat
and deny your impulses,
but you know you're just
as incapable
of letting this go as I am.
Thank you for seeing us,
Dr. Bryant.
I don't know how much help
I can be.
I- I didn't know
Clark well.
Lawyers don't mix much
with lab rats.
Well, we've been talking
to everyone.
Mr. Weilman
had contact with...
uh, friends, associates
here at techsan.
Does your new blockbuster drug,
insulprin, cause heart attacks?
How is that relevant?
Uh, no, that's okay.
I'm happy to answer that.
Insulprin...
Has been rigorously tested
for five years.
Subjects taking the drug
are certainly no more likely
to have heart attacks
than the control group.
We're very proud
of insulprin here.
It's gonna save a lot of lives.
And earn billions of dollars.
W- what does any of this have to
do with Clark Weilman's murder?
There was a lawsuit
filed against this company
by a man claiming
his mother's coronary
was caused by insulprin,
maybe techsan.
Yeah.
I remember that suit.
It was dismissed in summary judgment.
Something funny?
Sad, actually.
Um, I remember it, too,
because it turns out
this may woman
was in the placebo group.
She wasn't even taking
the drug.
That answer your question?
Daniel?
Are we done here?
Daniel, are you okay?
Hmm.
Well, I appreciate your maybe
not-so-healthy distrust
of large institutions,
but how about we just put aside
your conspiracy theories
and focus on finding
the killer?
I'm looking
for a Valerie Nelson!
Hammond?
I'm Valerie Nelson.
Oh. I'd like to have a word
with you.
What's this all about?
Well, it seems
that Pamela Weilman
had another motive
for killing her husband.
According to his phone records,
he was making a lot
of late-night calls
to a pretty, young coworker.
I knew it was wrong, but...
I fell in love with him.
So, where were you
on the night of march 5th?
Home...
Waiting for Clark to call.
It was the night he was gonna
tell Pamela he was leaving.
I guess
she didn't take it so well.
One of the wife's symptoms
is anterograde amnesia, right?
Mm.
So her husband comes home,
tells her that he's leaving her
for some hottie
from the office.
She goes into
an adrenaline-fueled rage,
and she kills him.
But, because
of the korsakoff's,
by the time the police
get there,
she's forgotten why
she killed the guy.
And when the detective says
she did it
for the insurance money...
that's how she remembers it.
Impressive theory.
But wrong.
Pamela Weilman isn't a killer.
She's a victim.
First, her husband
cheats on her,
and then this neanderthal cop
tries to put her in jail...
which is typical of how
the mentally ill are treated
by our so-called
justice system.
Well, I'm stuck.
And the only thing
that I know of
that's going to get me unstuck
is burger grease.
You know cholesterol
is the silent killer?
You'll have a garden burger.
I'll buy it for you.
Let's go.
No.
No, I-I can't.
I have... I have an appointment.
So, why didn't you say yes?
Because I had a date with you.
Daniel, we haven't had a date
since grad school.
It's time to move on.
Admit it.
I'm wearing you down.
How do you feel?
I'm fine. Why?
And we both know how you get
when you don't stick
to your routine.
Which is why I have Lewicki.
He keeps me organized.
What are you gonna do
when he graduates?
You know...
you know how often Lewicki
changes majors?
I don't think there's
much danger of graduation.
Fly ball to right.
Well-hit.
Back near the wall...
And... Gone!
Yes!
Into the basket!
You see that?
It's spring training.
Let's see how they do
in October.
Oh, ye of little faith,
I am telling you,
this is the year.
Believing the cubs
are gonna win the pennant...
that is a symptom
of a delusional mind.
Rationality's overrated,
particularly
if you're a cubs fan.
I have to go.
I have a class tomorrow.
Good night, Daniel.
And another...
bad throw by Baker.
Everybody's safe.
Sloppy game again defensively,
and that ultimately
cost the cubs.
Sadists.
Lewicki?!
Dr. Pierce...
I'm so sorry
to bother you at home.
You work at techsan.
My name's Gerard Permut.
What can I do for you,
Mr. Permut?
I- I have information
on Clark Weilman's murder.
You should go to the FBI.
No, I-I can't, I can't. I can't
trust them, okay? I can't.
Listen, I-I've read
all your books,
every single one of them,
and I-I know...
I know that you understand
people like me.
And, please, I don't...
I don't have anyone else
to turn to. I really...
all right, all right.
All right.
Come on.
Would you like to sit down?
I- I didn't
mean to do it,
but the voices
in my head...
they told me
that I had to do it.
All right. W-what did the voices
tell you to do?
I'm in love
with Valerie Nelson.
I found out that she was
sleeping with Clark Weilman.
The voices told me
that the pain would...
would go away if I killed him.
Ohh!
All right.
I- I'm gonna get you some help.
She told me that
we had a life together.
That's what she said. I never
should have trusted her, ever.
That bitch...
she's a liar!
Lewicki!
Who are you calling?
It's all right.
He works for me, all right?
W- we're gonna get you some help.
Lewicki!
You need something, doc?
I'm right in the middle of
kicking Obi-Wan's jedi ass.
I'm sorry to call you away
from something so urgent.
But as you can see,
I have a situation here.
There's no one else here,
is there?
No, doc.
It's just you and me.
Almost had you.
Doc, you have to eat.
This is not what I wanted.
It's mahler's first.
That is the Von karajan
recording.
I asked for the solti.
Do you know how hard it is
to find a cassette tape?
All right, if you just let me
buy you an iPod,
we can download any recording
you want.
You know what? That's not a bad idea.
You got to get with the program.
Just stay out of this.
He's here?
You know, doc,
maybe this guy
isn't just a hallucination.
You know, maybe he's some kind
of psychic vision.
There have been studies
that show that these...
no, Lewicki,
there have been no studies.
There have been frauds and scams
and entertainments...
okay, you said
this vision told you
he was jealous of the dead guy.
Maybe there really is some kind
of twisted love-triangle thing going on, you know?
Why do you keep
this idiot around?
Because when assholes
like you show up,
I need someone to tell me
that you're not real.
Answer that!
Dr. Pierce's residence.
Yes, I'll tell him.
Dean Haley wants to see you.
What in God's name
were you thinking, Daniel?
I'll tell you exactly
what I was thinking, Paul.
I was thinking this
pheromone-spewing 20-year-old
has been sitting in
the front row of my class
making eyes at me
for three semesters running,
and now she's inviting me
for a latte.
Oh, and, by the way,
she's sticking a skin-tight
t- shirt in my face,
advertising herself
as a "stimulus package. "
I don't need any more stimuli.
Look, you can't just go around
accusing students
of wanting to have sex
with you,
especially not in front
of witnesses.
What witnesses?
Are you really that oblivious?
She was with a friend.
That's who filed the complaint.
You're joking.
Tell me you're...
Look, Daniel, I have put up
with all of your eccentricities
because you are
a brilliant scholar,
you're a popular teacher,
and you're my friend.
But have you any idea
what kind of a hit our endowment
has taken, hmm?
We cannot afford a lawsuit.
What are you asking me to do?
He wants me to apologize...
to both girls.
It's outrageous!
Why are you smiling?
What, y-you think this is funny?
What I think is, is that
you deflected this offer
from this student
for the same reason
you turned down the dinner
invitation with Kate Moretti.
Enlighten me.
You are petrified of
anything remotely resembling
an intimate connection
with another human being.
Oh, spare me the psychobabble.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Natalie, look at me.
I- I-I hear voices.
I see things that aren't there.
I talk to the walls.
How am I ever gonna have
an intimate connection
with anybody?
You had an incident.
Daniel?
Well, sometimes this happens.
You deal with it,
and you move on.
Right.
So, why is it
that I get the feeling
that you're more worried
about this than usual?
What if next time
it happens in front of Kate?
You told Kate about
your condition a long time ago.
Well, knowing and seeing
are two different things.
I don't... m-maybe
I should get off this case.
Quit without solving it?
Then you'd really go crazy.
Have you talked to rosenthal
about going back on your meds?
No, no.
We've talked... look, for some
people, they're a miracle...
n- not me.
But you had fewer symptoms.
And I couldn't concentrate
long enough
to finish a damn sodoku.
I couldn't write.
I couldn't work.
No, no, no.
I- I can handle this, nat.
I just... I'll keep up
my talk therapy with rosenthal.
I- I'll stick to my routine.
I'll watch my diet.
I'll keep my mind focused
and occupied.
Okay. Well,
let's focus on the incident.
Tell me about it.
What is there to tell?
It was a schizophrenic
hallucination.
It was the product
of randomly firing neurons.
Daniel, you know
how your mind works.
Sometimes these hallucinations
tell you things
that your conscious mind
can't make sense of.
Tell me what you saw.
The man.
He works at techsan,
then he came to my house,
said he was the killer,
which I'm pretty sure
is physically impossible.
What else did he say?
That Valerie Nelson is a liar.
Who is she?
She was having an affair
with the victim.
She says she has nothing to do
with the crime.
And the police believe her.
Well, if she's lying...
How could you prove it?
The international atomic energy
agency confirmed in the 1990s
that Saddam Hussein
had an advanced nuclear weapons
development program.
Why are you making me relive
this nightmare?
Just watch.
had a design
for a nuclear weapon
and was working
on five different methods
of enriching uranium
for a bomb.
The British government
has learned
that Saddam Hussein recently
sought significant quantities
of uranium from Africa.
Intelligence sources tell us
that he has attempted to...
Thank you, Jimmy.
Jimmy's an aphasiac.
He's lost the ability to
comprehend spoken language.
To compensate, many aphasiacs
become highly sensitive
to subtle inflections
in speech.
Now, when we lie,
those vocal nuances
become more pronounced.
Most of us wouldn't notice,
but aphasiacs do.
And for some reason,
to them, it sounds funny.
He's a human lie detector.
Now, p-put that in.
You're doing great.
So, where were you
on the night of march 5th?
Home...
Waiting for Clark to call.
It was the night he was gonna
tell Pamela he was leaving.
Ms. Nelson,
Agent Moretti, FBI.
Ms. Nelson?!
Valerie? Valerie?
I need an ambulance.
Robert!
Think she's gonna make it?
It's too early to say.
Vicious blow to the back
of the head like that?
She might not even
have seen her attacker.
Why are we still on this case?
Chicago p. D.
Should be handling it.
Just find out
who she's been talking to.
What's the nature of your
relationship with Ms. Nelson?
I couldn't have picked her out
of the crowd
at the company picnic.
Then why the calls?
We came down here voluntarily.
Mr. klane isn't
under any obligation
to answer these questions.
Were you aware that Valerie
was having an affair
with your dead general counsel?
What does that have to do
with me?
Maybe Clark Weilman
wasn't the only one
getting executive perks
from Valerie.
Maybe you found out,
got jealous, killed Clark,
and then you tried to do
the same thing to Valerie.
What?!
We're done here.
Even if she doesn't
survive this surgery,
we will find out
what the two of you were up to.
Okay, Philip, Philip, let's go.
Sit, sit, it's fine.
Chamomile.
No milk, no sugar.
After Clark was killed,
I got an e-mail
from Ms. Valerie
saying it was urgent
I should call her, so I did.
You're welcome.
She said she had information
that could be damaging
to the company.
What kind of information?
Something about anomalous study
results for one of our products.
She said she didn't want to talk about it
Don't drink that.
What time?
It might kill you.
Are you trying to poison me?!
I told you, no milk, no sugar.
Come on, doc. That's the
murder weapon. Tea?
Yeah, it's tea.
Not tea... poison.
Remember Timothy may?
Said his mother was poisoned.
I poisoned her...
And killed Clark Weilman.
I don't understand.
What's to understand?
She's trying to
establish motive.
I'll give you a motive.
She was going to expose me,
and now that's your job.
How?
Can you be quiet, please?
I'm trying to listen.
Aah!
What the hell?
I just bought this suit!
Sorry. Try club soda.
You've had a gut feeling
all this time, haven't you,
especially after what
Timothy may said about his mom
and what those people
at techsan claimed
about the insulprin study.
What are you talking about?
Don't you remember my name?
Gerard Permut.
So what?
So, I know how much
you like puzzles.
It's another anagram.
I solved it.
I think I solved it.
"Gerard Permut.
Drug tamperer. "
Who's Gerard Permut?
You wrote on the wall?
I think somebody tampered
with the results
of the insulprin study.
What makes you say that?
Gut feeling.
Timothy may believed his mother
was poisoned,
that her heart attack was caused
by the medication.
Timothy may is paranoid.
That doesn't make him wrong.
May's mother
was taking a placebo.
According to the data
reported by the company.
Which you believe
was tampered with.
It would cost
the company billions
to pull that drug
off the market.
C.E.O. Would certainly have
motive to cover that up.
Maybe.
But who had direct access
to the study results?
Dr. Bryant.
Agent Moretti.
Dr. Pierce.
What can I do for you?
We are trying to figure out
who tried to kill
Valerie Nelson.
We found these
on her hard drive.
We were hoping maybe you could
tell us what they are.
Well, these look like
study results
of morbidity rates.
Right,
from your insulprin trial,
except they show an unusually
high incidence of heart attack
among women participating
in the study.
Yeah, well, there...
there must be a mistake.
What about this one?
Ah, yes.
These are the correct results.
Ah. You see here?
The incidence of heart attacks
is approximately the same
for those taking the placebo
as for those
taking the real drug.
But only because somebody
tampered with these results.
They moved patient names
from one group into the other.
Come on.
Who'd do something like that?
Valerie found out you were
falsifying the study,
so she went to her boyfriend,
techsan's top lawyer.
They were gonna ruin everything
that you had worked for,
so you had to stop them.
That's ridiculous.
Size 10 brogans?
What?
Your shoes.
You left a bloody footprint
in Valerie's apartment.
You spend your whole career
looking for that
one miracle cure, you know?
This wasn't about money for you.
It was about science.
You understand,
Dr. Pierce.
Every drug has side effects.
I figured out why it was causing
the heart attacks.
I could have worked out
the kinks...
But Valerie started
collecting evidence against me
like I'm a criminal.
You mean the study results.
Yes.
And then I saw her
stealing pills...
So I followed her.
She brought them to Clark.
She goes to a lawyer
instead of me?!
You figured
that they were going
to get the pills
independently tested,
prove that they were dangerous.
I thought...
If I could just
make him understand.
Clark, I don't know what
Valerie's been telling you,
but I can fix this.
Do you have any idea
the liability
you've exposed this company to?
Clark, please!
Get out of here
before I get the police!
Ohh!
I guess I went a little crazy.
Nice work, detective.
Psycho.
You didn't tell me
you found a footprint
in Valerie's apartment.
I didn't.
Detective Moretti, I am shocked
that you would
so blatantly manipulate
an obviously troubled
individual.
What's up, doc?
Daniel, what is it?
Case isn't over yet.
What are you talking about?
Daniel?
Dr. Bryant!
What now?
You said you figured out why
insulprin was
causing heart attacks.
What was it?
The drug was depleting
patients' thiamine levels.
Daniel, what is going on?
There's another victim.
Ms. Nelson?
I'm Agent Moretti, FBI.
This is Dr. Pierce.
Would you mind if I asked you
a couple questions
for our case
against Dr. Bryant?
I still can't believe
he tried to kill me.
Well, you found out
he was tampering
with the insulprin study,
so you told Clark Weilman
about your suspicions?
I knew that drug
was gonna hurt a lot of people
when it hit the market.
Clark was a lawyer.
I- I figured
he'd know what to do.
So he told you
you needed more evidence?
That's why you brought him
the pills?
Clark didn't want to expose
the company to any liability
unless he knew for sure.
Dr. Bryant had done
something wrong.
What?
It's just funny you didn't tell
the police any of this.
T- they wanted to know about
my relationship with Clark.
I didn't think it had anything
to do with the drug.
Oh, come on.
You gave Clark Weilman
those pills
so he could poison
his wife, right?
Are you out of your mind?
Well, that's not
the clinical description,
but yes, actually.
And poor Dr. Bryant...
he was out of his mind, too.
He was feeling so guilty
for what he'd done
that he became paranoid,
and he made
the same mistake we did.
He assumed that you'd stolen
those pills as evidence
when in fact you were supplying
Clark Weilman
with the perfect murder weapon.
What are you talking about?
The drug wasn't
on the market yet,
so it was
virtually untraceable.
You must have been dosing
Pamela for weeks,
just waiting for her heart
to give out.
I was trying to do
the right thing.
Why else would I call the C.E.O.
Of the company
and tell him
about the falsified results?
You were worried
that Pamela found out
her husband was poisoning her.
If she went to the police,
you would need a cover story
to explain why you had given him
the pills,
so you pretended
to be a whistle-blower.
No.
That is not right.
No, what's not right
is that Pamela Weilman was
accused of killing her husband
when in fact
you and your boyfriend
were trying to kill her.
I want a lawyer.
Gonna need a good one.
Nice working with you, doc.
You wanted to see me,
Professor?
Karyn, yes.
Uh, come in, please.
Um, I-I wanted
to apologize
for what I said on the common
the other day.
It was... it was,
uh, highly inappropriate
and, uh, uh, offensive.
And very perceptive.
I'm sorry my friend
was such a bitch.
I told her not to file
that complaint.
Oh, oh, uh, uh,
could you...
could you just wait...
uh, wait here one second?
Lewicki!
W- what is it, doc?
I need you to tell me if
there's someone in my office.
Hey!
That one was definitely real.
Last week, I asked,
"what is reality?"
This week,
I want to talk about normalcy.
What is normal?
If you feel sad, do you just
have a case of the blues,
or are you suffering
from a neurochemical imbalance?
The vast majority
of the case studies
that we've been looking at
involve patients whose brains
are anything but normal,
and there's no question
they suffer.
But...
Is it all bad?
For some,
their neurological states
might actually protect them
from painful truths that no one
would want to think about.
Others develop
a- a cheerful disposition
that may help them cope
with situations
the rest of us
would find disturbing.
And if we are
to establish a baseline,
then we also
have to ask ourselves
how the brains of even
so-called normal people
respond to certain stimuli.
And if we're able to
treat those people
living with
neurological disorders,
restore them to...
quote... "normalcy,"
well, of course
we're helping them.
But might we sometimes
also be stripping away
what makes them unique...
robbing them
of an essential part
of who they are?
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www. Addic7ed. Com
www.tvsubtitles.net