WHICH COMES FIRST --
YESTERDAY OR TOMORROW?
HANDS UP FOR YESTERDAY.
RIGHT. AND TOMORROW?
WOW. NOBODY?
NOT ONE?
MORTICIA,
EXPLAIN HOW YOU ARRIVED
AT THAT PREDICTABLE,
BUT UNPROVABLE, CONCLUSION.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING
ANYBODY HAS TO PROVE.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING
YOU KNOW.
Daniel:
SOMETHING YOU KNOW?
ALL WE KNOW IS THAT
WHAT WE THINK OF
AS PAST, PRESENT,
AND FUTURE
IS NOTHING MORE THAN A --
THAN A STORY
STITCHED TOGETHER
IN OUR BASAL GANGLIA.
OUR ENTIRE CONCEPT OF TIME
IS A --
IS AN ARTIFICIAL CONSTRUCT.
IN THAT CASE, I DON'T NEED
TO HAND IN MY LAB REPORT.
BECAUSE FOR ALL YOU KNOW,
I ALREADY DID.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THAT IS ENTIRELY CORRECT!
OF COURSE, BY THAT THINKING,
I MAY ALREADY HAVE FLUNKED YOU.
[ LAUGHTER ]
Max: ARTIFICIAL CONSTRUCT
OR NOT,
YOU HAVE A CURRICULUM REVIEW
WITH THE PROVOST IN 7 MINUTES,
AND DON'T FORGET YOU'VE GOT
6 THESIS PROPOSALS TO REVIEW
BEFORE OFFICE HOURS
AT 4:00,
SO IF YOU COULD
PICK UP THE PACE?
OKAY, YOU'RE OVERBOOKING ME,
LEWICKI.
THE BRAIN NEEDS DOWNTIME
TO FUNCTION.
NOT YOURS. WHAT DID YOU TELL ME
WHEN YOU HIRED ME?
"SCHEDULE
EQUALS SANITY."
IF YOU REALLY CARED
ABOUT MY SANITY,
YOU'D KEEP THE PROVOST
OUT OF MY CURRICULUM.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
A LITTLE BREAK WILL DO YOU GOOD.
I'LL BE BACK IN A MINUTE.
AND NEVER SAY
I DON'T BRING YOU TREATS.
"EXTREME KAKURO."
VERY NICE.
AGENT MORETTI.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU DOING TODAY?
I'M FINE. THANK YOU, MAX.
HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GOOD, I'M GOOD,
BUT UNFORTUNATELY,
PROFESSOR PIERCE
IS A LITTLE BUSY RIGHT NOW.
WELL, HE DOESN'T LOOK
VERY BUSY TO ME.
IF YOU NEED A CONSULTANT,
I CAN INTRODUCE YOU
TO ANOTHER VERY FINE PROFESSOR
IN THE DEPARTMENT.
THANK YOU, MAX, BUT
IT'S REALLY DR. PIERCE
THAT I NEED TO TALK TO.
I HATE TO SOUND DRAMATIC,
BUT IT REALLY COULD BE
A MATTER OF LIFE AND DEATH.
DOC --
YOU CAN TELL THE PROVOST
I'LL BE THERE AS SOON AS I CAN.
OKAY, WHAT IF HE'S AD--
AND IF HE COMPLAINS
THAT I'M LATE,
TELL HIM IT'S ALL
IN HIS BASAL GANGLIA.
Kate: REMEMBER
THE DATE NIGHT KILLER,
SUMMER OF '86?
VAGUELY.
WAIT, DANIEL, IT WAS
THE CRIME OF THE DECADE.
HOW CAN YOU NOT
REMEMBER THIS?
WELL, IT'S A HARD TO KEEP UP
WITH THE NEWS
WHEN YOU'RE CRAMMING
FOR YOUR MCATs.
OKAY, FOR FIVE WEEKS
IN A ROW,
EVERY FRIDAY, A GIRL WOULD
GO MISSING IN THE AFTERNOON
AND TURN UP DEAD IN A LANDFILL
ON SUNDAY MORNING,
RAPED AND BEATEN.
WELL,
THE KILLINGS STOPPED,
BUT THEY NEVER CAUGHT
THE GUY WHO DID IT.
WHY ARE YOU WORKING
ON A COLD CASE?
'CAUSE
IT'S NOT COLD ANYMORE.
THESE ARE CLIPPINGS
FROM 1986.
BUT SUNDAY BEFORE LAST,
A BODY TURNS UP IN AVONDALE,
SAME M.O. AS '86,
SAME CHLOROFORM BURNS
AROUND THE MOUTH,
BUT CPD DIDN'T MAKE
THE CONNECTION
UNTIL ANOTHER BODY SHOWED UP
JUST THIS PAST SUNDAY
IN LINCOLNWOOD.
BUT THIS TIME,
THEY GOT A PRINT.
100% MATCH TO ONE OF
THE CRIME SCENES FROM BACK THEN.
SO IF THE KILLER
STICKS TO THE PATTERN,
ANOTHER GIRL DISAPPEARS
FRIDAY NIGHT.
AND TURNS UP DEAD
ON SUNDAY.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU
CATCH HIM?
VICTIM NUMBER 6.
LACEY PENDERHALT.
THE KILLER GRABBED HER
FRIDAY, JULY 18, 1986.
THE NEXT DAY,
A PROPANE STOVE BLEW UP
AN ABANDONED HOUSE IN MAYWOOD.
FIREMEN FOUND LACEY
IN THE CELLAR,
TIED UP, UNCONSCIOUS,
BUT ALIVE.
BY THE TIME SHE CAME TO,
SHE WAS SO TRAUMATIZED,
SHE HAD SOME KIND
OF A PSYCHOTIC BREAK.
THE POLICE TRIED
TO QUESTION HER,
BUT SHE WAS INCOHERENT.
DID SHE EVER RECOVER?
WELL, SHE'S BEEN LIVING
IN A PSYCHIATRIC NURSING HOME
FOR THE PAST 26 YEARS,
APPARENTLY PRETTY OUT OF IT.
AND YOU WANT ME TO SEE
IF I CAN GET THROUGH TO HER.
THE BUREAU'S GOT 50 AGENTS
WORKING CRIME SCENES,
CHASING DOWN LEADS,
TRACKING PRESENT-DAY VICTIMS.
BUT I THINK
THAT THE ANSWER IS LACEY.
WELL, IF I'M GONNA HAVE
ANY HOPE OF REACHING HER,
I'M GONNA NEED TO KNOW
MOABSOLUTELY.S.
I JUST DON'T THINK YOU
SHOULD HEAR IT SECONDHAND.
I THINK YOU SHOULD GET THIS
FROM SOMEBODY WHO WAS THERE.
WHO'S THAT?
RETIRED POLICE DETECTIVE
JOE MORETTI,
A.K.A. MY DAD.
IT WAS A TERRIBLE SUMMER.
I WOULDN'T LET KATIE
3 FEET OUT OF MY SIGHT.
I WAS 6, DAD.
NOT EXACTLY THE TARGET DEMO.
TALK TO ME
WHEN YOU'RE A PARENT.
EVERY DETECTIVE
ON THE FORCE
WAS WORKING SOME ANGLE
OF THAT CASE.
MY SQUAD,
WE WERE CHECKING OUT
THE CLUES
FROM THE KILLER'S JOURNAL.
HE KEPT A JOURNAL?
YOU BURIED THE LEAD,
AG[ CHUCKLES ]
DON'T WORRY.
I BROUGHT A COPY.
THEY FOUND THE ORIGINAL
IN THE WRECKED HOUSE.
THIS IS WHERE THE KILLER KEPT
TRACK OF ALL HIS CRUSHES.
"I MET THE MOST INCREDIBLE GIRL
ON THE EL TODAY.
LILY --
ISN'T THAT A BEAUTIFUL NAME?"
LILY PASETTI.
VICTIM NUMBER 3.
SOUNDS LIKE
HE WAS FIXATED ON HER.
YEAH, FOR A WEEK.
EVERY MONDAY AND TUESDAY,
HE'D MEET A NEW GIRL,
AND SHE'D BE "THE ONE."
ON WEDNESDAY AND THURSDAY,
HE'D WRITE ABOUT DANCING
WITH THEM IN A CLUB
OR SWIMMING WITH THEM
AT THE LAKE.
AND EVERY SUNDAY,
IT WAS THE SAME THING --
HOW THE GIRL
DISAPPOINTED HIM,
HOW SHE'D BROKEN HIS HEART
OR TURNED OUT TO BE A PHONY.
"I BOUGHT SANDRA A DRINK
AT THE BLACKLIGHT."
ANYBODY AT THE BLACKLIGHT
SEE WHO BOUGHT HER A DRINK?
SHE WAS A HOT NUMBER.
FRIENDS SAID THERE WAS A TON
OF GUYS BUYING HER DRINKS.
BUT WE COULDN'T PUT
ANY ONE OF THOSE GUYS
AT THE CLUB
WHERE LILY WAS DANCING
OR SWIMMING AT THE LAKE
WITH SUZANNE.
BUT THE ENTRIES ABOUT LACEY
ARE DIFFERENT.
"I SAW LACEY TODAY,
AND I THOUGHT,
'WOW, SHE'S BEEN HERE
ALL SUMMER, EVERYWHERE I LOOK.'"
HE KNEW HER.
THAT'S WHY
WE WERE ALWAYS HOPING
THAT LACEY
WOULD COME AROUND,
BUT SHE'S NUTTIER
THAN GRANDMA'S FRUITCAKE.
SORRY, KATIE.
JUST A FIGURE OF SPEECH.
WHAT I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
IS WHY HE WOULD TAKE IT UP AGAIN
AFTER A 26-YEAR VACATION.
MAYBE HE GOT SCARED AFTER
YOU FOUND HIS HIDEOUT,
OR MAYBE HE JUST FOUND
SOME OTHER WAY
TO SCRATCH
WHAT WAS ITCHING HIM.
EITHER WAY, IT'S TIME
TO GO TALK TO LACEY PENDERHALT.
THANKS.
AND MAYBE SOMEDAY
YOU'LL EVEN COME AROUND
WHEN YOU DON'T NEED
SOMETHING.
NO, NO, NO.
NO,DAD --O.
I UNDERSTAND, FRESH IN TOWN,
NEW JOB, LOTS TO DO.
SPEAKING
ABOUT FRESH IN TOWN,
WHEN IS DONNIE
COMING IN FROM D.C.?
SOON. DEFINITELY. YEAH, SOON.
I -- AND I'LL CALL YOU.
NICE TYEAH.T YOU.
WAIT.
I JUST REMEMBERED.
I MET YOU PARENTS' NIGHT,
KATIE'S FRESHMAN YEAR.
YOU'RE THE PROFESSOR
SHE HAD THE BIG CRUSH ON
THE WHOLE TIME
S[ SQUEALS ] NOPE..
WHAT?
SO, YOU'RE PROBABLY WONDERING
WHO DONNIE IS.
NONE OF MY BUSINESS.
WELL, IT'S OKAY.
I SHOULD HAVE TOLD YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL ME
ANYTHING.
HE'S MY HUSBAND.
YOU'RE MARRIED?
SOON-TO-BE DIVORCED.
I MET HIM IN D.C.
IT JUST DID NOT WORK OUT.
WHY ARE YOU LYING
TO YOUR FATHER ABOUT THAT?
HE HATED DONNIE THE SECOND
HE LAID EYES ON HIM.
"HE'S ALL WRONG FOR YOU,
KATIE."
I JUST COULDN'T GIVE HIM
THE SATISFACTION
OF KNOWING HE WAS RIGHT,
YOU KNOW?
AGENT MORETTI?
DR. PIERCE?
RYAN CUTLER.
THANKS FOR SEEING US,
DR. CUTLER.
DOES LACEY KNOW
WE'RE COMING?
LACEY DOESN'T KNOW
MUCH OF ANYTHING.
IF YOU'RE HOPING FOR HELP
SOLVING YOUR CASE,
I'M AFRAID YOU'RE GOING TO BE
VERY DISAPPOINTED.
HI, LACEY.
MY NAME IS DR. PIERCE,
AND THIS IS MY FRIEND,
KATE MORETTI, WITH THE FBI.
IS IT ALL RIGHT IF WE ASK YOU
SOME QUESTIONS?
I'LL COME BACK A LITTLE LATER,
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA NEED TO SEE
HER COMPLETE MEDICAL HISTORY.
I'M -- I'M, UH, TOLD
THAT I CAN BE A LITTLE ADDLED,
SO, UH, LET ME SEE
IF I UNDERSTAND
WHAT IT IS
THAT I'VE BEEN READING.
26 YEARS AGO,
AFTER BEING BEATEN, RAPED,
TIED UP AND GAGGED,
LACEY PENDERHALT WAS
UNDERSTANDABLY HYSTERICAL,
AGITATED, AND DISORIENTED,
FOR WHICH CONDITION
SHE WAS ADMINISTERED
2 MILLIGRAMS OF LONOXONOL,
WHICH, EVEN IN THAT
PREHISTORIC ERA,
WAS 10 TIMES
THE RECOMMENDED DOSE
OF A DANGEROUSLY
POWERFUL SEDATIVE,
WHICH HAS SINCE BEEN PROVEN
TO TRIGGER PSYCHOSIS
IN PATIENTS
WITH RECENT HEAD INJURIES.
BECAUSE THE DRUG CAUSED LACEY
TO PRESENT AS PSYCHOTIC,
SHE WAS DIAGNOSED
WITH TRAUMATOGENIC
SCHIZO-AFFECTIVE DISORDER --
A PHRASE I MERCIFULLY HAVEN'T
HEARD SPOKEN IN 20 YEARS --
AND TREATED WITH HEAVY DOSES
OF CHLORPROMAZINE,
ANOTHER GENUINE RELIC OF
PSYCHOTHERAPEUTIC ANTIQUITY,
WHICH RENDERED HER
NEARLY COMATOSE.
THE NOW MENTALLY DISABLED
PATIENT
WAS TRANSFERRED
TO A LONG-TERM CARE FACILITY,
WHERE
THE SO-CALLED DOCTORS
RUBBER-STAMPED
THE ORIGINAL DIAGNOSIS
LIKE THE GOOD LITTLE EMPLOYEES
THEY WERE.
THE PATIENTS IN THIS FACILITY
GET THE VERY BEST POSSIBLE CARE.
RIGHT, I.E., ONCE A MONTH
A FUNCTIONARY ON THE PAYROLL
OF THE NATIONWIDE
HEALTH CONGLOMERATE
THAT OWNS THIS CHAIN OF
WAREHOUSES FOR THE MENTALLY ILL
GLANCES AT A CHART,
CHECKS A BOX,
AND MOVES ON TO THE NEXT
PATIENT ON THE SHELF.
YOU'RE GOING TO LEAVE NOW.
YES, I AM,
BUT I'LL BE BACK.
IN THE MEANTIME, I WANT LACEY
TAKEN OFF HER MEDS
SO I CAN ASK HER
SOME QUESTIONS.
I AM NOT GOING TO ENDANGER
MY PATIENT
ON THE STRENGTH
OF AN OPINION
OFFERED BY AN IVORY TOWER
THEORETICIAN
AFTER A 30-SECOND
EXAMINATION.
THE FACT IS, THE DECISION
ISN'T REALLY IN YOUR HANDS,
IS IT, DOCTOR?
WE'RE TALKING
TO THE WRONG PERSON.
THIS IS LACEY'S ROOM.
I HAVEN'T TOUCHED A THING
SINCE THE NIGHT
SHE WAS ATTACKED.
WE ALL KNEW
THE KILLER WAS OUT THERE.
I NEVER SHOULD HAVE LET HER
OUT OF MY SIGHT.
ACCORDING TO THE STATEMENT
YOU GAVE BACK THEN,
LACEY TOLD YOU
SHE WAS GOING TO A MOVIE?
"FERRIS BUELLER'S DAY OFF."
SHE KEPT SAYING,
"MOM, I'M NOT AN IDIOT.
"THERE'S A MILLION PEOPLE
ON THE STREET.
I'M NOT GONNA WALK DOWN
SOME DARK ALLEYWAY."
DR. PIERCE, IF I LET YOU DO
WHAT YOU'RE ASKING...
IF THEY STOP
GIVING HER THE DRUGS...
...WILL SHE
KNOW ME AGAIN?
HONESTLY, I DON'T KNOW
THE ANSWER TO THAT.
BUT IF WE TRY THIS,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO STOP
THE KILLER
FROM HURTING ANYBODY ELSE'S
DAUGHTER.
HAVE YOU STOPPED
HER MEDS?ST IN TIME.
YOU TELL ME.
[ GASPING ]
WHO ARE YOU?!
GET AWAY FROM ME!
VALIUM, 20cc.
UNLESS MY ESTEEMED COLLEAGUE
CAN OFFER A BETTER SUGGESTION.
IF YOU'D SEEN WHAT I DID
TO THIS POOR WOMAN.
I'M SURE YOU DID
WHAT YOU THOUGHT WAS RIGHT.
SO DID JOSEPH STALIN.
HOW COULD I HAVE BEEN SO WRONG
ABOUT SOMETHING --
DANIEL?
WHAT IS IT?
ME...IN ABOUT 40 YEARS.
[ SIGHS ]
THAT WAS WEIRD ONE,
EVEN FOR ME.
YOU'RE HALLUCINATING.
WHAT ELSE IS NEW?
DIDN'T I READ A BOOK ONCE
BY A CERTAIN BRILLIANT
NEUROSURGEON
WHO SPECULATES
THAT SOMETIMES,
EVEN THE MOST FRIGHTENING
HALLUCINATIONS
CAN BE THE BRAIN'S WAY
OF MAKING SENSE
OF THINGS THAT SEEM RANDOM?
MAYBE THE AUTHOR
OF THAT BOOK
WAS JUST TRYING
TO MAKE HIMSELF FEEL BETTER.
DANIEL, THINK.
WHAT IS THE OLD YOU
TELLING THE YOUNG YOU?
[ GASPS ]
THAT'S IT.
DANIEL, WHAT IS IT?
THAT'S WHAT
MUST HAWHAT?PPENED.
YEAH, BUT WHERE --
WHERE WAS I?
I-I DIDN'T SEE IT IN THERE.
NATALIE, I-I CAN'T --
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT RIGHT NOW.
DOC?
ARE YOU HAVING AN EPISODE?
YES,
I'M HAVING AN EPISODE.
WELL, DOC, IT'S OKAY.
I NEED TO GO TO THE HOSPITAL
RIGHT NOW.
YOU KNOW, I-I KNEW
I SHOULD HAVE KEPT
AGENT MORETTI AWAY FROM YOU.
WE'LL HAVE A DOCTOR
SEE YOU RIGHT AWAY.
I DON'T NEED TO BE ADMITTED,
LEWICKI.
I NEED TO SEE LACEY.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I KNEW IT.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
LACEY DIDN'T GET UPSET
BECAUSE SHE WAS HAVING SOME KIND
OF PSYCHOTIC HALLUCINATION.
SHE SAW HER OWN REFLECTION
IN THE GLASS,
AND SHE DIDN'T KNOW
WHO IT WAS.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
HAVE YOU GOT HER BACK
ON THE ANTIPSYCHOTICS YET?
NOT YET.
GOOD. MAYBE SHE'LL
TALK TO ME.
IF YOU BOTHER HER AGAIN,
YOU'LL BE DEALING
WITH SECURITY, NOT ME.
DOCTOR,
IT'S TUESDAY NIGHT.
ON FRIDAY,
ANOTHER GIRL DISAPPEARS.
DO YOU WANT THAT GIRL'S BLOOD
ON YOUR HANDS?
LACEY.
LACEY,
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME'S DR. PIERCE.
HOW DID I GET HERE?
YOU WERE THE VICTIM
OF A VIOLENT CRIME.
WHERE'S MY MOM?!
YOU'LL SEE YOUR MOTHER
VERY SOON, I PROMISE YOU.
RIGHT NOW,
THE POLICE NEED TO KNOW
THE VERY LAST THING
YOU REMEMBER.
I REMEMBER TALKING
TO MY FRIEND CINDY
ON THE PHONE LAST NIGHT,
AND THEN I--
AND THEN I WENT TO SLEEP.
WHAT NIGHT WAS LAST NIGHT?
THURSDAY.
WHAT HAPPENED TO ME?
WHAT IS GOING ON?
LACEY...
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
17.
RIGHT THERE --
SIGNIFICANT ACCUMULATION
OF HEMOSIDERIN --
OLD HEMORRHAGED BLOOD.
UH, MEANING WHAT?
LACEY SUFFERED
A TRAUMATIC BRAIN INJURY
AT THE TIME
OF HER ABDUCTION,
EITHER AT THE HANDS
OF HER KILLER
OR BECAUSE SOMETHING FELL ON
HER HEAD WHEN THE HOUSE BLEW UP.
HOW COME NOBODY
NOTICED THIS BACK IN 1986?
THEY DIDN'T HAVE
THIS TECHNOLOGY,
SO THEY JUST DRUGGED HER,
ASSUMING IT WAS
A PSYCHIATRIC PROBLEM,
AND THEY KEPT DRUGGING HER.
OKAY, NOW,
HOW DOES THIS HELP US?
IT GIVES US A DIAGNOSIS...
AND A PLAN.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING,
LACEY?
WHO ARE YOU?
HOW DID I GET HERE?
WHERE'S MY MOM?
LACEY HAS A TEXTBOOK CASE
OF ANTEROGRADE AMNESIA.
WHICH MEANS WHAT,
EXACTLY?
IT'S A RARE DISORDER
IN WHICH THE SUBJECT IS UNABLE
TO CREATE NEW MEMORIES.
Kate: THAT'S WHY
SHE THINKS SHE'S 17, BOSS --
NOT BECAUSE SHE'S DELUSIONAL,
BUT BECAUSE NOTHING
THAT'S HAPPENED TO HER
FOR THE LAST 26 YEARS
HAS STUCK.
SHE CAN HOLD ONTO THINGS
FOR A SHORT WHILE --
THE LENGTH OF A CONVERSATION,
MAYBE A LITTLE LONGER,
BUT THEN IT'S GONE.
DOES SHE REMEMBER
WHO ATTACKED HER?
NO. EVERYTHING STOPS
AT THURSDAY NIGHT.
WELL,
WHAT GOOD IS A WITNESS
WHO CAN'T REMEMBER
SOMEONE SHE MET AN HOUR AGO,
MUCH LESS THE MAN WHO ATTACKED
HER AND KIDNAPPED HER IN 1986?
ACTUALLY, WE HAVE
EVERY REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT BECAUSE OF HER CONDITION,
SHE DOES REMEMBER HIM.
HOW DO YOU FIGURE THAT?
ACCORDING TO THE JOURNAL,
THE KILLER IS SOMEONE
THAT LACEY INTERACTED WITH
SEVERAL TIMES
IN THE DAYS
LEADING UP TO HER ABDUCTION.
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED
TO HER THAT WEEK
IS AS FRESH IN HER MIND
A-AS THIS MORNING IS FOR US.
IF THE PHYSICAL INJURY
CAUSED THE AMNESIA,
THEN WHY WOULDN'T
SHE REMEMBER EVERYTHING
UP TO THE MOMENT
SHE GOT CLOBBERED?
BECAUSE HER MEMORY
WASN'T CUT LIKE A RIBBON.
IT WAS -- IT WAS SMASHED,
LIKE GLASS.
LACEY'S MOTHER HAS KEPT
HER BEDROOM LIKE A TIME CAPSULE.
NOTHING HAS CHANGED
SINCE THE DAY SHE LEFT.
NOW, IF WE BRING HER HOME
WHEN SHE'S SEDATED,
LET HER WAKE UP
WHERE SHE EXPECTS TO,
AND FOR HER, IT'LL BE
A FRIDAY MORNING IN 1986.
WE'LL BE ABLE TO ASK
HER ABOUT EVERYTHING
THAT SHE SAW THAT WEEK.
WE KNOW WHAT TO ASK.
WE GOT THE JOURNAL.
NOT EXACTLY ORTHODOX.
ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
"ORTHODOX" HASN'T
EXACTLY CAUGHT THIS KILLER.
LOOK, THE MOTHER'S GOT TO BE
WHAT, LIKE 65?
HOW ARE YOU GONNA EXPLAIN
HER AGING 26 YEARS OVERNIGHT?
PROBERT, I DO KNOW THAT WOMEN
ARE A COMPLETE MYSTERY TO YOU,
BUT HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
OF A LITTLE SOMETHING
CALLED A MAKEOVER?
Daniel: YOU LOOK WONDERFUL,
MRS. PENDERHALT.
YOU TOOK CARE OF THE CORDLESS
PHONES, EVERYTHING ELSE?
IT'S ALL IN THE GARAGE.
S-SHE LOOKED SO PEACEFUL
LAST NIGHT,
ASLEEP IN HER OWN BED.
I'M JUST TERRIFIED
OF WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
WHEN SHE WAKES UP.
SHE'LL BE AT HOME,
IN HER OWN ROOM.
AND YOU'LL JUST INTRODUCE HER
TO SOME PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO ASK HER
A COUPLE QUESTIONS.
WELL, WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU ARE GONE?
I MEAN, SAY WE WALK INTO
THE KITCHEN AND WE'RE TALKING,
AND SUDDENLY SHE CAN'T REMEMBER
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
OR HOW SHE EVEN
GOT IN THERE?
SO TELL HER A HALF-TRUTH.
SHE GOT A BUMP
ON THE HEAD,
AND THAT'S WHY SHE'S BEEN
A LITTLE FORGETFUL.
THE DOCTOR SAYS SHE NEEDS
TO STAY HOME AND REST,
AND SHE'LL BE FINE
TOMORROW.
AND THEN THAT TOMORROW
NEVER COMES.
SHE'S AT HOME
WITH SOMEONE WHO LOVES HER
AND NOT WITH STRANGERS
IN SOME HOSPITAL.
WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN SHE LOOKS AT HER OWN HANDS?
FOR 26 YEARS, SHE HASN'T WASHED
A DISH OR CHIPPED A NAIL.
I-I WISH MY HANDS
LOOKED LIKE HERS.
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
MOM!
COULD YOU, LIKE, KNOCK?
Lacey:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
LACEY, I'M SURE
YOU'VE BEEN HEARING ON THE NEWS
ABOUT
THE DATE NIGHT KILLER.
OH, MY GOD.
DID ANOTHER GIRL GET KILLED?
PLEASE TELL ME
IT'S NOT SOMEBODY I KNOW.
NO. NO, ANGEL.
EVERYBODY'S FINE.
MOM...
I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST SO -- I'M JUST SO HAPPY
TO HAVE YOU HOME, HONEY.
WHERE ELSE WOULD I BE?
RIGHT.
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
YOU DON'T LOOK SO HOT.
NO, I'M FINE. I JUST --
I DIDN'T SLEEP VERY WELL.
MRS. PENDERHALT, CAN I TROUBLE
YOU FOR A CUP OF COFFEE?
NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK, HONEY.
OH, I LOVE THEM.
OH. [ LAUGHS ]
GREAT MINDS.
LACEY, THE POLICE
FOUND A JOURNAL
THAT THE KILLER
HAS BEEN KEEPING ALL SUMMER
OF THE GIRLS
WHO HE'S KIDNAPPED,
AND, UH, I'M AFRAID
THAT THE MOST RECENT ENTRIES
HAVE BEEN ABOUT YOU.
ARE YOU SAYING
HE WANTS TO KILL ME?
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
WE NEED TO ASK YOU
SOME QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHO YOU'VE BEEN
TALKING TO THIS WEEK,
BECAUSE WE BELIEVE
THAT ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
COULD BE THE KILLER.
ON MONDAY,
HE WROTE IN HIS JOURNAL,
"HAD A BLAST WATCHING
LACEY PLAY SOFTBALL."
DO YOU REMEMBER ANYONE
WATCHING YOU PLAY SOFTBALL?
NO.
UNLESS...
UNLESS?
COACH PARKER.
BUT IT COULDN'T BE HIM.
I MEAN, HE'S, LIKE,
THE GREATEST GUY EVER.
EXCEPT?
SOMETIMES, I THINK THERE'S
SOMETHING A LITTLE SKEEZY
ABOUT THE WAY
HE LOOKS AT CHERYL JAMES.
DO YOU THINK
IT COULD BE COACH PARKER?
UH, WE DON'T KNOW, BUT WE
WILL CERTAINLY CHECK IT OUT.
SOMEONE COMPLAINED
ABOUT INAPPROPRIATE BEHAVIOR
26 YEARS AGO?
NOT A COMPLAINT.
JUST A REPORT ABOUT AN UNDERAGED
GIRL NAMED CHERYL JAMES.
[ SCOFFS ]
CHERYL JAMES PARKER,
MY WIFE OF 22 YEARS.
ON TUESDAY, HE WRITES,
"SAW LACEY AT THE POOL."
YOU WERE AT THE POOL
ON TUESDAY?
YEAH. IT'S FREE ON TUESDAYS.
I-I ALWAYS GO.
ANYBODY FLIRT WITH YOU?
[ GASPS ]
THERE'S THIS HOT LIFEGUARD --
RICK MATTHEOH.
HE'S ALWAYS FLIRTING.
I HAVE A PICTURE OF --
OF HIM.
HMM.
MOM!
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY MIRROR?
IT BROKE
DURING THE NIGHT.
I CLEANED IT UP
WHILE YOU WERE ASLEEP.
THE PICTURES
ARE ALL IN THE TOP DRAWER.
THAT'S ME
AND CINDY AND RICK.
HE SAYS HE'S GONNA GO TO L.A.
TO BECOME A ROCK STAR.
YEAH. I REMEMBER
LACEY PENDERHALT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
AND WHERE WERE YOU
THE LAST TWO WEEKENDS?
PLAYING
THE UPPER PENINSULA.
WE'RE THE HOTTEST
MOTLEY CRUE TRIBUTE BAND...
WEST OF CLEVELAND.
THURSDAY, "I SAW LACEY
AT WORK YESTERDAY.
"SHE'S SO DISTRACTING!
BUT THERE'S NOBODY
I'D RATHER BE DISTRACTED BY."
WORK?
OH, THAT COULD BE
EDDIE RUSSELL.
HE'S A JUNIOR PARTNER
AT THE LAW OFFICE
WHERE I DO FILINGS
ON MONDAY AND WEDNESDAY.
DID HE TALK TO YOU?
OH, HE'S ALWAYS
TALKING TO ME.
AND EVERY TIME HE DOES, I FEEL
LIKE I NEED TO TAKE A BATH.
HMM.
APPARENTLY, HE HAD
TOO MANY EGGNOG
AT THE OFFICE
CHRISTMAS PARTY,
AND HE WAS CHASING HIS ASSISTANT
DOWN THE FIRE STAIRS
WHEN HE LOST HIS BALANCE.
BEEN IN A BED
FOR SIX YEARS NOW.
SEEMS THERE IS JUSTICE
IN THE UNIVERSE AFTER ALL.
WELL, THANK YOU.
I'M VERY SORRY TO --
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
EXCUSE ME.
I NEED TO TAKE THIS.
MORETTI.
UNH-UNH.'RE OFF THE CASE?
JUST OFF LACEY.
HE WANTS ME RUNNING DOWN LEADS
WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN A BAR?
THEY'VE ALREADY CHECKED
AND DOUBLE-CHECKED THOSE LEADS.
AND I DID NOT GRADUATE
THIRD IN MY CLASS FROM QUANTICO
TO BE A TRIPLE-CHECKER.
WILL YOU LEAVE THOSE ALONE?
THEY'RE OLDER THAN YOU ARE.
SO, WHAT, YOU WANT ME
TO GO DOWN THERE
AND TELL YOUR BOSS
HE'S WASTING TALENT?
NO.
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW
IS IF THERE'S ANYTHING ELSE
YOU CAN REMEMBER FROM '86
THAT MIGHT HELP US.
BABE, I'VE DONE
THE FULL DOWNLOAD.
BUT I DO HAVE A QUESTION.
YOU ALWAYS TELL
YOUR OLD MAN THE TRUTH?
I DON'T SEE WHAT THAT
HAS TO DO WITH ANYTHING.
WELL,
JUST THINK ABOUT IT.
IN HER OWN HEAD,
LACEY IS 17.
SHE TELLS HER MOTHER
SHE'S GOING TO THE MOVIE, ALONE,
ON A FRIDAY NIGHT.
SO?
COME ON, KATIE.
YOU THINK I FORGOT
THAT CERTAIN NIGHT IN 1997
WHEN A CERTAIN 17-YEAR-OLD
TOLD HER DAD
THAT SHE WAS GOING TO THE MALL
WITH MARSHA FORD?
HER DAD BUMPS INTO HER
ON NAVY PIER
IN THE COMPANY OF A BUM
WITH A RING IN HIS NOSE.
HE WAS NOT A BUM.
HE WAS A PHILOSOPHY MAJOR
AT NORTHWESTERN.
THE POINT IS,
DAUGHTERS DON'T ALWAYS TELL
THEIR PARENTS THE TRUTH.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
IS HE HERE?
YOU REALLY
SHOULD CALL FIRST.
YES.
NEXT TIME, I PROMISE.
LOOK, WHAT YOU'RE DOING
IS NOT GOOD FOR HIM.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
LIKE, HIS CONDITION?
BECAUSE I KNOW
ABOUT HIS CONDITION.
IS HE HAVING
SOME SORT OF A --
NO, NO, NO. HE'S FINE.
BUT HE'S AGITATED, OKAY?
HE MISSED OFFICE HOURS.
HE HASN'T GOTTEN ANY WORK DONE.
HE'S OBSESSING ON THE CASE.
IF YOU KEEP DISRUPTING
HIS ROUTINE,
WHO KNOWS
WHAT COULD HAPPEN?
LISTEN, I'M SORRY,
BUT I WOULDN'T BE HERE
IF IT WEREN'T
EXTREMELY URGENT
THAT I BRING HIM
TO LACEY'S HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
WHAT ARE YOU TWO
WHISPERING ABOUT?
[ KNOLACEY...OR ]
HONEY, THIS IS DR. PIERCE
AND AGENT MORETTI OF THE FBI.
THE FBI?
WHY?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
UH, LACEY,
I'M SURE YOU'VE HEARD
ABOUT THE DATE NIGHT KILLER
ON THE NEWS.
OH, MY GOD.
DID SOMEBODY I KNOW
GET KILLED?
NO, BUT WE HAVE REASON
TO BELIEVE
THAT THE KILLER
IS SOMEBODY YOU KNOW.
WHAT?
MRS. PENDERHALT, CAN I TROUBLE
YOU FOR A CUP OF COFFEE?
IT'S NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
HONEY, I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
LACEY, UM, WE KNOW
THAT YOU TOLD YOUR MOTHER
THAT YOU WERE GONNA BE GOING
TO THE MOVIES TONIGHT, ALONE.
"FERRIS BUELLER."
WE KNOW YOU'RE NOT
TELLING US THE TYEAH.
WHY WOULD I LIE?
LACEY,
I WAS 17 MYSELF ONCE,
AND I KNOW HOW GROWN-UPS
CAN FREAK OUT
AND OVERREACT
ABOUT NOTHING.
I MEAN, MY DAD ONCE GROUNDED ME
FOR JUST SAYING
THAT I THOUGHT KEITH RICHARDS
LOOKED COOL WITH A CIGARETTE.
SO I KNOW WHY
YOU MIGHT FEEL
LIKE YOU HAVE TO
MAKE THINGS UP SOMETIMES.
BUT PLEASE, THINK ABOUT ALL
THOSE GIRLS WHO WERE KILLED.
THINK ABOUT THE GIRLS
WHO STILL MIGHT DIE.
YOU CAN HELP US
SAVE THEM.
I WAS GOING TO
GO MEET A GUY.
I DIDN'T TELL MY MOM
BECAUSE SHE WOULD KILL ME.
UH-HUH.
HE'S 24.
WHO IS HE?
HE'S A PHOTOGRAPHER.
HE SAW ME IN THE PARK
AND ASKED TO TAKE MY PICTURE,
AND I SAID YES.
THAT'S ALL HE DID --
TAKE YOUR PICTURE?
HE KISSED ME.
BUT HE NEVER ASKED ME
TO TAKE OFF MY CLOTHES
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT,
I SWEAR.
MM-HMM.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
KENNY STRAND.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING ]
RELAX!
COME ON. HAVE FUN.
WE'RE SELLING
PERFUME HERE,
NOT REMAKING
"NIGHT OF THE LIVING DEAD."
Kate: KENNY?
CAN'T YOU SEE
THAT I'M...
SORRY. I THOUGHT
YOU WERE MY IDIOT ASSISTANT.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
ARE YOU THE KENNY STRAND
WHO TOOK PICTURES OF GIRLS
IN OAK PARK
IN THE SUMMER OF 1986?
THAT'S ME, IN THE LONG-GONE DAYS
BEFORE I SOLD MY SOUL.
EVER DONE ANY MODELING?
ACTUALLY, I'M IN A DIFFERENT
LINE OF WORK.
AND I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS
TO ASK YOU.
I ALWAYS WONDERED
WHAT HAPPENED TO LACEY.
ONE NIGHT, SHE DIDN'T
SHOW UP FOR THE SHOOT.
NEVER HEARD FROM HER
AGAIN.
HMM. BUT YOU DID
TAKE HER PICTURE?
SHE'S ALL OVER
MY FIRST BOOK.
WHEN YOU MADE OUT WITH HER,
WERE YOU AWARE
THAT SHE WAS UNDER 18?
[ CHUCKLES ]
UH, IT WAS
AN INNOCENT KISS.
I WAS, UH,
GETTING HER MORE COMFORTABLE,
GETTING HER TO LOOSEN UP
IN FRONT OF THE CAMERA.
YEAH,
I'M SURE YOU WANTED
ALL THE GIRLS YOU PHOTOGRAPHED
LOOSENED UP.
IT WAS NOTHING LIKE THAT.
LOOK AT THE PICTURES.
I WAS CELEBRATING THEIR YOUTH,
THEIR INNOCENCE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I'M NOT SEEING ANYTHING
FETISHIZED OR EROTICIZED HERE.
[ CELLEXCUSE ME.ING ]
[ BEEP ]
CUT ANSEL ADAMS LOOSE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT?
ANOTHER WOMAN WAS JUST ABDUCTED
IN BEDFORD PARK.
So much for your nutjob expert
and your brain-damaged witness.
GUY SAID HIS GIRLFRIEND LEFT THE
CLUB AROUND 9:20 FOR A SMOKE.
HALF-HOUR LATER,
HE GOES LOOKING.
GIRLFRIEND'S GONE.
BOUNCER SAYS AROUND 9:25,
HE SAW A GUY AROUND 50,
WHITE, MEDIUM HEIGHT,
PRACTICALLY CARRY
SOME DRUNK-OFF-HER-[BLEEP] GIRL
TO HIS CAR.
CHLOROFORM.
BOUNCER ASKS THE GUY
IF HE NEEDS A HAND.
GUY SAYS HE'S GLAD
HIS LITTLE GIRL
HAS THE SENSE
TO CALL HER DADDY
WHEN SHE'S TOO DRUNK
TO DRIVE HERSELF HOME.
GIRL'S NAME
[ EIS MELINDA DAVIS.S ]
Kate: IF WE DON'T FIND HER
IN THE NEXT 24 HOURS,
WE'RE DEFINITELY GONNA
FIND HER ON SUNDAY MORNING.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
DANIEL, WHAT'S WRONG?
NOTHING.
BOSS WANTS US TO CANVASS
THE AREA FOR WITNESSES
AND CHECK SECURITY CAMS
WITHIN A FIVE-MILE RADIUS
FOR MEDIUM-SIZED,
MAYBE BLUE, MAYBE HONDAS.
ALL RIGHT. WELL, I NEED TO FIND
SOMEONE TO BRING YOU HOME.
OTHERWISE, LEWICKI'S GONNA
COME AFTER ME WITH AN AX.
YEAH.
LET'S TAKE THE STAIRS.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
Natalie:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU MEAN BESIDES
GETTING RUN OVER
BY IMAGINARY,
HOMICIDAL BICYCLES?
BETTER
THAN A REAL ONE.
YEAH. HMM.
NICE SHIRT.
OH. YEAH.
NOW THAT I'VE DUG IT
OUT AGAIN,
I DON'T REALLY WANT TO
TAKE IT OFF.
THAT WAS A GREAT NIGHT,
WASN'T IT?
WHICH NIGHT?
THE NIGHT WE SAW
TEARS FOR FEARS AT THE VIC.
WE DIDN'T GO
TO THAT CONCERT TOGETHER.
OF COURSE WE DID.
WE WERE DATING THEN.
WE WENT EVERYWHERE
TOGETHER.
DANIEL, I ASKED YOU
TO GO WITH ME,
AND YOU KEPT SAYING
THAT THE GOVERNMENT SCANNERS
IN PUBLIC PLACES
WERE MONITORING YOUR THOUGHTS.
I ENDED UP GOING
WITH JOSH LEWIS.
JOSH LEW-- NO, YOU --
NO, YOU'RE WRONG. YOU'RE WRONG.
WE WENT TO TEARS FOR FEARS
TOGETHER.
DON'T GIVE ME THAT LOOK.
I CAN -- HEY, I CAN PROVE IT.
♪ SHOUT, SHOUT ♪
♪ LET IT ALL OUT ♪
♪ THESE HERE THEY ARE. S... ♪
TWO STUBS, TEARS FOR FEARS,
AUGUST 10, 1986 --
26 YEARS AGO LAST MONTH.
♪ I'M TALKING TO YOU ♪
♪ COME ON ♪
DANIEL...
THOSE AREN'T STUBS.
THEY'RE WHOLE TICKETS.
YOU BOUGHT THEM, BUT YOU
NEVER WENT TO THE CONCERT.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
W-W-WE PUSHED OUR WAY
TO THE FRONT.
WE ALMOST GOT TRAMPLED TO DEATH
ON THE DANCE FLOOR.
I-I-I GOT A T-SHIRT!
YOU BOUGHT THAT SHIRT
AT HEGWISCH RECORDS.
WHAT?
YOU TOLD KATE THAT YOU DIDN'T
REMEMBER THE DATE NIGHT KILLER
BECAUSE YOU HAD
YOUR HEAD IN THE BOOKS.
♪ YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO SELL
YOUR SOUL ♪
BUT I WAS IN MY BOOKS.
YES, BUT THAT WAS ALSO THE
SUMMER THAT YOU STARTED TO...
BREAK.
SO I IMAGINED
THE WHOLE THING?
I PUT MYSELF
IN JOSH LEWIS' PLACE?
YOU CONFUSED DESIRE
WITH REALITY.
JUST LIKE THE KILLER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
HE WROTE IN HIS JOURNAL
THAT HE --
HE DANCED
WITH HIS VICTIMS,
HE BOUGHT THEM COCKTAILS,
HE SWAM IN THE LAKE WITH THEM.
BUT HE NEVER REALLY DID.
HIS ENTIRE CONNECTION TO THESE
WOMEN IS ALL IN HIS HEAD.
H-H-HE'S A DELUSIONAL
EROTOMANIAC!
THAT'S WHY --
WHY THE LEADS IN THE JOURNAL
DON'T LEAD ANYWHERE.
YES, THE WOMEN DANCED
AND DRANK
A-AND SWAM IN THE LAKE!
BUT NOT WITH THE KILLER.
HE WROTE THAT HE SAW LACEY
EVERYWHERE THAT SUMMER.
BUT THAT'S JUST BECAUSE
HE WAS FOLLOWING HER AROUND!
WHICH MEANS...
THE BICYCLES.
LET ME SEE
THAT BOOK AGAIN,
THE -- THE ONE
WITH THE PHOTOGRAPHS.
I'LL CALL YOU BACK.
DANIEL, KENNY'S ALIBI
CHECKED OUT.
GIVE ME THE BOOK.ER.
YEAH. LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A BICYCLE.
UH-HUH.
AND THERE.
ANOTHER BICYCLE.
DID YOU NOTICE
ALL THIS BEFORE?
I -- YES.
[ STAMMERS ]
I DIDN'T NOTICE THAT I WAS
NOTICING UNTIL LATER.
LOOK AT THAT.
FIREWORKS.
EVERYBODY'S LOOKING
UP AT THE FIREWORKS,
EVERYONE IN THE WHOLE PARK. LOOK
AT THIS ONE GUY ON THE BIKE.
WHO'S HE LOOKING AT?
THAT'S ME AND THAT'S CINDY
AND THAT'S AILEEN.
MM-HMM.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE
THIS GUY HERE ON THE BIKE?
NO.
[ GASPS ]
BUT I KNOW WHERE HE WORKS.
SEE THAT "M"
ON HIS SHOULDER BAG?
THAT'S FOR
MERCURY MESSENGERS.
AT THE LAW OFFICE
WHERE I WORK,
THE BIKE BOYS ARE ALWAYS COMING
IN AND OUT, PICKING STUFF UP.
THANK YOU, LACEY.
YOU MAY HAVE JUST HELPED US
CATCH A KILLER.
Roger:
THERE WERE 33 MESSENGERS
WORKING FOR MERCURY IN 1986.
BUT THREE ARE DEAD,
TWO LIVING OUT OF THE COUNTRY,
SEVEN NONWHITE,
FOUR UNTRACEABLE, AND A WHOLE
BUNCH OF SOLID ALIBIS.
LEAVING
EIGHT POSSIBILITIES.
WE LIKE NUMBER 29,
SIMON KAYDEE.
HE'S THE RIGHT AGE
IN '86.
HE DRIVES A DARK-BLUE
NISSAN ALTIMA.
THE SUBJECT OF SEVERAL REPORTS
OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE.
HE LIVES IN STICKNEY.
IT'S PRACTICALLY FARMLAND
OUT THERE.
IT'S A GOOD PLACE TO TIE UP
A GIRL IN YOUR BASEMENT.
AND GET THIS --
JUST LAST NIGHT,
HE SWIPED HIS CREDIT CARD
AT A MALL
JUST TWO MILES FROM THE CLUB
WHERE THE GIRL WAS NABBED.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S MOVE ON KAYDEE.
WHOA, WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
LIKE [BLEEP] YOU ARE.
STAY HERE.
I'LL CALL YOU
AS SOON AS I CAN.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
Man: COME ON, DOC.
YOU'RE SMARTER
THAN THESE JOKERS.
YOU KNOW I'M NOT THE GUY.
YOU SAW MY BLUSHING BRIDE AND
THE DATE OF THE WEDDING, TOO --
SIX WEEKS AGO.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
IF A GUY'S GOT A PRETTY LITTLE
FILET MIGNON
LIKE THAT AT HOME,
WHY WOULD HE WANT TO GO OUT
AND SLAUGHTER HIMSELF A
HAMBURGER EVERY SATURDAY NIGHT?
LOOK HARDER, DOC.
IT'S ALL RIGHT THERE.
EVERYTHING
YOU NEED TO KNOW.
[ KNOCK ON GLASS ]
CALL AGENT MORETTI!
I NEED TO TALK TO HER!
DANIEL, SLOW DOWN.
I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
I'm saying you need to forget
about number 29.
NUMBER 17 I-IS YOUR MAN --
KEITH TREVOY OF BERWYN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
The question
we couldn't answer --
WHY DID HE START
KILLING AGAIN?
I-IT'S ALL ABOUT THE ITCH
HE NEEDED TO SCRATCH.
W-W-What was he looking for?
The one.
The -- The girl he could love
who would love him back.
NUMBER 17 -- HE GOT MARRIED
SEPTEMBER 27, 1986 --
8 WEEKS
AFTER THE KILLINGS STOPPED.
B-BUT HIS WIFE DIED
FOUR WEEKS AGO --
just before
the recent murders.
Y-YOU'VE GOT TO GET
TO BERWYN!
WE HAVE ORDERS
TO SHOW UP IN STICKNEY.
THERE ARE THREE DOZEN AGENTS
ON THEIR WAY TO STICKNEY.
THEY CAN SPARE A COUPLE.
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
Keith: I KNOW HOW MUCH
YOU LOVE PINOT NOIR.
IT'S SO WONDERFUL THAT...
WE LIKE THE SAME THINGS,
ISN'T IT?
Call for backup.
NO MORE SCREAMING, OKAY?
HELP ME!
WE'RE GOING IN.
I'LL COVER THE FRONT.
YEAH.
[ SOBBING ]
[ CLATTER ]
[ GROANS ]
AAH!
[ GUN COCKS ]
[ GASPS, WHIMPERS ]
[ SOBS ]
PUT DOWN THE KNIFE.
IT'S OVER, KEITH.
CPD AND THE FBI
HAVE THIS PLACE SURROUNDED.
THEN I MIGHT
AS WELL KILL HER.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT.
SHE'S THE ONE.
SHE'S NOT GONNA LET YOU DOWN
LIKE THE OTHERS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
WE READ HER DIARY.
WE FOUND IT IN HER HOUSE.
SHE SAID
THAT SHE LOVES YOU.
SHE DIDN'T REALIZE IT
AT FIRST,
BUT NOW SHE KNOWS THAT YOU'RE
WHAT SHE'S ALWAYS WANTED.
GO ON, MELINDA.
TELL HIM.
TELL HIM HOW YOU FEEL.
IT'S TRUE.
I LOVE YOU...
MORE THAN ANYONE
I'VE EVER MET.
THEN WHY DIDN'T YOU
SAY SO?
[ GASPS ]
BECAUSE...
YOU SCARED ME.
BUT I LOVE YOU.
LIAR!
[ GROANS ]
[ SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE ]
MY KID, THE HERO!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHAT? I CAN'T BRAG ABOUT
MY DAUGHTER IN MY OWN BAR?!
[ LAUGHS ]
IT'S NOT LIKE
I DIDN'T HAVE HELP.
AH, BUT YOU KNEW WHERE TO GO
FOR HELP, WHICH IS...
THE WHOLE KEY TO LIFE.
[ LAUGHS ]
COME ON, KATIE. WHAT? WHAT?
YOU SHOULD BE CELEBRATING.
POUR US A COUPLE
OF SCOTCHES, DAD.
WHAT'S UP?
REMEMBER WHAT YOU, UH,
WERE SAYING
ABOUT KIDS SOMETIMES
LYING TO THEIR PARENTS?
I GOT SOMETHING
TO TELL YOU.
IT'S ABOUT DONNIE.
I KNEW IT.
HEY, LACEY, HONEY,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
A FRIEND OF MINE.
THIS IS
DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
DOCTOR?
IS SOMEBODY SICK?
OH, NO.
NO, NOTHING LIKE THAT.
UM, YOUR MOTHER TELLS ME
THAT YOU LIKE TEARS FOR FEARS,
AND, UM, WELL,
I JUST HAPPEN TO HAVE
TWO TICKETS TO SEE THEM
AT THE VIC
THAT I CAN'T USE.
WOULD YOU LIKE THEM?
OH, MY GOD!
ARE YOU SERIOUS?!
THEY'RE ALL YOURS.
[ GASPS ] THANK YOU!
I LOVE YOU!
[ LAUGHS ]
OH, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
HMM.
YOUR DAUGHTER SAVED LIVES.
I HOPE YOU KNOW THAT.
YES, BUT SHE'S NEVER
GONNA KNOW THAT.
AND SHE'S NEVER GOING
TO GO TO THAT CONCERT.
NO.
BUT EVERY DAY,
YOU CAN GIVE HER THOSE TICKETS.
AND EVERY DAY, SHE'LL BE
JUST AS EXCITED TO GET THEM.
THANK YOU, DR. PIERCE.
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING
MY DAUGHTER BACK TO ME.
ANTEROGRADE AMNESIA
IS A TERRIBLE AFFLICTION.
BUT IF YOU'LL FORGIVE THIS
STODGY, OLD SCIENCE PROFESSOR
A MOMENT OF PHILOSOPHICAL
SPECULATION,
IT'S AN AFFLICTION
THAT CAN REMIND US
OF SOMETHING VERY IMPORTANT.
ALL WE REALLY HAVE
IS THE PRESENT MOMENT...
HE'LL BE FINISHED
IN A MINUTE.
ACTUALLY, I, UH -- I CAME
TO TALK TO YOU, NOT HIM.
UH, ME?
YEAH, LOOK, I JUST
WANTED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR BURSTING IN
THE WAY I DO ALL THE TIME.
ACTUALLY, I'M THE ONE
WHO SHOULD BE APOLOGIZING.
WHY?
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU SEE, A BIG PART OF MY JOB
IS FINDING PUZZLES HARD ENOUGH
TO TAKE HIM OUT OF HIS OWN HEAD
FOR A WHILE.
AND...THIS WEEK,
I REALIZED SOMETHING.
YOU BRING HIM PUZZLES,
TOO.
SO IF I WERE YOU, I WOULD
TRULY SAVOR THE HERE AND NOW,
THAT PRECIOUS AND IRREPLACEABLE
RIGHT-THIS-SECOND
THAT IS NEVER TO BE REPEATED
AGAIN IN ALL OF HISTORY --
QUIET MOMENT,
A BEAUTIFUL CAMPUS,
YOUR FRIENDS
ON EITHER SIDE OF YOU,
THE SUN STREAMING IN
THROUGH THE WINDOW.
SAVOR THIS WHILE YOU CAN...
BECAUSE FOR THE REST
OF THE WEEK,
YOU'RE ALL GONNA BE
BUSTING YOUR [BLEEP]
ON A 12-PAGE PAPER
ON TIME AND MEMORY...
...DUE 8:30 MONDAY MORNING.
NO EXTENSIONS, NO EXCUSES.
[ GROANING CONTINUES ]
"OH, PROFESSOR PIERCE!"
COME ON, YOU GUYS.
THIS IS THE FUN PART.