HMM.
CHECK OUT THIS LETTER
TO THE EDITOR.
APPARENTLY,
YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY GUY
WHO THINKS BIG MEDIA
AND BIG BUSINESS
ARE CRUSHING THE HUMANITY
OUT OF HUMANITY.
I'M GONNA CRUSH THE HUMANITY
OUT OF YOU
IF YOUNO, SERIOUSLY.LKING.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU
ON ONE OF YOUR RANTS.
LISTEN TO THIS.
"WHEN YOU DEVOTE
NOT EVEN A SINGLE PAGE
"TO ANYTHING OTHER
THAN YOUR SLAVISHLY FAWNING
"SO-CALLED 'NEWS,'
"PANDERING TO CORPORATE
ADVERTISERS,
"YOU DESTROY ALL HOPE
OF TOMORROW
FOR HONEST,
HARDWORKING AMERICANS."
"WOW!
HOW INTRIGUING, MAX.
"THANK YOU
FOR SHARING SOMETHING
"YOU THOUGHT
WOULD INTEREST ME.
"OH, AND THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR THE PAPAYA.
IT'S DELICIOUS."
ACTUALLY,
IT COULD USE A LITTLE LIME.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
GET IT YOURSELF.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
YOU HEARD ME.
AND AS OF RIGHT NOW,
YOUR ASSISTANT
IS OFFICIALLY ON STRIKE.
IF THIS IS ABOUT A RAISE,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO CONSIDER
A SLIGHTLY LESS
MELODRAMATIC APPROACH.
IT'S NOT ABOUT
THE MONEY, DOC.
IT'S ABOUT
THE WORKING CONDITIONS.
OKAY, IT'S ABOUT YOU SHOWING ME
A LITTLE COMMON COURTESY.
WHAT ARE YOU -- LEWICKI!
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
I'LL READ THE [BLEEP] LETTER.
[ SIGHS ]
[ TAPPING ]
WHO ARE YOU?
[ British accent ]
OH, UH, I'M AFRAID
MY IDENTITY IS CLASSIFIED,
OLD BOY.
YOU'RE A HALLUCINATION.
WHOSE ASSISTANCE
YOU'LL REQUIRE
IF YOU HAVE ANY HOPE
OF CRACKING THAT CODE.
WHAT CODE?
COME NOW, OLD BOY.
SURELY YOU NOTICED
THE AWKWARD SYNTAX.
"SLAVISHLY FAWNING
SO-CALLED NEWS"?
CLEARLY THE WORDS
HAVE BEEN TWISTED
AROUND SOME SORT OF
HIDDEN MESSAGE.
THERE'S MY BOY.
Daniel:
IT'S STEGANOGRAPHY.
HIDDEN WRITING.
LOOK.
IF YOU READ EVERY 10th WORD,
LOOK WHAT YOU GET.
"YOU'LL BE PROUD OF ME.
"FRONT-PAGE NEWS TOMORROW.
ONE DOWN, FOUR TO GO.
THE BUTCHER TOLD ME
WHERE TO START."
IT'S HOW THE FRENCH
RESISTANCE COMMUNICATED
WITH BRITISH INTELLIGENCE
DURING WORLD WAR II --
WITH MESSAGES
IN THE NEWSPAPER,
RIGHT WHERE ANYBODY
COULD SEE.
FRENCH RESISTANCE?
WOW.
MEANWHILE,
BACK ON THE PLANE OF REALITY,
SOME OF US
HAVE WORK TO DO.
THINK ABOUT IT, KATE.
WHAT ENDS UP
ON THE FRONT PAGE?
WORLD NOR CRIME.TICS...
I'M GUESSING
WHOEVER WROTE THIS
IS SENDING A MESSAGE
TO AN ACCOMPLICE.
"ONE DOWN, FOUR TO GO" --
THAT COULD BE BANKS TO ROB
OR VICTIMS TO BUTCHER.
DO YOU THINK
THAT THIS MIGHT BE YOU...
MAKING CONNECTIONS WHERE
POSSIBLY THERE AREN'T ANY?
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF EVERY 10th WORD
IN SOME RANDOM PIECE OF TEXT
MAKING THIS MUCH SENSE?
OR IT COULD BE SOMETHING
COMPLETELY INNOCENT.
THEN WHY HIDE IT
IN A CODE?
LOOK AT THE GUY'S NAME --
JAMES SMITH.
IT'S GOT TO BE THE MOST COMMON
NAME IN AMERICA.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY AN ALIAS.
AND WHY USE AN ALIAS UNLESS
YOU'RE DOING SOMETHING ILLICIT?
ALL RIGHT, LOOK, THE LETTER
PROBABLY CAME IN VIA E-MAIL.
THERE MIGHT BE SOME WAY
TO TRACE THE I.P.,
BUT IT COULD BE FROM
AN INTERNET CAFé IN SINGAPORE.
Probert: YOU'RE ACTUALLY
TAKING THIS SERIOUSLY?
I WANT TO BE THERE
WHEN YOU TELL THE BOSS
THAT WE'RE TAKING ON A CASE
THAT DR. STRANGE FOUND
WITH HIS SECRET DECODER RING.
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
MORETTI.
WHAT?
OKAY,
WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
THAT WAS THE CPD.
THEY NEED OUR HELP WITH
A POSSIBLE TERRORIST ATTACK.
A LAWYER DOWNTOWN
OPENED UP A PACKAGE
AND GOT SPRAYED IN THE FACE
WITH SARIN.
DIED BEFORE PARAMEDICS
GOT THERE.
OF COURSE, A LAWYER,
BECAUSE THE BUTCHER TOLD HIM
WHERE TO START.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
IT'S SHAKESPEARE --
"HENRY VI, PART 2."
DICK THE BUTCHER SAYS,
"FIRST THING WE DO,
LET'S KILL
ALL THE LAWYERS."
A SARIN ATTACK.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE
FRONT-PAGE NEWS TO ME.
Maya: [ Voice breaking ]
NORMALLY, I OPEN
MR. SCANTLIN'S MAIL
MYSELF,
BUT THERE WAS A BOX
MARKED "PERSONAL."
HE THOUGHT SOMEONE
SENT HIM A PRESENT,
SO HE OPENED IT HIMSELF.
AND THERE WAS A POP,
LIKE A FIRECRACKER,
AND SOME KIND OF SPRAY
CAME OUT.
AND HE STARTED TWITCHING.
I TRIED TO HELP HIM.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU COULD
HAVE DONE, MISS BENOWITZ.
SARIN IS MORE TOXIC
THAN CYANIDE.
Kate:
CAN YOU THINK OF ANYBODY
WHO MIGHT HAVE HAD A REASON
TO DO THIS?
TOM WAS A MENSCH.
EVERYBODY LOVED HIM.
BUT HE WAS A TRIAL LAWYER.
HE WON A LOT OF CASES.
I MEAN, THE --
THE LOSERS WEREN'T HAPPY.
THERE IS NOTHING
ON THE PACKAGE --
NO PRINTS,
NO RETURN ADDRESS.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, WE'LL TALK
TO HIS FRIENDS, RELATIVES,
ACQUAINTANCES,
BUT I THINK WE SHOULD START
WITH HIS CASE FILES.
FARRINGTON
v. AWAKAMA SUSHI.
SCANTLIN GOT AWAKAMA
FOR 7 MIL
FOR A SINGLE CASE
OF E. COLI.
HERE'S SOMETHING.
MILLER v. KLAUSNER
EXTERMINATION.
KLAUSNER WAS ORDERED TO PAY
$70,000 IN MEDICAL EXPENSES,
$1.4 MILLION PUNITIVE.
THIS COULD BE OUR GUY.
WHY HIM
OUT OF ALL THESE CASES?
SARIN'S A NERVE AGENT,
BUT IT WAS ORIGINALLY DEVELOPED
AS A PESTICIDE.
AN EXTERMINATOR WOULD HAVE
EVERYTHING HE NEEDED
TO MIX UP A BATCH,
RIGHT ON THE SHELF.
Klausner: YEAH.
I HATE TOM SCANTLIN.
I BUILT MY BUSINESS
FROM NOTHING.
32 TRUCKS, 58 EMPLOYEES,
CONTRACTS WITH EVERY SCHOOL
DISTRICT IN THE COUNTY.
NOT BAD FOR A GUY WHO NEVER
GOT PAST EIGHTH GRADE, HUH?
AND THAT S.O.B.
TOOK IT ALL AWAY.
ACTUALLY,
IT WAS A JURY OF YOUR PEERS
WHO DECIDED AGAINST YOU.
THEY DECIDED WRONG.
LBJ ELEMENTARY HAD ROACHES
THE SIZE OF CHIPMUNKS.
SO MY GUYS SPRAYED
WITH A VERY RELIABLE PESTICIDE
I IMPORTED FROM MEXICO.
WHICH YOU HAD TO DO
BECAUSE IT WASN'T YET APPROVED
HERE IN THE U.S.
THEY USE THAT STUFF LIKE KETCHUP
ON FRIES SOUTH OF THE BORDER,
AND NO ONE'S COMPLAINING.
SOMEONE NORTH OF THE BORDER
SURE COMPLAINED.
ONE KID CRIES SICK,
AND HIS PARENTS
GET A FAST-TALKING LAWYER
WHO SUES THE CRAP
OUT OF ME.
ON THE NEWS,
HE MADE IT SOUND
LIKE I DELIBERATELY SET OUT
TO POISON SCHOOLCHILDREN.
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY THAT
YOU SHOULD MENTION THE NEWS,
BECAUSE THERE WAS
A LETTER TO THE EDITOR
IN TODAY'S PAPER
ABOUT HOW THE MEDIA IS STACKED
AGAINST THE LITTLE GUY.
YOU MIGHT
FIND IT INTERESTING.
GO AHEAD. READ IT.
SORRY, I DON'T HAVE
MY READING GLASSES.
MAYBE YOU DON'T NEED
TO READ IT
BECAUSE YOU ALREADY KNOW WHAT
IT SAYS BECAUSE YOU WROTE IT.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I DON'T WRITE LETTERS
TO THE PAPERS.
LISTEN, JUST BECAUSE
I HATED SCANTLIN
DOESN'T MEAN
THAT I KILLED HIM.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT.
I JUST -- I WANTED TO OFFER
MR. KLAUSNER MY READING GLASSES.
YEAH, UH, I PROBABLY GOT
A DIFFERENT PRESCRIPTION.
ALL RIGHT. I THINK
I UNDERSTAND WHAT'S GOING ON.
DO -- DO YOU HAVE DYSLEXIA,
MR. KLAUSNER?
HOW DID YOU --
IT WOULD HELP EXPLAIN
WHY A MAN AS SMART AS YOU
DIDN'T MAKE IT
PAST EIGHTH GRADE,
AND WHY YOU DON'T
WANT TO READ THE LETTER.
IT'S NOTHING
TO BE ASHAMED OF.
IT JUST MEANS
YOU'RE NOT OUR MAN.
Probert:
JUST BECAUSE HE'S DYSLEXIC
DOESN'T MEAN HE'S INNOCENT.
PROBERT, FOR HIM, WORDS AND
LETTERS SWIM AROUND THE PAGE.
SO, SADLY, HE AVOIDS READING
AND WRITING ALTOGETHER.
IT'S NOT LIKE HE SUDDENLY
WOKE UP ONE MORNING
AND DECIDED TO START
COMMUNICATING
BY CONSTRUCTING
ELABORATE CODES
BURIED INSIDE
LETTERS TO THE EDITOR.
SO IT'S BACK TO THE
NEEDLE-IN-A-HAYSTACK STRATEGY.
ACTUALLY,
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
THERE MAY BE A WAY TO GET
THE NEEDLE TO COME TO US.
IN HIS CODE, THE KILLER SAYS,
"YOU'LL BE PROUD OF ME."
HE'S LOOKING
FOR APPROVAL.
IF I WRITE HIM BACK,
TELL HIM WHAT A GREAT JOB
I THINK HE'S DOING,
MAYBE HE'LL TALK TO ME.
YOU PLAN ON MAKING FRIENDS
WITH THIS LUNATIC?
WE'RE PEAS IN A POD.
Kate:
"YOU THINK YOU HAVE GUTS,
BUT ALL I HEAR IS WHINING
AND SELF-PITY."
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO DO,
GET HIM TO SARIN-GAS
THE WHOLE CITY?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A FAN LETTER.
HAVE YOU CONSIDERED REQUESTING
A NEW PARTNER?
YOU'RE JUST TRYING TO GET
HIS ATTEXACTLY.RIGHT?
IF HE'S AS SMART
AS I THINK HE IS,
HE'LL SEE
THE HIDDEN MESSAGE.
EVERY 10 WORDS,
YOU SAID?
Daniel: "GREAT MOVE.
"I WISH I HAD YOUR GUTS.
"JUST ONE QUESTION --
"OUT OF ALL THE LYING, CHEATING
LAWYERS, WHY THAT ONE?
YOUR FRIEND,
KINDRED SPIRIT."
"KINDRED SPIRIT."
I LIKE THAT.
WE SHOULD RUSH A COPY OF THIS
TO THE PAPER
SO THEY CAN GET IT
IN TOMORROW'S EDITION.
MAYBE WE COULD
BRING IT OVER THERE
IN A HORSE AND BUGGY.
IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO BE FUNNY?
LISTEN, PAPERS
HAVE ONLINE EDITIONS.
I'M JUST GONNA POST THIS
AS A COMMENT
TO THE ORIGINAL LETTER,
OKAY?
MAYBE HE'S NOT CHECKING
THE COMMENTS.
MAYBE HE DOESN'T EVEN
OWN A COMPUTER.
YOU KNOW,
MAYBE HE'S LIKE ME.
SOME PEOPLE STILL LIKE THE FEEL
OF A NEWSPAPER IN THEIR HANDS.
WHAT ARE YOU, A LUDDITE?
THE LUDDITES
WERE ONTO SOMETHING.
STUDIES HAVE SHOWN THAT PEOPLE
WHO SPEND TOO MUCH TIME ONLINE
LOSE THE ABILITY TO IDENTIFY
SIMPLE EMOTIONS
EXPRESSED IN PHOTOGRAPHS
OF HUMAN FACES.
I MEAN, COMPUTERS MAY BE THE
GREATEST TECHNOLOGICAL ADVANCE
OF THE LAST 100 YEARS, BUT THIS
WHOLE INTERNET THING IS --
INVALUABLE IN MAKING
INSTANTANEOUS CONTACT
AT CRUCIAL TIMES?
HE ANSWERED?
WHAT DID HE SAY?
"HEY, KINDRED SPIRIT.
"GLAD TO KNOW
I'M NOT ALONE.
"YOU'LL GET
YOUR ANSWER TOMORROW
"WHEN THE NEXT [BLEEP]
GETS HIS MAIL.
"BUT IF YOU'RE AS SMART
AS I THINK YOU ARE,
YOU CAN BE THERE
WHEN IT HAPPENS."
WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS THAT?
IT'S ANOTHER CIPHER.
HE WANTS TO MAKE SURE I'M THE
ONLY ONE THAT GETS THE MESSAGE.
CAN YOU DECIPHER IT?
Codebreaker:
THAT'S A NASTY ONE.
AND IT'S ONLY, WHAT?
SIX HOURS BEFORE
THE MORNING POST COMES 'ROUND.
NOT SURE IF WE CAN CRACK IT
IN TIME.
NO. NO. NO.
IT'S NOT A VIGENèRE SEQUENCE.
AND IT'S NOT A POLYALPHABETIC
SUBSTITUTION, EITHER.
WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS THAT?
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE
IF IT'S NOT WHAT IT IS?
TRACED THE I.P. ADDRESS THE GUY
USED TO SEND THE REPLY FROM.
CAME UP EMPTY.
CODEBREAKERS AT THE NSA
COME UP WITH ANYTHING?
NOTHING YET.
WELL, THEN
HE BETTER HURRY UP,
BECAUSE THE CHICAGO
POSTAL WORKERS
ARE ABOUT TO HAVE
THEIR MORNING COFFEE!
YEAH, DO YOU NOT THINK I'M
EXCRUCIATINGLY AWARE OF THAT?
I CAN'T --
DON'T -- I CAN'T --
I CAN'T DO THIS WITH EVERYBODY
HOVERING AROUND ME.
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
THOUGHT YOU COULD USE
A LITTLE BIT OF HELP.
YEAH,
YOU'VE BEEN A BIG HELP.
WHAT FUN IS THERE
PLAYING A GAME
IF THE OTHER FELLOW
HASN'T GOT A SPORTING CHANCE?
YOU'RE TALKING IN RIDDLES.
I HAVE ENOUGH OF THOSE.
I'M SIMPLY SAYING IT WOULDN'T
BE CRICKET FOR THIS FELLOW
TO WRITE A CODE
WITHOUT SENDING ALONG AT LEAST
A HINT OF HOW TO CRACK IT.
YOU THINK THE KILLER HID A KEY
WITHIN THE CODE ITSELF.
WELL, IF HE HAD,
HE'D LIKELY OPEN WITH IT...
WOULDN'T HE?
LOOK AT THE NUMBERS,
PIERCE.
LOOK VERY CLOSELY
AT THE NUMBERS.
WHAT IS THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN THE GROUPS OF FIGURES?
[ SIGHS ]
14, 41...
NO. 144. 12.
144 IS THE SQUARE OF 12.
225 IS THE SQUARE
OF 15.
SQUARES AND THEIR ROOTS.
WELL, THAT'S GOT
TO MEAN SOMETHING.
WHAT? WHAT?
S-SQUARE ROOTS.
SQUARES.
N-NOT "ROOT"
LIKE A POTATO.
A ROUTE --
LIKE A HIGHWAY!
IT'S A ROUTE CIPHER.
SQUARES AND THEIR ROOTS --
THE NUMBERS WERE THE TELL.
SQUARES AND THEIR ROOTS.
BUT THE THREE STOOD APART,
MEANING YOU BREAK
EACH STRING OF LETTERS
INTO THREE EQUAL ROWS.
THEN YOU JUST -- YOU JUST HAVE
TO FIGURE OUT THE ROUTE.
IT COULD BE
UP AND DOWN COLUMNS
OR IN A SPIRAL PATTERN --
DANIEL,
THIS IS FANTASTIC,
BUT CAN YOU JUST TELL ME
WHAT IT SAYS?
HERE.
"YOU'D BETTER HURRY.
"FIRST MONUMENT BANK
105 COUCH PLACE."
CALL FIRST MONUMENT BANK,
HAVE THEM CLEAR THE BUILDING
AND WARN THEIR EMPLOYEES
NOT TO OPEN UP ANY MAIL.
I'M GONNA GET
AN AMBULANCE OVER THERE.
TELL THEM TO BRING ATROPINE
AND PRALIDOXIME CHLORIDE
Probert:
WE'RE TOO LATE.RIN.
PRESIDENT OF
FIRST MONUMENT BANK
OPENED A PACKAGE
10 MINUTES AGO.
HE GOT BLASTED WITH SARIN.
HIS NAME'S RUSS ANDERSON.
HE'S ON HIS WAY
TO THE E.R.
IF I'D BEEN
10 MINUTES FASTER,
HE WOULD NOT BE LYING IN THERE
ON LIFE SUPPORT.
DANIEL,
THIS IS NOT YOUR FAULT.
OKAY, YOU DIDN'T
POISON THOSE MEN.
AND WE CAN STILL CATCH THE GUY
WHO DID THIS
BEFORE HE HITS
SOMEONE ELSE.
HAVE YOU GOTTEN AHOLD
OF MR. ANDERSON'S WIFE?
SHE'S ON A PLANE.
SHE'LL BE HERE IN AN HOUR.
I DON'T KNOW
IF HE'LL LAST THAT LONG.
CAN WE TALK TO HIM?
HE'S GONE INTO A COMA.
THAT DOESN'T
NECESSARILY MEAN
WE CAN'T TRY TO ASK HIM
SOME QUESTIONS.
MR. ANDERSON,
MY NAME IS DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
I'M SO SORRY
ABOUT WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN POISONED.
THE DOCTORS HERE ARE DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN TO HELP YOU.
YOUR WIFE IS FLYING IN
FROM COLORADO RIGHT NOW.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE NEED YOUR HELP
CATCHING WHOEVER IT IS
THAT TRIED TO KILL YOU.
I'M GONNA ASK YOU
A SERIES OF QUESTIONS.
WHEN YOU WANT
TO ANSWER "YES,"
THINK ABOUT
THROWING A BASEBALL.
AND FOR "NO," THINK ABOUT
SINGING "HAPPY BIRTHDAY."
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
THAT'S THE CEREBELLUM,
THE REGION OF THE BRAIN
RESPONSIBLE FOR HAND-EYE
COORDINATION.
HE'S THINKING
ABOUT THROWING A BASEBALL.
THIS IS EXTRAORDINARY.
SO HE'S SAYING "YES."
DO YOU KNOW
WHO ATTACKED YOU?
THAT'S THE MEDIAL
PRE-FRONTAL CORTEX.
WHERE WE STORE OUR MEMORIES
OF MUSIC.
HE'S THINKING ABOUT SINGING
"HAPPY BIRTHDAY."
SO HE'S SAYING "NO," HE DOESN'T
KNOW WHO ATTACKED HIM.
DO YOU KNOW A LAWYER
NAMED THOMAS SCANTLIN?
"YES."
DO YOU KNOW MR. SCANTLIN
IN A PERSONAL CAPACITY?
"NO."
IN A PROFESSIONAL
CAPACITY?
"YES."
MR. SCANTLIN
WAS ATTACKED YESTERDAY
THE SAME WAY YOU WERE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA WHY?
"YES."
MR. ANDERSON, I'M GONNA ASK YOU
TO SPELL OUT THAT REASON.
I'LL RUN THROUGH THE ALPHABET
LETTER BY LETTER,
AND WHEN I SAY A LETTER
THAT'S CORRECT,
I WANT YOU THINK ABOUT
THROWING THAT BASEBALL.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
OKAY. HERE WE GO.
"A"...
"D," "E"...
GOT IT.
"DA-FOE." "DAFOE."
I MEAN, IT COULD BE A LAST NAME.
IS THAT RIGHT, MR. ANDERSON?
IS DAFOE SOMEBODY THAT YOU --
[ RAPID BEEPING ]
CODE!
[ ELECTRIC SHOCK ]
[ CHARGING ]
CLEAR!
[ ELECTRIC SHOCK ]
HIS HEART'S STOPPED.
IT'S OVER.
TIME OF DEATH, 10:47 P.M.
MR. DAFOE,
THANK YOU FOR COMING IN.
OF COURSE. YEAH.
I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE
RUSS ANDERSON'S DEAD.
HE HAD CHILDREN.
TOM SCANTLIN, TOO.
YOU WERE FRIENDS?
MORE BUSINESS ACQUAINTANCES,
REALLY.
A LUNCH OR TWO A YEAR
AND SHARE A TABLE
AT A CHARITY EVENT,
THAT SORT OF THING.
WE ASKED MR. ANDERSON
IF HE HAD ANY IDEA
WHY HE AND MR. SCANTLIN
WERE TARGETED,
AND THE ONLY THING
HE COULD GIVE US
BEFORE HE DIED
WAS YOUR NAME.
MY NAME?
WAIT, YOU DON'T THINK I HAD
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THE K--
NO. NO. THE KILLER
SEEMS TO HAVE A GRIEVANCE
AGAINST POWERFUL MEN.
YOUR BEING THE C.E.O. OF A
GLOBAL AGRICULTURAL CONGLOMERATE
CERTAINLY PUTS YOU
IN THAT CLUB.
BUT THE KILLER'S
ALSO MADE IT CLEAR
THAT HE HAS THREE MORE VICTIMS
ON HIS LIST.
OH, MY GOD.
WHAT WE NEED
TO DO NOW IS
DETERMINE WHAT POSSIBLY
CONNECTS THE THREE OF YOU
SO WE CAN GET A BETTER IDEA
OF WHO THIS KILLER MIGHT BE.
WELL, CHICAGO'S ULTIMATELY
A SMALL TOWN.
WE'VE DONE SO MUCH BUSINESS
TOGETHER OVER THE YEARS.
DID ANY OF THAT BUSINESS
SCREW SOMEBODY SO BADLY
THAT THEY'D WANT TO SEE ALL
THREE OF YOU FAT CATS DEAD?
I-I'M SORRY,
WHO ARE YOU AGAIN?
SORRY.
THIS IS DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
HE'S A SPECIAL CONSULTANT
HELPING THE FBI WITH THIS CASE.
HE GETS A LITTLE PASSIONATE
SOMETIMES.
WHAT HE'S
TRYING TO ASK IS,
COULD ANY OF YOUR DEALINGS
WITH MR. SCANTLIN OR ANDERSON
HAVE POSSIBLY GIVEN ANYONE
MOTIVE FOR MURDER?
WELL, SCANTLIN'S FIRM
DREW UP THE I.P.O.
THAT WE DID LAST YEAR,
AND A DIVISION OF ANDERSON'S
BANK HANDLED THE OFFERING.
AND WHAT ABOUT THAT
WOULD HAVE SET SOMEONE OFF?
WE HAD TO LAY OFF
13 EXECUTIVES
AND ABOUT 250
LOW-LEVEL EMPLOYEES.
SURE, NOTHING LIKE A LITTLE
CORPORATE DOWNSIZING
TO PUMP UP
THE STOCK PRICE.
GETTING YOUR FISCAL HOUSE
IN ORDER
IS STANDARD BEFORE AN I.P.O.
CAN'T MAKE AN OMELETTE WITHOUT
BREAKING A FEW EGGS, RIGHT?
NO, YOU CAN'T.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
WE'RE GONNA NEED A LIST
OF THOSE 263 EMPLOYEES,
INCLUDING THE LOW-LEVEL ONES.
ANOTHER NEEDLE
IN ANOTHER HAYSTACK.
MEANWHILE, THE KILLER
COULD BE AT THE POST OFFICE,
DROPPING HIS NEXT DELIVERY
DOWN THE MAIL SLOT.
Daniel: I'LL SEND HIM
ANOTHER FAN LETTER.
MAYBE HE'LL SEND ME
ANOTHER CLUE.
MAYBE THIS TIME I'LL FIGURE
IT OUT FAST ENOUGH.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL LOG BACK
ONTO THE THREAD.
OKAY. UH, NO CODE THIS TIME --
JUST MESSAGE.
UH, "NOW I UNDERSTAND.
"YOU'RE DOWNSIZING
THE [BLEEP]
"THE SAME WAY
THEY DOWNSIZED YOU.
WHO'S NEXT?
YOURS, KINDRED."
OKAY. IT'S SENT.
NOW WE JUST GOT TO HOPE THAT
HE'S MONITORING THE THREAD.
I'M PRETTY SURE
HE'S MONITORING.
FOUR, THREE, TWO...
[ COMPUTER CHIMES ]
"YOU'RE NOT AS SMART
AS I THOUGHT YOU WERE.
"YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND ME
AT ALL.
I'M FINISHED WITH YOU.
GOODBYE."
DANIEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHY AREN'T YOU
HELPING KATE?
I-I COULDN'T -- I COULDN'T THINK
IN THAT PLACE.
YOU KNOW,
I-I HAD TO TALK TO YOU.
HOW CAN I HELP?
I THOUGHT I'D MADE A CONNECTION
TO THE KILLER.
YOU KNOW, BUT I-I MUST HAVE
GUESSED WRONG ABOUT HIS MOTIVE,
AND NOW --
NOW HE'S CUT ME OUT.
DID YOU TRY
CONTACTING HIM AGAIN?
NOT UNTIL
I HAVE A BETTER GUESS.
BUT IF HE'S NOT ANGRY ABOUT
BEING DOWNSIZED, WHAT IS IT?
YOU HEAR THOSE SIRENS?
IT SOUNDS LIKE
IT'S RIGHT NEXT DOOR.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
OH, SORRY. SORRY.
I WORK -- I WORK HERE.
KATE?
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
GOING ON?
LET ME KNOW
WHEN YOU GET IT.
OKAY, DANIEL, LISTEN.
IT WAS SARIN AGAIN.
IT WAS PACKED IN A CANISTER
LIKE THE OTHERS
WITH A CHARGE TO RELEASE THE GAS
WHEN THE PACKAGE WAS OPENED.
NOBODY.NED IT?
LOOKS LIKE IT WAS DROPPED
AND WENT OFF ACCIDENTALLY.
THE VICTIM
WAS KELLY OWENS.
SHE WAS WORKING PART-TIME
IN THE FACULTY MAIL ROOM.
OH, THAT POOR GIRL.
AND HER PARENTS.
WELL, OBVIOUSLY
SHE WASN'T THE TARGET.
WHO WAS THE PACKAGE
ADDRESSED TO?
MAILING LABEL WAS INCINERATED
IN THE EXPLOSION.
WE DON'T KNOW.
ACTUALLY,
I'M PRETTY SURE WE DO.
OUR MAD SCIENTIST HERE
MADE THE PAPER.
WHAT?
"ANONYMOUS SOURCES REPORT
THAT DR. DANIEL PIERCE OF CLMU
"HAS BEEN HELPING THE FBI
DECIPHER THE KILLER'S
CODED MESSAGES."
HE FOUND OUT HIS KINDRED
SPIRIT'S TALKING TO THE COPS.
"ANONYMOUS SOURCES."
WHAT, HAVE YOU BEEN BLABBING
TO THWHO, ME?
THERE'S DOZENS OF AGENTS
WORKING ON THIS CASE.
AND IF YOU THINK THAT I WOULD
JEOPARDIZE MY CAREER
TO GET YOUR NAME IN THE PAPER,
YOU'RE CRAZIER THAN I THOUGHT.
LISTEN, THERE WILL BE AN
INVESTIGATION INTO THE LEAK.
WHAT MATTERS NOW
IS THAT YOU'RE IN DANGER.
NO, NO, I DON'T BUY IT.
I DON'T BUY IT.
THIS GUY'S A METHODICAL KILLER
WITH AN URGENT AGENDA.
HE'S NOT GONNA WASTE TIME
ON SOME DETOUR
JUST 'CAUSE HE FINDS OUT
I'M N HIS BEST FRIEND.
WE NEED TO ERR
ON THE SIDE OF CAUTION.
I'M TAKING YOU HOME AND HAVING
YOU GUARDED, ALL RIGHT?
COME ON.
NO, NO,
I DON'T WANT SOME STRANGER
LURKING AROUND MY HOUSE.
OKAY, FINE.
IT'LL HAVE TO BE SOMEONE
WHO YOU ALREADY KNOW.
YOU GOT CABLE?
[ STAMMERS, SCOFFS ]
THAT PACKAGE WASN'T MEANT
FOR ME.
DANIEL, MAYBE YOU DON'T
WANT TO ACCEPT IT
BECAUSE THEN YOU'D
HAVE TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR WHAT HAPPENED
TO THAT POOR GIRL.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I'M SAYING.
I-I AM RESPONSIBLE.
I MEAN, IF I'D CAUGHT THE KILLER
ASORRY TO INTERRUPT.-
DO YOU MIND?
OH, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE TALKING TO SOMEONE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
MUSTARD.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, GREY POUPON,
YELLOW?
I'M MAKING A SANDWICH.
LEWICKI!
YES.
WOULD YOU GET THE GOOD AGENT
SOME MUSTARD?
UH, I'M ON STRIKE,
REMEMBER?
LEWICKI,
I DON'T HAVE TIME FOR THIS.
THEN I SUGGEST
YOU SAY "PLEASE."
AND I SUGGEST
YOU GET THE [BLEEP] MUSTARD.
FINE.
BUT NOT BECAUSE
YOU ORDERED ME TO --
BECAUSE
I'M A NICE PERSON.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
IF THE PACKAGE WASN'T FOR YOU,
WHO WAS IT FOR?
I DON'T NOW.
SOMEONE ON CAMPUS
WHO IS SOMEHOW CONNECTED TO
ANDERSON, SCANTLIN, AND DAFOE.
WELL, LET'S TAKE THEM
ONE AT A TIME.
WHAT FIELD IS DAFOE IN?
HE'S A C.E.O. --
WHERE THE [BLEEP]
MY FACULTY DIRECTORY?
IN HERE,
UNDER THE GONG.
[ GONG CLANKS ]
COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE.
ARTHUR WEI --
HOLDS THE DISTINGUISHED
FREDERICK JAMES DAFOE
PROFESSORSHIP
OF GENETIC ENGINEERING.
PROBERT!
CAN I HELP YOU?
I'M DR. DANIEL PIERCE,
DEPARTMENT OF NEUROSCIENCE.
THIS IS AGENT PROBERT
OF THE FBI.
FBI?
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
THIS CONVERSATION
IS PRIVATE.
I ASSUME YOU HEARD
ABOUT KELLY OWENS,
THE GIRL WHO DIED
ON CAMPUS TODAY?
YEAH, IT'S TERRIBLE.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN YOU.
EXCUSE ME?
YOU WERE THE TARGET.
WHAT'S YOUR CONNECTION
TO FREDERICK DAFOE,
APART FROM THE FACT THAT YOU
HOLD A CHAIR GENEROUSLY ENDOWED
BY HIS FOUNDATION?
WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS THIS?
LOOK,
EITHER YOU TALK TO ME,
OR I GET THAT GUY OUT THERE
TO PHONE HIS BUDDIES
AT THE BUREAU,
AND THEN IT'S THE HANDCUFFS,
THE ALL-NIGHT INTERROGATION,
SWEATING IN A DAMP CELL
UNTIL YOU FINALLY BREAK
AND SPILL IT ANYWAY.
ALL IN ALL, I'D SAY
YOUR BEST BET IS TALKING TO ME.
NOW, WHAT DID YOU DO
FOR FREDERICK DAFOE
THAT GOT YOU
THE ENDOWED CHAIR?
I'M AN AGRICULTURAL
GENETICIST.
I CREATED A NEW STRAIN OF CORN
FOR HIS COMPANY.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE
TRY TO KILL YOU FOR THAT?
LOOK, WHILE I WAS WORKING
ON THE GENE,
I REALIZED THERE WAS
A POSSIBILITY
OF A TROUBLING
COLLATERAL EFFECT.
WHAT "COLLATERAL EFFECT"?
MY STRAIN OF CORN WAS
GENETICALLY DOMINANT.
IF THE SEED BLEW
INTO THE NEIGHBORING FARM,
IT WOULD WIPE OUT
THE NATIVE CORN
AND TAKE OVER
THE OTHER FARMER'S FIELD.
I WAS TRYING
TO RE-ENGINEER THE SEED
SO IT COULD ACHIEVE HARMONY
WITH THE OTHER STRAINS,
BUT DAFOE
ORDERED ME NOT TO.
WHY?
AT THE TIME,
I DIDN'T KNOW IT,
BUT ONCE THE GENE SPREAD
TO THE NEIGHBORING FARMS,
DAFOE STARTED SUING THE FARMERS
FOR SELLING HIS CORN --
MY CORN --
TO THE CONSUMER.
[ Scoffing ]
ON WHAT GROUNDS?
COPYRIGHT INFRINGEMENT.
HE HELD THE PATENT
ON THE GENE.
HE SUED THEM FOR SELLING
A STRAIN OF CORN
THAT BLEW IN ON THE WIND?
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
LOOK, THEY DIDN'T REALIZE
THEY WERE GROWING IT.
A LOT OF THEM
WENT INTO FORECLOSURE.
OH. OF COURSE.
LET ME GUESS --
DAFOE STARTED BUYING UP
THEIR FARMS ON THE CHEAP.
I WENT TO DAFOE.
I TOLD HIM
IF HE DOESN'T DROP THE SUITS,
I WOULD INFORM
THE DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE
THAT HE'D PLANNED
THE WHOLE THING.
RIGHT, AND THEN HE OFFERED YOU
THE ENDOWED CHAIR
AND MAYBE A LITTLE GRANT MONEY
AS A KICKER.
YOU'RE A SCIENTIST.
YOU KNOW HOW HARD IT IS
TO GET FUNDING --
SPARE ME THAT CRAP.
YOU TOOK YOUR 30 PIECES
OF SILVER,
AND THOSE FARMERS
LOST EVERYTHING.
NO, YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NO, I THINK I UNDERSTAND
JUST FINE...PROFESSOR.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Kate: KEVIN LANG, CAL BOWDEN,
RAY DONALDSON --
ANY OF THESE NAMES MEAN ANYTHING
TO YOU, MR. DAFOE?
UH, NO,
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF THEM.
OF COURSE NOT.
YOU GOT LAWYERS FOR THAT.
LANG, BOWDEN, AND DONALDSON
WERE THREE OF THE FARMERS
WHOSE LIVES YOU RUINED
WHEN YOU SUED THEM
FOR COPYRIGHT INFRINGEMENT
FOR UNKNOWINGLY TAKING CORN
CONTAINING THE DAFOE GENE
TO MARKET.
THAT GENE WAS PATENTED.
YEAH, AND DESIGNED TO OBLITERATE
EVERY CORNSTALK IN ITS PATH.
Kate: SCANTLIN HANDLED
THE LAWSUITS,
AND THEN ANDERSON FAST-TRACKED
THE FARMS TO FORECLOSURE,
SO YOU COULD SNAP UP
THOSE PROPERTIES
FOR PENNIES
ON THE DOLLAR.
YES, THAT'S CALLED
GOOD BUSINESS.
U.S. ATTORNEY'S GONNA CALL IT
CONSPIRACY TO COMMIT FRAUD.
ALL RIGHT,
LISTEN, SWEETIE,
I'M NOT GONNA SAY
ANOTHER WORD TO YOU
WITHOUT A LAWTHAT'S FINE.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME,
THE KILLER IS STILL OUT THERE.
IT'S A PRETTY GOOD BET
THAT YOU ARE ON HIS LIST.
SO I SUGGEST YOU TELL US
WHICH OF THE FARMERS YOU RUINED
MIGHT BE DOING THIS.
OKAY, THERE WAS AN INCIDENT
AT THE SHAREHOLDERS MEETING.
A VERY ANGRY MAN
STORMED INTO THE ROOM,
YELLING THREATS AND OBSCENITIES,
AND HE HAD TO BE ESCORTED OUT.
I NEED A NAME.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE MY SECURITY PEOPLE
MIGHT HAVE IT.
LOOK, ARE YOU GOING TO
BE ABLE TO KEEP ME SAFE?
OH, YEAH.
U.S. MARSHALS WILL PROTECT YOU.
AFTER ALL, WE WOULDN'T WANT
ANYTHING HAPPENING TO YOU
BEFORE YOU CAN START SERVING
YOUR SENTENCE.
GOT THE NAME OF THE FARMER THAT
STORMED THE SHAREHOLDER MEETING
AND THREATENED DAFOE --
PAUL LEVASSEUR.
GREAT.
LET'S GO PICK HIM UP.
HE'S SERVING 8 TO 10
IN STATEVILLE PRISON.
BEEN THERE THREE MONTHS.
NOT OUR GUY.
BUT MAYBE HE CAN
TELL US WHO IS.
HOW DO YOU FIGURE THAT?
WHY DID THE KILLER PUT
HIS MESSAGE IN A NEWSPAPER?
MAYBE BECAUSE HE WAS SENDING IT
TO SOMEBODY
WHOSE LETTERS GET OPENED
AND READ
BEFORE THEY'RE DELIVERED.
SOMEONE IN PRISON.
MY GREAT-GREAT-GRANDFATHER
HOMESTEADED THAT LAND.
MY FAMILY...
FARMED IT FOR 100 YEARS.
AFTER THE LAWSUIT, I TRIED
OTHER THINGS TO GET BY.
SOLD TRACTORS.
DUG DITCHES FOR THE COUNTY.
NOTHING STUCK.
SO YOU ROBBED A BANK.
JUST TRYING TO KEEP MY FAMILY
ABOVE WATER.
LOSING THE FARM,
SEEING ME BEHIND BARS...
BROKE MY WIFE'S HEART.
SHE HUNG HERSELF
NINE WEEKS AGO.
I'M SO SORRY.
LISTEN, MR. LEVASSEUR,
WE'RE HERE TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT YOUR SON, EDDIE.
Daniel: THE CODED MESSAGE
IN THE NEWSPAPER --
HE PUT THAT THERE FOR YOU,
DIDN'T HE?
"FRONT-PAGE NEWS."
JUST LIKE HE SAID.
I TRIED TO CALL HIM
AFTER I READ ABOUT SCANTLIN,
BUT HIS PHONE WAS TURNED OFF.
YOU COULD HAVE CALLED
THE POLICE.
[ Crying ]
I KNOW I SHOULD HAVE, BUT...
HE WAS YOUR BOY.
YOU COULDN'T BEAR
TO TURN HIM IN.
AFTER --
AFTER THIS ALL WENT DOWN,
SOMETHING IN HIM BROKE.
BUT I SWEAR TO YOU,
HE'S A GOOD BOY.
A BRILLIANT BOY.
FINISHED COLLEGE
IN THREE YEARS.
COULDN'T WAIT TO GET STARTED IN
ON HIS PhD.
BUT HE HAD TO DROP OUT
AFTER YOU LOST THE FARM.
I COULDN'T SEND HIM A DIME.
HE'S BEEN TEACHING
HIGH-SCHOOL MATH IN HARVEY.
ACTUALLY, HE HASN'T BEEN THERE
IN OVER A MONTH.
HE HASN'T BEEN BACK
TO HIS APARTMENT, EITHER.
WE NEED TO FIND HIM
BEFORE SOMEONE ELSE DIES.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHERE HE IS?
THERE'S A -- THERE'S A PLACE
HE USED TO LIKE TO GO TO THINK.
ON THE BACK ACREAGE
OF OUR OLD FARM.
LOOK AT THIS.
HE KNEW WE WERE COMING.
"HEY, KINDRED,
MY LIFE'S AN OPEN BOOK.
"WHEN YOU CRACK THIS ONE,
YOU'LL KNOW EVERYTHING.
"BUT SEARCH YOUR MIND.
DO YOU REALLY
WANT TO STOP ME?"
WHAT IS IT WITH THIS GUY?
FIRST HE BLOWS YOU OFF,
THEN HE LEAVES YOU ANOTHER CLUE?
HE WANTS TO AVENGE
THE INJUSTICE
DONE TO HIS FATHER
AND THE OTHER FARMERS,
BUT HE DID NOT MEAN TO KILL
AN INNOCENT COLLEGE STUDENT,
SO MAYBE HE'S FEELING GUILTY
OR CONFLICTED.
SOME PART OF HIM
WANTS TO GET CAUGHT.
LET'S GIVE HIM
WHAT HE WANTS.
"MY LIFE'S AN OPEN BOOK."
"OPEN BOOK."
IT'S A BOOK CIPHER.
LOOK, THE NUMBERS
ARE IN GROUPS OF THREE.
THE FIRST ONE CORRESPONDS
TO A PAGE NUMBER
IN A PARTICULAR BOOK,
THE SECOND ONE --
SECOND NUMBER TO --
TO A LINE ON THAT PAGE,
AND THE THIRD NUMBER TO A WORD
IN THAT LINE.
YOU FIND THE WORDS,
YOU PUT THEM TOGETHER,
YOU GET YOUR MESSAGE.
IT COULD --
IT COULD BE ANY BOOK
IN THE WORLD.
YOU'RE NOT LISTENING,
OLD BOY.
HE'S TELLING YOU EVERYTHING
YOU NEED TO KNOW.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
"SEARCH YOUR MIND,"
PIERCE.
I AM. I AM.
It's not helping!
DANIEL, YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. DON'T --
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
OKAY? I'M F-FINE.
JUST DON'T WORRY ABOUT...
ME.
YOU NEED TO TAKE ME HOME.
Daniel:
THIS IS OUR KEY.
"THE MIND:
KNOWING THE UNKNOWABLE".
BY DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
I LOVE THIS BOOK.
BUT WHAT DO YOU --
HE'S NOT SAYING
"SEARCH YOUR MIND."
HE'S SAYING
HE MEANS THE TITLE
OF YYEAH.OOK.
GO TO PAGE...312.
SECOND LINE, THIRD WORD.
"TODAY."
PAGE 57.
17th LINE, 12th WORD.
14th LINE, 9th WORD.
"FAMILY."
"TODAY I DESTROY
THE VILLAIN
THE SAME WAY THE VILLAIN
DESTROYED MY FAMILY."
"DESTROY THE VILLAIN."
WHO'S HE TALKING ABOUT?
IT'S GOT TO BE DAFOE.
I MEAN, HE'S THE MAIN VILLAIN
IN THIS WHOLE SORDID STORY.
DAFOE IS IN
PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
HOW'S THE KILLER
GONNA DESTROY HIM THERE?
THERE ARE A MILLION WAYS
TO DESTROY SOMEONE
WHOSE ONLY PRIORITY
IS PROFITS.
I MEAN, YOU COULD TAKE OUT
THEIR PROCESSING PLANTS,
OR THEIR WAREHOUSES
OR THEIR GRAIN ELEVATORS.
YEAH,
IT'S A HUGE COMPANY.
WE DON'T HAVE THE MANPOWER
TO PROTECT EVERY ONE
OF HIS FACILITIES.
BUT WE CAN TRY.
JUST GET THE BOSS ON THE PHONE.
Codebreaker:
A WORD WITH YOU, OLD CHAP?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
"TODAY
I DESTROY THE VILLAIN
THE SAME WAY THE VILLAIN
DESTROYED MY FAMILY."
YEAH. SO?
PERHAPS
THERE'S ANOTHER CODE
BURIED IN
THE MESSAGE ITSELF.
Natalie: DANIEL, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO LISTEN TO HIM.
EACH LETTER
REPRESENTS A NUMBER.
YOU DON'T NEED HIS HELP.
PERHAPS IT'S AN ADDRESS.
YOU'VE CRACKED THE CIPHERS.
NOW IT'S ABOUT
CRACKING EDDIE.
[ STAMMERS ]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT DID DAFOE DO
THAT REALLY HURT HIM?
DID HE TAKE AWAY HIS FARM,
HIS LIVELIHOOD, OR SOMETHING
MORE IMPORTANT TO HIM?
I LOVE YOU, NATALIE VINCENT.
I DID IT.
I-I SOLVED THE RIDDLE.
SO DO WE.AT EDDIE'S DOING.
OUR AGENTS FOUND A TRUCK BOMB
FULL OF FERTILIZER
JUST OUTSIDE
DAFOE HEADQUARTERS.
WHAT? NO. NO, NO, NO.
THAT'S A DECOY.
REMEMBER THE ORIGINAL MESSAGE --
"ONE DOWN, FOUR TO GO."
THAT MAKES FIVE VICTIMS.
NOW EDDIE'S TELLING US,
"TODAY I DESTROY THE VILLAIN
THE SAME WAY THE VILLAIN
DESTROYED MY FAMILY."
H-HIS FATHER'S IN PRISON,
HIS MOTHER TOOK HER OWN LIFE,
ALL BECAUSE OF DAFOE.
THREE OF THE VICTIMS ARE DEAD.
WHO ARE THE LAST TWO?
DAFOE'S PARENTS.
HE'S IN THERE
WITH THE DAFOES.
QUESTION IS,
WHAT'S HE WAITING FOR?
HE'S WAITING
TO TALK TO ME.
WANT TO GIVE THIS A TRY?
NO, IT'S GOT TO BE
FACE-TO-FACE.
DANIEL,
YOU'RE NOT GOING IN THERE.
HE TOLD ME
HOW TO FIND HIM.
HE MUST HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY TO ME.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
I'M GOING IN WITH YOU.
AND YOU'RE WEARING A WIRE
SO SWAT CAN HEAR
WHAT'S GOING ON.
LOOK, IF YOU CAN GET HIM
IN FRONT OF A WINDOW,
ONE OF MY SNIPERS
CAN TAKE HIM OUT.
[ SIGHS ]
UH, EDDIE,
I'M DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
MAY I COME IN?
JUST HIM.
AND IF YOU OR ANYONE ELSE
SO MUCH AS RATTLES
THIS DOORKNOB,
I PRESS THIS BUTTON,
AND WE ALL GO UP TOGETHER.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
DANIEL.
I-I CAN DO IT.
THERE'S A WAY
OUT OF THIS, EDDIE.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY
OUT FOR ME.
IF YOU BELIEVE THAT,
THEN WHY DID YOU TELL ME
WHERE TO FIND YOU?
I MEAN,
THE PUZZLES WERE CLEVER,
BUT YOU KNEW
I'D BE ABLE TO SOLVE THEM.
YEAH.
I WANTED YOU HERE...
BECAUSE YOU SAID
YOU WERE MY KINDRED SPIRIT,
AND I WANTED TO BELIEVE
THAT THERE WAS SOMEONE OUT THERE
WHO UNDERSTOOD ME.
BUT YOU'VE BEEN WORKING
FOR THE COPS THE WHOLE TIME.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO DIE
WITH ME.
GET HIM OUT OF THERE
RIGHT NOW!
NO, IF WE STORM IN THERE,
HE PUSHES THE BUTTON.
YOUR GUY'S ALL ON HIS OWN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU KNOW,
I KNEW I WAS TAKING A RISK
WHEN I CAME
THROUGH THAT DOOR,
BUT I CAME ANYWAY.
WHY?
BECAUSE I AM
YOUR KINDRED SPIRIT.
NO, IT'S TRUE.
YEAH,
I'M WORKING FOR THE COPS,
BUT I BELIEVE IN WHAT
YOU'RE FIGHTING FOR, EDDIE.
I HATE LAWYERS, EDDIE,
AND -- AND --
AND CORPORATIONS
AND THE WAY THEY SCREW OVER
HARDWORKING, HONEST PEOPLE.
WHAT SCANTLIN AND ANDERSON
AND THE REST OF THOSE [BLEEP]
DID TO YOUR FAMILY
IS UNFORGIVABLE.
IT'S -- IT'S EVIL.
I UNDERSTAND WHY YOU'D
WANT TO MAKE THEM PAY. I DO.
BUT THESE PEOPLE
DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
YES, THEY DID.
THEY RAISED A MONSTER.
THEY RAISED A SON THAT HAS
NO CONSCIENCE AT ALL.
AND YOUR FATHER
RAISED YOU,
AND YOU DO HAVE
A CONSCIENCE.
AND THAT'S THE REAL REASON THAT
YOU BROUGHT ME HERE, ISN'T IT?
'CAUSE DEEP DOWN,
YOU WANT ME TO STOP YOU
FROM KYOU'RE WRONG. ELSE.
YOU STARTED THIS, EDDIE,
BECAUSE YOU WANTED TO MAKE
YOUR FATHER PROUD OF YOU.
HE STILL CAN BE.
NOBODY ELSE HAS TO DIE.
YOU'VE ALREADY FINISHED THE JOB.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
DAFOE AND WEI
ARE GOING TO JAIL.
YOU'RE LYING.
NO, I'M NOT.
THANKS TO YOU, I FIGURED OUT
WHAT THEY WERE DOING
TO YOUR FATHER
AND THE OTHER FARMERS.
THE U.S. ATTORNEY
IS GONNA INDICT THEM.
THERE'LL BE LAWSUITS,
EDDIE.
SOME OF THOSE FARMERS
WILL GET THEIR LAND BACK.
IT'S TOO LATE
FOR MY FATHER AND ME.
WELL, MAYBE YOU COULD STILL
BE TOGETHER.
HOW? IN HELL?
I'LL TALK
TO THE U.S. ATTORNEY
ABOUT HAVING YOU SENTENCED
TO STATEVILLE.
I PROMISE.
NOW...
WHY DON'T YOU
PUT DOWN THAT DETONATOR,
AND LET'S WALK
OUT OF HERE TOGETHER.
IF I GO OUT THERE,
THE ONLY CELL THEY'RE GONNA
PUT ME IN IS ONE ON DEATH ROW.
AND I DESERVE TO DIE.
I KILLED AN INNOCENT GIRL.
YEAH, AND YOU CAN PAY
FOR THAT CRIME, EDDIE,
BUT NOT WITH YOUR LIFE.
THERE WERE MITIGATING
CIRCUMSTANCES.
YOU WERE TRAUMATIZED
BY WHAT DAFOE AND HIS CABAL
DID TO YOUR FAMILY,
AND I'LL TESTIFY TO THAT.
YOU LIED TO ME BEFORE.
HOW DO I KNOW
YOU'RE NOT LYING TO ME NOW?
I GOT THE SHTAKE IT.
EDDIE,
GET AWAY FROM THAT WINDOW!
GOD!
WHY THE [BLEEP]
DID YOU DO THAT, HUH?
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
LET THEM KILL ME?
BECAUSE I MEANT
WHAT I SAID, EDDIE.
NOBODY ELSE HAS TO DIE.
I COULD STILL
PUSH THIS BUTTON.
YEAH, YOU CAN.
BUT I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE GOING TO.
COME ON. COME ON. COME ON.
WHAT THE [BLEEP] GOING ON?
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
HE'S SURRENDERING!
HE LEFT
THE DETONATOR INSIDE!
GO! GO! GO! GO!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING,
EDDIE.
[ EDDIE GRUNTS ]
YEP.YOU OKAY?
YOU SURE?
YEAH. THAT --
THAT COULD HAVE GONE
A WHOLE DIFFERENT WAY.
I KNEW YOU WERE CRAZY.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE THAT CRAZY.
YEAH. ME NEITHER.
Daniel:
WHAT IS A CONSCIENCE?
IS IT SOMETHING WE CAN LOCATE
ON AN MRI?
STUDIES HAVE SHOWN
THAT PEOPLE WITH DAMAGE TO THE
VENTROMEDIAL PREFRONTAL CORTEX
ARE ACTUALLY MORE WILLING
TO SACRIFICE A HUMAN LIFE
AS LONG AS THEY PERCEIVE THAT
IT'S FOR SOME GREATER GOOD.
BUT WHAT ABOUT PEOPLE
WHO HAVE NO TROUBLE
SACRIFICING OTHERS
TO THEIR OWN SELFISH ENDS?
IS HEARTLESS CRUELTY
OUR TRUE NATURE
AND EMPATHY THE ABERRATION?
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO SAY,
"IT'S NICE TO BE NICE."
AND THAT MAY BE TRUE.
OR ARE WE BETTER OFF
SPENDING EVERY WAKING MOMENT
TENDING OUR OWN SELFISH NEEDS?
THE GOOD NEWS IS,
IT TURNS OUT THERE'S
AN EVOLUTIONARY ADVANTAGE
TO SIMPLE HUMAN KINDNESS.
WE COULDN'T GET THROUGH
A COLD PALEOLITHIC WINTER
WITHOUT A LITTLE COOPERATION.
STILL, ON SOME PREHISTORIC LEVEL
WE'RE ALL LONE HUNTERS.
SO IT CAN FEEL DANGEROUS
TO SHOW ANY SOFTNESS
TO OTHER MEMBERS OF THE TRIBE.
BUT IF WE MANAGE TO LAY DOWN OUR
CLUBS AND OUR SHARPENED ROCKS,
ANSWERING THE CALL
OF THE ALTRUISTIC IMPERATIVE
CAN BE ITS OWN REWARD.