WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
DYING IN A PLANE CRASH?
OR CATCHING
AN INCURABLE DISEASE?
GETTING EATEN BY A SHARK.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHAT YOU SHOULD
REALLY BE AFRAID OF...
IS FAILING THIS CLASS.
[ BOOK SLAMS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHAT, WE SCARE YOU?
FEAR CAN OVERRIDE
RATIONAL THOUGHT.
BEFORE THE NEOCORTEX
CAN EVEN PROCESS A THREAT,
THE AMYGDALA KICKS IN,
AND NOW YOU'RE IN
FIGHT-OR-FLIGHT MODE.
BUT THIS SAME NEUROLOGICAL
PROGRAMMING CAN ALSO SPOOK US.
CAUSE US TO ACT IRRATIONALLY
WHEN, IN REALITY,
THERE'S NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
SO...
CAN WE OVERRIDE
OUR MOST PRIMAL INSTINCTS?
CONDITION OURSELVES
NOT TO REACT OUT OF FEAR?
ALL YOUR MEALS
ARE ON THE FRIDGE.
EVERYTHING
IS COLOR-CODED.
ALL YOU GOT TO DO IS REHEAT THEM
IN THE MICROWAVE.
I DON'T EAT IRRADIATED FOOD.
YOU KNOW THAT.
[ SIGHS ]
OKAY, YOU KNOW, DOC,
MAYBE I COULD JUST DO AN iCHAT
WITH MY FOLKS.
IT'S THEIR 30th ANNIVERSARY,
LEWICKI.
YOU'RE GOING HOME.
I CAN MANAGE ON MY OWN
FOR ONE WEEKEND.
I'LL BE FINE.
WHAT IS AN iCHAT?
I DO SOLEMNLY SWEAR
TO SUPPORT
AND DEFEND THE CONSTITUTION
OF THE UNITED STATES
AGAINST ALL ENEMIES
FOREIGN AND DOMESTIC.
"AND I WILL PROVE
A CRUSHING DISAPPOINTMENT
TO MY CONSTITUENTS."
AND I TAKE THIS
OBLIGATION FREELY.
"I WILL MAKE
SHADY BACKROOM DEALS
"WITH MY FELLOW SENATORS
"AND ACCEPT AS MUCH
SPECIAL-INTEREST MONEY
AS I CAN STUFF
IN MY POCKETS."
YOU VOT FOR RYLAND.
LESSER OF TWO EVILS.
[ HORN HONKS ]
LEWICKI,
YOUR CAB IS HERE!
MAYBE HE'LL SURPRISE YOU.
RYLAND WAS
THE LAST GUY'S PROTéGé.
HE'LL TURN OUT TO BE YET
ANOTHER WALL STREET LACKEY
JUST LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE
IN CONGRESS.
DANIEL,
DON'T BE SO CYNICAL.
EASY FOR YOU TO SAY --
YOU DIDN'T VOTE.
OF COURSE I VOTED.
I WASN'T TALKING TO YOU.
OKAY. UH...
TELL HER I SAY, "HI."
HEY, DOC?
YOU GOT A LETTER.
THERE'S NO STAMP,
SO IT MUST HAVE BEEN
HAND-DELIVERED FROM SOME GUY --
WESLEY SUMTER?
WHO'S WESLEY SUMTER?
HE'S A F[ HORN HONKS ]
WOULD YOU GET OUT
OF HERE ALREADY?
[ Sighing ]
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, UH,
I WILL SEE YOU ON SUNDAY.
DON'T DO ANYTHING
CRAZY, DOC.
NO PROMISES.
I CAN CANCEL.
IT'S A JOKE.
I'M JOKING. GO!
[ SIGHS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
DANIEL, WHAT'S WRONG?
[ GASPS ]
OH [BLEEP] IT!
Wesley, are you trying
to give me a coronary?!
I'm sorry.
I-i didn't mean to scare you.
Well, what's with
the melodrama, huh?
T-T-The note, the meeting
at 2:00 in the morning?
What the [bleep]
is going on?!
I'll explain everything,
okay, b-but not here.
People could be listening.
Come on. Come on.
Okay, this is good.
This is good, this is good.
LISTEN, THIS NEW SENATOR,
RYLAND...
YOU REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIS PREDECESSOR?
WELL, YEAH, HIS PRIVATE JET FLEW
INTO THE SIDE OF A MOUNTAIN.
HIS PLANE WAS SABOTAGED.
SABOTAGED? BY WHOM?
LARRY CRAWFORD, C.E.O.
OF THE VERTERON CORPORATION.
THE ELECTRONICS COMPANY?
YEAH. PAULSON...
PAULSON CHAIRED -- HE CHAIRED
A-A COMMITTEE THAT --
THAT -- THAT --
THAT WAS --
WAS GONNA PASS A...
A CLEAN-ENERGY BILL
THAT WOULD HAVE COST
VERTERON BILLIONS.
OKAY.
OKAY, S-SO THEY STOOD TO GAIN
FROM PAULSON'S DEATH,
BUT WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THEY HAD ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE PLANE CRASH?
THEY MADE THE -- [ SNIFFS ]
THE ANTI-COLLISION SYSTEM
THAT SHOULD HAVE PREVENTED
THE ACCIDENT.
NOT ONLY THAT, BUT --
BUT -- BUT -- [ GULPS ]
ONE OF THEIR ENGINEERS,
BRIAN WILLINGHAM,
DIED RIGHT AFTER HE FOUND OUT
ABOUT THE SABOTAGE.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
T-THEY SAID
IT WAS SUICIDE,
BUT -- BUT I THINK
IT WAS MURDER.
WESLEY, W-W-WHAT ARE YOU
COMING TO ME WITH THIS FOR?
YOU SHOULD GO
TO THE POLICE.
[ SCOFFS ]
I TRIED.
I TRIED,
BUT -- BUT NO ONE --
NO ONE WOULD
TAKE ME SERIOUSLY.
E-EXCEPT FOR ONE GUY,
THIS -- THIS REPORTER,
UH, UH,
FROM THE STAR-HERALD,
BUT THEN -- BUT THEN
HE, UH -- HE DROVE HIS CAR
OFF OF A ROAD,
AND HE BROKE HIS NECK.
NOW,
THAT'S THREE MEN DEAD,
AND I'M GONNA BE THE FOURTH
IF THIS COMPANY ISN'T STOPPED.
WESLEY,
I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE SCARED,
A-A-AND IF WHAT YOU'RE SAYING
IS TRUE, IT'S TERRIBLE.
BUT...
ISN'T IT POSSIBLE YOU'RE MAKING
CONNECTIONS THAT...
THAT AREN'T REALLY THERE?
[ SCOFFING ]
[ GULPS ]
I READ ABOUT YOUR WORK
IN THE SARIN BOMBER CASE,
AND I THOUGHT THAT --
THAT IF ANYONE WERE TO HELP ME
BLOW THE LID OFF THIS THING,
IT WOULD BE YOU,
BUT I GUESS I WAS WRONG.
W-W-WAIT, WESLEY.
L-LOOK, LOOK.
THERE'S AN FBI AGENT
THAT I KNOW.
I-I'LL ASK HER
TO LOOK INTO IT, OKAY?
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, PROFESSOR.
WAIT, OH.
EVERYTHING --
EVERYTHING THAT --
THAT YOU NEED TO KNOW IS --
IS IN HERE.
HERE IT IS.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ LAUGHS ]
I-I KNEW YOU WOULD HELP.
I --
WESLEY.
HEADING OUT?
IT'S NOT EVEN 3:00 A.M. YET.
YEAH, THOUGHT I'D KNOCK OFF
A LITTLE EARLY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
STICK AROUND.
I'LL BUY YOU BREAKFAST.
THERE WILL BE BACON.
YOU DO KNOW
MY WEAKNESS.
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
MORETTI.
D-DANIEL, SLOW DOWN.
UH, OKAY, JUST STAY CALM.
I'LL BE RIGHT OVER.
CALL CPD.
THERE'S BEEN A MURDER
AT THE CLMU CAMPUS --
COURTYARD BY THE CHAPEL.
[ POLICE ROGER.CHATTER ]
WE HAVE A SLIGHT PROBLEM.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHERE'S WESLEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU TELL ME.
I WAS THE FIRST PERSON
ON THE SCENE,
AND THERE WAS NO BODY
WHEN I GOT HERE.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING ]
DANIEL?
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
LISTEN, CPD's BEEN
INTERVIEWING FACULTY
AND STUDENTS FOR HOURS.
NO ONE SAW ANY SHOOTING
OR ANYONE FLEEING THE SCENE.
THIS AREA O-OF THE CAMPUS
IS DESERTED AT NIGHT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
CRIME TECHS DIDN'T TURN UP
ANY BLOOD RESIDUE, EITHER.
WELL, OBVIOUSLY SOMEBODY'S
CLEANED UP THE CRIME SCENE.
THESE...
THESE ARE JUST NEWSPAPER
CLIPPINGS, OKAY?
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE HERE.
I GOT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU --
THE BOSS IS [BLEEP]
FORENSICS HAS BEEN OUT HERE
ALL NIGHT.
I GOT TO SEND
THESE PEOPLE HOME.
WELL, I'M SORRY
IF WESLEY'S MURDER
HAS INCONVENIENCED
THE CRIME LAB.
DANIEL, LISTEN.
REARDON KNOWS ABOUT YOUR...
CONDITION.
SHE DOESN'T CONSIDER YOU A...
RELIABLE WITNESS.
[ SCOFFS ]
WE RAN THE NAME
YOU GAVE US.
THERE'S NO RECORD
OF A WESLEY SUMTER
ANYWHERE IN CHICAGO
OR HAVING EVER ATTENDED CLMU.
I TOLD YOU,
HE ONLY AUDITED MY CLASS.
I-I-I DON'T KNOW
IF HE EVER REGISTERED.
AND HE WOULDN'T BE THE FIRST
PERSON TO KEEP HIS NAME...
out of
a government database.
LISTEN,
YOU KNOW I'VE GOT YOUR BACK,
AND I'M GONNA KEEP DIGGING,
EVEN IF REARDON DOESN'T LIKE IT,
BUT I...
I GOT TO ASK YOU...
IS IT POSSIBLE
THAT YOU SAW SOMETHING
THAT DIDN'T REALLY HAPPEN?
Daniel: LOOK AT THIS.
IT SAYS THE NTSB's REPORT
ON THE PLANE CRASH
HAS BEEN DELAYED A THIRD TIME.
MAYBE WESLEY WAS RIGHT.
M-MAYBE THE SENATOR'S PLANE
REALLY WAS SABOTAGED.
Natalie:
DANIEL, THE STORY HE TOLD
IS EXACTLY THE KIND
OF PARANOID SCENARIO
THAT A SCHIZOPHRENIC
WOULD COME UP WITH.
YOU THINK WESLEY
WAS MENTALLY ILL?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT YOU ARE.
MAYBE KATE'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO SAW THIS GUY.
WELL, I-IF WESLEY WASN'T REAL,
WHERE DID ALL THESE COME FROM?
YOU HAVE A CLOSET FULL
OF OLD NEWSPAPERS.
LEWICKI JUST -- JUST SAVES THOSE
FOR THE CROSSWORDS.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE LETTER?
YOU DO HAVE A TYPEWRITER.
YOU'RE SAYING
I SENT IT TO MYSELF.
HAVE YOU BEEN TAKING
YOUR MEDS?
LEWICKI PICKED UP A PRESCRIPTION
FOR ME WEEKS AGO.
YOU KNOW THAT.
I DIDN'T ASK YOU IF YOU HAD
A PRESCRIPTION FILLED.
I ASKED IF YOU WERE TAKING
YOUR MEDS.
IF WE OPEN THE MEDICINE CABINET
AND COUNTED THE PILLS,
HOW MANY WOULD BE LEFT?
YOU'VE BEEN UNDER
A LOT OF STRESS
SINCE YOU STARTED WORKING
WITH KATE AGAIN,
BUT I DON'T THINK YOUR
COPING MECHANISMS ARE ENOUGH
TO KEEP YOU
ON AN EVEN KEEL ANYMORE.
IF YOU WON'T TAKE THE MEDICATION
FOR YOURSELF,
THEN DO IT FOR HER.
W-WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
KATE'S OUT THERE TRYING TO FIND
EVIDENCE FOR A MURDER
THAT MIGHT HAVE ONLY HAPPENED
IN YOUR MIND.
THINK ABOUT HER CAREER,
HER REPUTATION.
WHAT IF YOU'RE WRONG?
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
NEVER UNDERESTIMATE THE POWER
OF SHOE LEATHER.
MIGHT WANT TO MAKE US
SOME POPCORN.
WHERE DID YOU GET THIS?
A STUDENT CAUGHT THE WHOLE THING
ON HIS CELLPHONE.
[ SIGHS ]
IT REALLY HAPPENED.
I'M SORRY I DOUBTED YOU.
I UNDERSTAND WHY YOU DID.
LOOK, I'VE ASKED THE CART UNIT
TO ENHANCE THE TAPE,
TRY TO I.D. THE SNIPER.
SO WESLEY REALLY WAS
ONTO SOMETHING BIG,
A-A-AND WHOEVER KILLED
THE SENATOR
WAS TRYING
TO SILENCE HIM.
JUST SO WE'RE CLEAR,
I'M NOT INVESTIGATING SOME
JAMES BOND MURDER PLOT, OKAY?
I'M JUST LOOKING FOR A GUY
WITH A CROSSBOW.
DO WE HAVE AN ADDRESS YET
FOR WESLEY OR NEXT OF KIN?
NO, AND THERE'S NO PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE AT THE CRIME SCENE.
WELL, IF WE CAN'T FIND HIS BODY,
THEN MAYBE --
MAYBE LOOKING INTO
WHAT HE WAS INVESTIGATING
WILL LEAD US TO THE KILLER.
YOU SAID WESLEY WAS TALKING
TO A REPORTER?
[ SNAPS FINGERS ]
YES.
YES!
FROM THE, UH...
STAR-HERALD.
UH...UH...
HERE.
DAVID ALCOTT.
BUT HE'S DEAD.
MAYBE HIS BOSS AT THE PAPER
HAS SOME INFORMATION ON WESLEY.
OH, YOU MUST MEAN
"CRAZY" WESLEY.
OH, HE CALLS THE ASSIGNMENT DESK
AT ALL HOURS
AND LEAVES THESE BIZARRE
MESSAGES ON OUR VOICEMAIL.
ONCE, HE CALLED FROM A WAREHOUSE
IN NEW MEXICO,
CLAIMED HE HAD FOUND
THE SOUND STAGE
WHERE NASA HAD FAKED
THE LUNAR LANDING.
THE GUY IS ABSOLUTELY NUTS.
SOME MYTHS, IT SEEMS,
NEVER DIE.
BUT PUTTING A MAN ON THE MOON
WAS MY GREATEST ACCOMPLISHMENT.
50 YEARS LATER,
AND THEY'RE STILL TRYING
TO UNDERMINE MY PRESIDENCY.
DO YOU HAVE ANY CONTACT INFO
FOR WESLEY --
A PHONE NUMBER, MAYBE?
I'LL LOOK,
BUT I DOUBT IT.
YOU KNOW,
THE GUY IS A TOTAL WHACK JOB.
WHY ARE YOU ASKING
ABOUT HIM, ANYWAY?
WELL, HE WAS MURDERED
LAST NIGHT.
YES. YES.
UH, BUT BEFORE HE DIED,
HE TOLD ME HE TIPPED OFF
ONE OF YOUR REPORTERS,
WHO ALSO DIED RECENTLY.
YOU MEAN DAVID ALCOTT?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT ALCOTT
WAS WORKING ON?
NO, DAVID KEPT HIS CARDS
PRETTY CLOSE TO HIS VEST.
HE WAS ALWAYS AFRAID
OF BEING SCOOPED.
WHAT ABOUT HIS COMPUTER?
HE NEVER USED ONE.
HE WAS PRETTY OLD-SCHOOL.
BUT WE CLEANED OUT
HIS DESK
AND THREW EVERYTHING
IN A BOX.
I COULD GET MY ASSISTANT
TO FIND THE BOX FOR YOU.
WESLEY'S NAME IS MENTIONED,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING
IN THE REPORTER'S NOTES
THAT AREN'T ALSO
IN THE NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS.
PLEIADES.
SEVEN SISTERS --
GREEK MYTHOLOGY.
WHAT, YOU THINK THE ONLY CLASS
I TOOK IN COLLEGE WAS YOURS?
YOU THINK IT MEANS
SOMETHING?
GOT TO ADMIT, THOUGHT
IT WAS A WILD-GOOSE CHASE.
I MEAN, WHAT THE [BLEEP]
DOES A CAMPUS SHOOTING
HAVE TO DO WITH THE DEATH
OF A UNITED STATES SENATOR?
BUT I THINK I ACTUALLY FOUND
A CONNECTION.
WELL,
WILL MIRACLES NEVER CEASE?
I RAN ALCOTT'S
CELLPHONE RECORDS.
THERE WERE SEVEN CALLS
BETWEEN HIM AND A CELL
REGISTERED TO HELEN PAULSON.
W-WIFE OF
THE LATE SENATOR?
WHY WOULD SHE BE CALLING
A REPORTER?
HELEN PAULSON.
IF THE SENATOR WAS MURDERED,
HE MAY HAVE BEEN THREATENED.
AND MAYBE HIS WIFE
CAN GIVE US A NAME.
"INSIDERS SAY THE GOVERNOR
HAS DECIDED
TO APPOINT HELEN PAULSON TO FILL
HER HUSBAND'S SENATE SEAT."
BUT THE GOVERNMENT
DIDN'T APPOINT HER.
MAYBE THE INSIDERS
WERENO.ONG.
"IN A HASTILY CALLED
PRESS CONFERENCE,
"MRS. PAULSON ANNOUNCED
SHE WAS DECLINING
"THE GOVERNOR'S OFFER
"AND INSTEAD URGED HIM
TO CALL A SPECIAL ELECTION
"TO LET THE PEOPLE
OF ILLINOIS DECIDE
WHO THEIR NEXT SENATOR
WILL BE."
SHE ENDORSED
SCOTT RYLAND.
WHY WOULD ANYBODY TURN DOWN
A SENATE SEAT?
I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
HOW ABOUT INSTEAD OF
STANDING HERE SPECULATING,
WE JUST ASK HER?
OKAY, GOT IT, GOT IT.
[ CAR DOOR CLOSES ]
AGENT MORETTI, FBI.
IS THAT HELEN PAULSON?
YEAH.
SHE'S IN PREWHAT HAPPENED?
DON'T KNOW. SHE WAS UNRESPONSIVE
WHEN WE GOT HERE.
THE MAID FOUND HER LIKE THIS
AND JUST CALLED 911.
EXCUSE ME.
THIS IS NO COINCIDENCE,
PROFESSOR.
IT'S DALLAS
ALL OVER AGAIN.
CLEARLY, SOMEONE TRIED TO
ASSASSINATE THE SENATOR'S WIFE.
[ SIREN WAILING ]
MRS. PAULSON IS DISPLAYING SIGNS
OF NEURODEGENERATION
AND CONGESTIVE
HEART FAILURE.
ANY IDEA
WHAT'S CAUSING IT?
WISH I COULD SAY.
HER PRIMARY PHYSICIAN SAID
SHE WAS THE PICTURE OF HEALTH
A MONTH AGO.
I'M JUST PUMPING HER
FULL OF ANTIBIOTICS
UNTIL THE LABS COME BACK.
CAN WE TALK TO HER?
YEAH,
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
MRS. PAULSON. HI.
THIS IS DR. PIERCE.
I'M AGENT MORETTI,
WITH THE FBI.
YES.
LISTEN, YOU SPOKE RECENTLY
WITH A NEWSPAPER REPORTER,
DAVID ALCOTT.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHAT THE TWO
OF YOU TALKED ABOUT?
HE SAID...
THAT SOMEONE CAUSED
TED'S PLANE TO CRASH.
HE SAID HE HAD EVIDENCE.
DID -- DID HE TELL YOU
WHO HE THOUGHT DID IT?
LAWRENCE CRAWFORD.
C.E.O. OF VERTERON.
WESLEY WAS RIGHT.
DID THE REPORTER SAY WHAT KIND
OF EVIDENCE HE HAD?
NO, BUT...
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
...I-I TOLD HIM
HE MUST BE MISTAKEN.
[ WHIMPERS ]
LARRY WOULD NEVER
HURT TED.
HE'S ONE OF
OUR CLOSEST FRIENDS.
MRS. PAULSON...
WHY DID YOU TURN DOWN
YOUR HUSBAND'S SENATE SEAT?
SENATE?
YES.
IS TED HERE?
[ MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY ]
CLEAR THE ROOM!
[ FLATLINE ]
THANK YOU FOR SEEING US
ON A SATURDAY, MR. CRAWFORD.
NO PROBLEM. I HOPE
THIS WON'T TAKE LONG, THOUGH.
MY SON'S SOCCER GAME STARTS
IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
OH, WE'LL GET YOU THERE
ON TIME.
I SEE YOU HAVE AN INTEREST
IN ASTRONOMY.
IT'S A HOBBY.
AND WHAT
ARE THO STARS?
THOSE ARE THE PLEIADES.
THE SEVHMM.ISTERS.
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TALK ASTRONOMY.
NO.
IT'S ABOUT HELEN PAULSON.
WE SPOKE WITH HER
A FEW HOURS AGO,
JUST BEFORE SHE...DIED.
HELEN DIED?
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE DON'T KNOW,
BUT AN AUTOPSY HAS BEEN ORDERED.
SO MUCH TRAGEDY
FOR ONE FAMILY.
SHE TOLD US THAT SOMEBODY
AT THIS COMPANY
WAS INVOLVED IN
HER HUSBAND'S PLANE CRASH.
YEAH, SHE TOLD ME
THE SAME THING.
A REPORTER WAS MAKING
WILD ALLEGATIONS.
I TOLD HELEN I WAS SURE
IT WASN'T TRUE
BUT I'D LOOK INTO IT,
WHICH I DID.
AND, OF COURSE,
THERE WAS NOTHING TO IT.
BUT VERTERON DID MANUFACTURE
THE TERRAIN-AVOIDANCE SYSTEM
THAT WAS INSTALLED
IN THE SENATOR'S PLANE.
YES, THAT'S TRUE.
SO IF THE SYSTEM
WAS WORKING,
HE SHOULDN'T HAVE FLOWN
INTO THE SIDE
OF A MOUNTAIN
ON A CLEAR NIGHT.
THE T.A.S.
WAS WORKING PERFECTLY.
YOU SOUND PRETTY SURE
OF THAT.
WE EXAMINED DEBRIS
FROM THE PLANE.
YOU EXAMINED?
IS IT STANDARD
PROCEDURE FOR --
FOR A COMPANY TO DETERMINE
ITS OWN CULPABILITY
IN A FATAL PLANE CRASH?
THE NTSB ASKED
FOR OUR COOPERATION.
WE GAVE IT TO THEM.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME,
HAVE A LOOK AT THIS.
THE NTSB REPORT.
HOW DO YOU HAVE THIS?
THIS HASN'T BEEN RELEASED YET.
THEY'RE RELEASING IT
MONDAY. THEY E-MAILED
ME AN ADVANCED COPY.
[ Laughing ]
AND THEY SAY THE GOVERNMENT
IS TOO COZY
WITH BIG BUSINESS.
AS YOU CAN SEE, A HYDRAULICS
FAILURE CAUSED THE CRASH.
OUR SYSTEM HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
THIS SO-CALLED REPORT
IS MEANINGLESS.
YOUR INVESTIGATORS HAVE HAD
MONTHS TO FALSIFY THIS DATA!
I GOT A GAME TO GET TO.
ANY MORE QUESTIONS,
YOU TALK TO MY LAWYER.
DANIEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
CRAWFORD HAD A PAINTING
OF THESE STARS
PROMINENTLY DISPLAYED
IN HIS CONFERENCE ROOM.
IT CAN'T BE A COINCIDENCE
THAT THE REPORTER WROTE DOWN
THE NAME "PLEIADES."
THERE HAS TO BE A PATTERN OR
A SYMBOL THAT MEANS SOMETHING.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
AM I LOOKING FOR?
MAYBE THE STARS ARE SIGNIFICANT
IN SOME OTHER WAY.
WHAT IS THEIR HISTORY?
WHERE DO THEIR NAMES COME FROM?
GREEK MYTHOLOGY.
THE PLEIADES WERE THE DAUGHTERS
OF ATLAS THE TITAN
AND SOME FLOOZY SEA NYMPH.
WHAT ELSE?
[ SIGHS ]
"ANCIENT ASTRONOMERS
ONCE BELIEVED
"THAT THE BRIGHTEST STAR
IN THE PLEIADES, ALCYONE,
"WAS THE CENTER
OF THE UNIVERSE,
AROUND WHICH ALL
THE HEAVENS REVOLVED."
"CENTER OF THE UNIVERSE."
DANIEL?
AH...
AL-CY-ON...
UH, FREEMASONS.
ILLUMINATI.
"THE ORDER OF ALCYONE --
ONE OF THE MOST ANCIENT
AND POWERFUL SECRET SOCIETIES."
UH, "SOME BELIEVE
THE ORDER'S SENIOR COUNCIL
"HAS MANIPULATED
WORLD EVENTS
"THROUGH THE APPOINTMENT
OF ITS MEMBERS
"TO POSITIONS OF POWER
AND INFLUENCE.
"THEIR ULTIMATE GOAL IS TO
CREATE A SINGLE WORLD GOVERNMENT
WITH THE ORDER ITSELF
AT THE CENTER OF THE UNIVERSE."
YOU DON'T BELIEVE
A SECRET SOCIETY
IS MURDERING CONGRESSMEN.
MAYBE!
MAYBE SOME -- SOME MODERN-DAY
CABAL OF BUSINESSMEN
LIKE CRAWFORD HAS ADOPTED
THE PHILOSOPHY OF THIS GROUP
AND THEY'RE TRYING TO INSTALL
THEIR OWN PEOPLE IN GOVERNMENT
TO SERVE THEIR
COMPANIES' INTERESTS.
NOW YOU'RE SEEING
THE BIG PICTURE, PROFESSOR.
A CUBAN -- REALLY?
I ENJOY THE IRONY.
NOW, THIS --
UH, THIS CONSPIRACY
WAS NEVER ABOUT
GETTING PAULSON OUT.
IT WAS ABOUT GETTING
HIS SUCCESSOR IN.
SCOTT RYLAND.
SOME VERY POWERFUL MEN
MUST HAVE WANTED RYLAND
IN THAT SENATE SEAT.
BUT KILLING PAULSON DOESN'T MAKE
HIS PROTéGé SENATOR.
THIS IS CHICAGO,
PROFESSOR.
REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED HERE
WHEN I RAN FOR THE WHITE HOUSE?
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
DANIEL?
IT'S 1960 ALL OVER AGAIN.
REMEMBER JFK's ELECTION?
THAT WAS A LITTLE
BEFORE MY TIME.
THERE WAS THIS MAFIA BOSS,
SAM GIANCANA.
THE RUMOR WAS,
HE STUFFED THE BALLOT
AND STOLE CHICAGO
FOR THE DEMOCRATS.
BUT IT'S A LOT EASIER TO STEAL
AN ELECTION THESE DAYS.
ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS PUSH A BUTTON.
"VERTERON ACQUIRES
DOVER ELECTION SOLUTIONS."
SO?
SO, IT TURNS OUT
CRAWFORD'S COMPANY
DOESN'T JUST MAKE AVIONICS.
EIGHT MONTHS AGO, THEY BOUGHT
INTO A NEW BUSINESS --
ELECTRONIC VOTING MACHINES.
THOSE [BLEEP] MURDERED PAULSON
AND RIGGED THE ELECTION.
THEY STOLE THAT SENATE SEAT
FOR SCOTT RYLAND.
DANIEL WAS RIGHT.
THE ELECTION RESULTS DON'T MATCH
UP WITH THE EXIT POLLING.
THE COUNTIES IN BLUE WERE
PREDICTED TO GO FOR RYLAND.
THE COUNTIES IN RED WERE
EXPECTED TO GO TO HIS OPPONENT.
LOOKS LIKE A LANDSLIDE.
EXCEPT THAT IS NOT
WHAT ACTUALLY HAPPENED.
THESE ARE THE COUNTIES
THAT RYLAND ACTUALLY WON.
Daniel: YOU SEE?
A SLIM ENOUGH MARGIN,
IT LOOKS LIKE A SQUEAKER.
WOULDN'T BE THE FIRST TIME
THE EXIT POLLS WERE WRONG.
AND EVEN IF THE RESULTS
WERE TAMPERED WITH,
HOW DO WE PROVE THAT?
WESLEY BELIEVED THAT A --
THAT A VERTERON ENGINEER,
BRIAN [FINGERS SNAP]
WILLINGHAM
GOT WIND OF CRAWFORD'S PLAN
AND TURNED UP DEAD --
UH, "SUICIDE."
MAYBE IF THIS WILLINGHAM
FIGURED IT OUT,
SOMEBODY ELSE
AT VERTERON DID, TOO.
WE NEED THE NAMES AND ADDRESSES
OF ALL THEIR EMPLOYEES,
ESPECIALLY THE ONES
IN THE ELECTION DIVISION.
I WAS WORKING LATE THE NIGHT
BEFORE THE VOTE.
I NOTICED THAT SOMEONE
HAD UPLOADED
SOME KIND OF SOFTWARE UPDATE
TO THE D.R.E. SERVERS.
D.R.E.?
DIRECT RECORDING
ELECTRONIC VOTING.
I DECOMPILED THE CODE,
AND I DISCOVERED A VIRUS
HIDDEN INSIDE.
[ SIGHS ]
IT WAS DESIGNED TO ALTER
THE VOTING TABULATION
ON EVERY MACHINE
THAT RECEIVED THE UPGRADE.
SO YOU TOLD BRIAN WILLINGHAM
WHAT YOU'D FOUND.
BRIAN WAS THE ONLY ONE
THAT I TRUSTED AT THE COMPANY.
[ SIGHS ]
HE STARTED ASKING
QUESTIONS.
BUT THE C.E.O. WOULDN'T EVEN
GIVE HIM THE TIME OF DAY.
SO...
[ SIGHS ]
HE HACKED INTO
CRAWFORD'S E-MAIL.
DID HE TELL YOU
WHAT HE FOUND?
HE WAS PRETTY CERTAIN
THAT CRAWFORD WAS BEHIND
THE WHOLE THING.
AND THERE WAS
SOMETHING ELSE.
HE SAID THAT HE READ
IN THE E-MAILS
THAT THERE WAS GOING TO BE
SOME KIND OF BIG MEETING
AT VERTERON --
SOME KIND OF
SENIOR COUNCIL.
A LOT OF IMPORTANT PEOPLE
WERE GOING TO BE THERE...
[ SIGHS ]
...INCLUDING SENATOR RYLAND.
DID HE TELL YOU WHEN THIS
MEETING WAS GONNA TAKE PLACE?
[ SIGHS ]
I DON'T KNOW -- SOMETIME
AFTER RYLAND WAS SWORN IN.
[ SIGHS ]
WOULD YOU BE WILLING TO TESTIFY
TO WHAT YOU'VE TOLD US?
YES.
IT'LL BE HER WORD
AGAINST HIS.
IF WE'RE GONNA GET CRAWFORD,
WE NEED HARD EVIDENCE.
I MADE A COPY OF THE VIRUS.
GET THIS DOWN TO CART
AND GET IT ANALYZED.
MRS. PAULSON DIED FROM
CONGESTIVE HEART FAILURE
BROUGHT ON BY ACUTE
RADIATION POISONING.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT KIND?
POLONIUM-210.
I FOUND MASSIVE TRACES
IN HER HAIR AND BONE MARROW.
SHOULD WE BE WEARING
LEAD SUITS?
POLONIUM'S ONLY DANGEROUS
IF INGESTED.
SHE CONSUMED ABOUT 10 MICROGRAMS
PROBABLY A WEEK AGO.
COULD THIS HAVE BEEN
AN ACCIDENT?
POLONIUM JUST DOESN'T EXIST
IN THESE QUANTITIES IN NATURE.
SHE WAS ASSASSINATED.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
MORETTI.
OKAY.
THAT WAS THE CART UNIT.
THE FLASH DRIVE
THAT JANICE GAVE US,
THERE'S NOTHING ON IT.
AFTER EVERYTHING
SHE TOLD US,
WHY WOULD SHE GIVE US
A BLANK FLASH DRIVE?
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY --
WHERE IS SHE NOW?
PROTECTIVE CUSTODY --
EMISSARY HOTEL.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
HOW LONG HAS SHE
BEEN IN THERE?
SHE SAID SHE WASN'T
FEELING WELL.
SHE WANTED TO TAKE
A NAP.
AN HOUR AGO, MAYBE.
OPEN THE DOOR.
[ LOCK BEEPS ]
JANICE!
WE'RE TOO LATE.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
SO?
SO,
I'VE BEEN REASSIGNED.
WHY?!
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
THAT JANICE
ALSO DIED FROM EXPOSURE
TO POLONIUM.
THAT'S BECAUSE CRAWFORD
OR SOMEBODY AT VERTERON
REALIZED SHE WAS A LOOSE END
AND POISONED HER.
WASHINGTON
ISN'T BUYING THAT.
THEY'RE CONSIDERING THIS
A PUBLIC HEALTH CRISIS.
THE PRIORITY RIGHT NOW
IS FINDING THE SOURCE
OF THE POLONIUM
SO THAT NO ONE ELSE
GETS SICK.
THESE WOMEN DIDN'T DIE
BECAUSE A RADIOISOTOPE
SEEPED INTO
THEIR TAP WATER.
IT'S LIKE WESLEY SAID --
ANYBODY THAT GETS CLOSE
TO THE TRUTH GETS KILLED.
DANIEL,
THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO.
WE CAN'T BACK OFF NOW,
KATE.
THINK ABOUT WHAT JANICE SAID
ABOUT THE -- THE BIG MEETING.
THAT COULD BE THE KEY TO
BREAKING THIS WHOLE CONSPIRACY.
WE HAVE NO IDEA WHEN THAT
MEETING IS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN.
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
IT ALREADY DID.
JFK: SHE'S ENTIRELY MISTAKEN,
PROFESSOR.
OF COURSE YOU KNOW
WHEN IT'S HAPPENING.
WHAT?
THE ANSWER
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR...
IS IN THE STARS.
THE MEETING IS TOMORROW MORNING,
JUST BEFORE SUNRISE.
YOU'RE GETTING ALL THIS
FROM AN ASTRONOMY BOOK?
THE PLEIADES.
REMEMBER, WE SAW THEM
IN CRAWFORD'S OFFICE,
AND ALCOTT WROTE IT
IN HIS NOTEBOOK.
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO
WITH WHAT TIME THE MEETING
IS SUPPOSED TO TAKE PLACE?
THE HELIACAL RISING.
LISTEN. LISTEN.
"THE PLEIADES ARE A GROUP
OF STARS THAT RISE EVERY DAY,
"JUST LIKE THE SUN,
"BUT ONE DAY A YEAR,
THEY RISE BEFORE DAWN
"AND ARE VISIBLE
ABOVE THE EASTERN HORIZON.
THIS FIRST APPEARANCE IS KNOWN
AS THE HELIACAL RISING,"
WHICH, THIS YEAR,
TAKES PLACE...
TOMORROW MORNING.
WE'VE GOT TO GET TO VERTERON
BEFORE DAWN.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
WE'RE GONNA FIGURE OUT
WHO ALL
THE CONSPIRATORS ARE.
DANIEL, I FEEL LIKE
THAT'S A LOT OF FAITH
TO PUT IN A SCRIBBLE
IN A NOTEBOOK.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
DANIEL PIERCE,
YOU ARE UNDER ARREST FOR
THE MURDER OF WESLEY SUMTER.
THIS VIDEO'S A FAKE.
NO, IT WAS JUST ENHANCED
BY THE CART UNIT.
I AM BEING SET UP!
OKAY.
WHO'S SETTING YOU UP?
I HAVEN'T
THE FAINTEST IDEA,
BUT IF YOU WANT TO SEARCH
MY HOUSE F-FOR A CROSSBOW,
BE MY GUEST.
DID YOU HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE OTHER DEATHS?
AREDAVID ALCOTT...S ]
BRIAN WILLINGHAM...
HELEN PAULSON.
SURE, SURE. YES, I-I-I-I HAVE
A SECRET STASH OF POLONIUM-210
IN MY MEDICINE CABINET.
KATE...
KATE, Y-YOU BELIEVE ME.
I-I-I DIDN'T --
I DIDN'T KILL WESLEY SUMTER
OR ANYBODY ELSE,
FOR THAT MATTER.
DANIEL, I KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT
CAPABLE OF HURTING ANYONE.
IF YOU WERE IN
THE RIGHT FRAME OF MIND.
BUT IT IS POSSIBLE
THAT YOU DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT YOU WERE DOING
WHEN YOU PULLED
THAT TRIGGER.
OH, KATE...
JFK: THERE'S A FOX
IN THE HENHOUSE, PROFESSOR.
THIS G-MAN WAS ONE
OF THE CONSPIRATORS.
PROBERT?
YEAH?
HE HAD CUSTODY OF THE DRIVE
THAT WAS MYSTERIOUSLY ERASED.
HE WAS FIRST ON THE SCENE
AFTER THE SNIPER KILLED
YOUR FRIEND.
YOU...
YOU MOVED WESLEY'S BODY.
DANIEL,
THIS ISN'T HELPING.
WHO ARE YOU WORKING FOR --
CRAWFORD, SENATOR RYLAND?
LOOK, PIERCE,
I KNOW THAT YOU THINK
I'VE ALWAYS HAD IT OUT
FOR YOU.
THE TRUTH IS,
I CARE ABOUT YOU.
BUT YOU ARE
A VERY SICK MAN.
NOW, WE'RE GONNA DO EVERYTHING
THAT WE CAN TO MAKE SURE
YOU GET THE VERY BEST LAWYER
SO THAT YOU CAN GET THE HELP
THAT YOU NEED.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
WHEN WE GET BACK, THE S.A.I.C.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THROWING AWAY ANY CHANCE
OF FUTURE PROMOTION.
DANIEL, YOU MIGHT BE CRAZY,
BUT YOU ARE NO KILLER.
THAT TAPE WAS DOCTORED.
I THOUGHT
YOU DIDN'T BELIEVE ME.
PROBERT WAS STANDING
RIGHT THERE.
I HAD TO PRETEND
TO AGREE WITH HIM.
HIT THE PARKING GARAGE,
WOULD YOU?
[ GRUNTS ]
GREAT.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO WITH HIM?
LET ME WORRY ABOUT THAT, OKAY?
NOW, YOU NEED TO LEAVE.
THAT DOOR WILL LET YOU OUT
INTO THE ALLEY.
YOU CAN'T.
I'M GOING TO VERTERON.
YOU'RE NOT GOING INTO
THAT BUILDING BY YOURSELF!
LISTEN, I'M JUST GONNA GO
INTO THE CONFERENCE ROOM
AND TRY TO PLANT A WIRE.
I'LL ONLY BE IN THERE
A FEW MINUTES.
DON'T YOU NEED A COURT ORDER
FOR THAT?
I JUST TASED MY PARTNER
AND DUMPED HIM IN A TRUNK!
I'M NOT EXACTLY DOING THINGS
BY THE BOOK TODAY!
LISTEN, JUST LAY LOW
FOR A FEW HOURS.
I WILL MEET YOU
IN MILLENNIUM PARK AT SUNRISE.
BUT, DANIEL, I...WAIT!
[ SIGHS ]
[ SIREN WAILS ]
SHE TOLD ME TO MEET HER
AT SUNRISE.
SHE SHOULD BE HERE
BY NOW.
RELAX, PROFESSOR.
SHE'S A PROFESSIONAL.
SHE'S GOT A LOT MORE ON THE BALL
THAN ANY OF HOOVER'S BOYS.
SHE'LL BE HERE.
[ SIGHS ] NO, NO, NO,
S-SOMETHING'S HAPPENED.
SHE'S IN TROUBLE.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
I'M GOING AFTER HER.
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU KNOW THE CODE.
ACTUALLY...
...I'M PRETTY SURE I DO.
[ BEEPING ]
PLEIADES.
OF COURSE.
[ LOCK DISENGAGES ]
Ryland: THANKS TO
YOUR UNWAVERING SUPPORT,
I NOW STAND BEFORE YOU
AS A UNITED STATES SENATOR.
THIS VICTORY BELONGS
TO EVERYONE HERE
AT THIS HISTORIC CONFERENCE.
AND IT BRINGS US
ONE STEP CLOSER
TO ACHIEVING
OUR ULTIMATE OBJECTIVE --
DOMINION OVER
THE AFFAIRS OF...
OH.
THIS IS AN UNEXPECTED
SURPRISE.
MR. PRESIDENT, IT'S A PLEASURE
TO FINALLY MEET YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
PLEASURE'S MINE,
SENATOR.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
GOING ON HERE?
SIR, YOU'LL HAVE TO
COME WITH ME.
GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME.
LET GO OF ME!
I KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON HERE!
YOU'RE NOT FOOLING ANYONE!
YOU'RE A MURDERER, CRAWFORD!
YOU'RE A KILLER!
YOU'RE ALL KILLERS!
THE WORLD IS GONNA KNOW!
IT'S ME.
LISTEN, IT'S ME!
YOU'RE A MURDERER, CRAWFORD!
DOC, IT'S MAX.
I KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON
IN THIS ROOM!
THE WORLD WILL KNOW!
DOC, LISTEN, PLEASE!
LISTEN TO ME, DOC!
IT'S MAX!ALCYONE!
LOOK AT ME!
LOOK AT ME.
IT'S MAX --
MAX LEWICKI, DOC.
MAX?
HOW DID YOU --
I'M HERE, DOC.
OKAY? YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
J[ GASPS ]
I'VE GOT YOU.
I'VE GOT YOU, DOC, OKAY?
HOW DID I GET HERE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, DOC?
YOU'RE HOME.
NO, NO, NO.
I WAS DOWNTOWN JUST --
JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO!
DOC, I...I THINK
YOU'RE CONFUSED.
NO, NO, I'M NOT,
I'M NOT.
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
HAPPENED?
NO.
[ MUMBLES ]
I DON'T KNOW.
DOC, I JUST GOT HOME.
DANIEL?
KATE!
OH, KATE!
THANK GOD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
I WAS SO WORRIED
ABOUT YOU.
WHY?
WHY DID YOU NOT MEET ME
AT MILLENNIUM PARK?
MILLENNIUM PARK?
I WENT IN THE BUILDING
TO FIND YOU.
I KNOW YOU SAID NOT TO,
BUT THEN --
T-THEY MUST HAVE DRUGGED ME.
THEY MUST HAVE DRUGGED ME
BECAUSE THE NEXT THING I KNEW,
I-I-I WAS HERE.
I-I WAS HOME.
DANIEL,
THE LAST TIME I SAW YOU
WAS WHEN I DROVE YOU HOME
FROM THE UNIVERSITY
AFTER WE LOOKED
FOR WESLEY'S BODY.
THAT WAS TWO DAYS AGO.
YOU REMEMBER THAT?
YES, I REMEMBER THAT!
AND THEN YOU --
THEN YOU CAME BACK
THAT AFTERNOON,
AND YOU G-- YOU HAD THAT --
T-T-THE -- THIS.
HERE, HERE.
PLAY IT. PLAY IT.
JUST PLAY IT!
IT'S A RECORDING
O-O-OF THE SNIPER
O-ON THAT DISK.
A STUDENT -- A STUDENT
CAUGHT IT ON HIS CELLPHONE.
AND THEN PROBERT --
PROBERT, WITH
HIS COMPUTER TRICKERY --
PUT MY HEAD ON THE
SNIPER'S BODY -- TELL HIM!
SURE, DANIEL,
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
[ SNIFFS ]
WHAT THE [BLEEP] IS THIS?
IT'S AN fMRI SCAN.
YOU WANTED ME
TO BURN IT TO A DVD
SO YOU COULD SHOW IT
IN CLASS.
[ GASPS ]
COME ON, DOC.
I...
COME ON, DOC,
LET'S GET YOU WASHED UP.
KATE...
JUST GO WITH MAX.
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
IIT'S OKAY.
I-I-I'M NOT AN INVALID,
LEWICKI.
I'M CAPABLE
OF WASHING MYSELF.
DOC, I'D RA--
GIVE ME A LITTLE
TIME ALONE, PLEASE.
I'D RATHER STAY
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST I-I-I'M NOT GONNA
HURT MYSELF, OKAY?
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT.
PLEASE,
JUST GET THE [BLEEP] OUT.
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
SOME OF THESE
ARE ARTICLES
DANIEL SAID
HIS FRIEND WESLEY GAVE HIM.
DOC'S BEEN BUSY.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
HE'S LEFT THE HOUSE
SINCE YOU DROPPED HIM OFF.
[ WATER RUNNING ]
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
[ GRUNTS ]
DANIEL, YOU NEED HELP.
THIS IS A MAJOR
ESCALATION.
IT'S ONE THING TO HAVE VISIONS
OF JOHN KENNEDY,
BUT YOU'VE SPENT THE ENTIRE
WEEKEND IN A DELUSIONAL STATE.
[ SIGHS ]
I MUST HAVE KNOWN [SNIFFS]
ON SOME LEVEL
THAT IT WASN'T REAL.
T-THAT'S -- THAT'S WHY I MADE
MYSELF SNAP OUT OF IT.
BULL[BLEEP]
YOU'D STILL BE WANDERING
THE HOUSE,
TALKING TO THE WALLS IF MAX
HADN'T COME HOME WHEN HE DID.
WHAT IF HE'D LEFT
FOR A WEEK?
WHAT WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
TO YOU THEN?
I SHOULD HAVE STARTED
TAKING THESE WEEKS AGO
WHEN I HAD THE PRESCRIPTION
FILLED, BUT...
I CONVINCED MYSELF
I DIDN'T NEED THEM.
IT'S TOO LATE TO START THIS
ON YOUR OWN.
YOU NEED TO GO
TO THE HOSPITAL.
I DO THAT, THEY'RE GONNA
PUT ME ON SOMETHING
A LOT STRONGER
THAN THESE.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT
YOU NEED.
WHAT I NEED...
IS TO BE WITH YOU.
TRYING TO KEEP ME AROUND IS
WHAT GOT YOU INTO THIS MESS.
FOR THE SAKE
OF YOUR SANITY
AND EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT YOU CARE ABOUT,
YOU NEED TO LET ME GO.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[ BREATHES SHAKILY ]
[ CRYING ]
THAT WESLEY GUY --
DOC GOT A LETTER
FROM HIM RIGHT BEFORE I LEFT,
AND...NOW HE'S DEAD?
FRANKLY, MAX,
I'M NOT EVEN SURE
THAT "WESLEY"
WAS A REAL PERSON.
I SPENT THE WEEKEND
TRACKING DOWN
EVERY WESLEY SUMTER
IN NORTH AMERICA.
NONE OF THEM
EVER ATTENDED CLMU
OR LIVED WITHIN 200 MILES
OF CHICAGO.
EXCUSE ME.
CAN SOMEONE
PLEASE GIVE ME A RIDE?
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
CAN I HELP YOU?
MY NAME IS
DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
I'M A PARANOID SCHIZOPHRENIC,
AND I NEED TO BE ADMITTED.
Probert: YOU'RE NOT
GONNA BELIEVE THE VIDEO
THAT POPPED UP ON THE INTERNET
AN HOUR AGO.
ROGER, I'M NOT REALLY
IN THE MOOD
FOR TALKING CATS
RIGHT NOW.
NO, NO, NO.
TRUST ME, YOU WANT TO SEE THIS.
Wesley:
MY NAME IS WESLEY SUMTER.
I'VE ARRANGED FOR THIS VIDEO
TO BE RELEASED
ONLY IN THE EVENT
OF MY DEMISE.
IF YOU ARE WATCHING THIS,
THEN I HAVE ALREADY
BEEN KILLED.