Subs created by: David Coleman.
The one day of the week..
No lectures, no office hours,
- no obligations of any kind..
- Doc..
The one day that I.. I get
a little solitude, you know,
a little "me" time, a chance
to do some actual writing.
Haley twisted my arm.
Your arm is mine to twist, not Haley's.
Did he even say what this was about?
Daniel, it is my honor to inform
you that you have been awarded
this year's Davenport Prize
for exploration in science.
I.. I swear, I knew nothing about this.
And, as I'm sure you are aware,
this award is not just about
the laurels you bring to
yourself and the university.
It's also about the $50,000
check that goes along with it.
Woo!
To Daniel Pierce.
Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Daniel.
How could you blindside me like that?
You are making me look bad
in front of the Chancellor.
The man put you up for this
prize, for goodness sakes.
Just one handshake.
That's all I'm asking.
Kate.
Please tell me you're here about a case.
- Yes, I am, but this..
- Ms. Moretti,
I agreed to allow Daniel
to consult with the FBI
so long as it didn't interfere
with his academic duties.
And right now you are interfering with..
Actually, I'm here to talk to you.
To me?
Yeah, listen, a jogger
was found shot in the back
in the national forest preserve.
We're having trouble making an I.D.
There's no wallet on him,
no match on the fingerprints.
What has this got to do with him?
All we've got to go on
are some tattoos on the
body which appear to
be religious in nature,
and Dean Haley's course
on spiritual iconography
was one of the best classes I ever took.
I'm flattered you remember.
Anyhow, I'm hoping you could
take a look at the tattoos,
let me know if there's anything about
them that could help me I.D. the victim.
I confess I've always been
something of an armchair Detective.
Paul, you couldn't
possibly. The Chancellor.
I just tell him that it's a
murder investigation, right?
Come on, Daniel. You'll need to
keep him entertained while I'm gone.
Help me.
Wh.. Uh, Dean Haley, uh, actually,
our victim may have
suffered some head injuries,
so I do need a brain
specialist to review the X-rays.
You couldn't possibly spare
Daniel, uh, just for an hour?
I'm sure the Chancellor will understand.
This is very exciting.
Oh.
Probably a little too much
bubbly at the reception, I think.
Okay. Um, let's see what we've got here.
Well, the Angel appears to draw
from Christian influences, but..
These eight wings..
Probably represent the
eight arms of Shiva..
The Hindu God of destruction.
Ah. Uh-huh.
Which would make this simian
figure representative of Hanuman.
The Hindu monkey God.
And I'd say these numbers
represent the book of Ruth..
Chapter 1, verse 16.
"Thy people shall be my people".
The words Naomi spoke when converting
to the faith of her Mother-in-law.
So, you probably want to make
inquiries at a local Hindu temple
frequented by converts from
the Judeo-Christian tradition.
You might want to inquire
at a local methadone clinic.
Why do you say that?
I think it's a pretty safe bet
your victim here was a junkie.
"Monkey on my back," is a
common term for heroin addiction.
1:16 is probably a sobriety date, which
a lot of addicts tattoo on their bodies.
If he got sober with
the help of methadone,
maybe somebody at a
clinic would recognize him.
Of course, I don't want to..
Contradict the expert.
I'm here about your son, Mrs. Baker.
What's Jared done now?
Well, he's listed you
as his emergency contact
on his intake form at the
7th street methadone clinic.
Your son's body was found
yesterday in the forest preserve.
It appears he was
murdered. I'm.. Very sorry.
Thank you for bringing
me the news in person.
I always thought I would get a
call in the middle of the night.
You were expecting this?
I tried everything..
Therapists, rehab, a
clinic in Switzerland.
But when he turned 21 and came
into his grandfather's trust,
he had money for all the
drugs he could possibly desire.
When was the last time you saw him?
Four months ago, maybe five.
Okay.
And do you know where he was living?
With some kind of religious cult.
It bled him of every
last cent he had left.
He said he found the voice of God
and was finally getting clean.
Some good the voice of God did him.
It's called Haven House.
Looks like some sort of commune.
It's all centered around this kid..
Kyle Jensen.
16 years old.
They say he talks directly to God.
And your victim gave all
his money to this wacko cult?
Almost $500,000.
What?!
That's the way it works.
Everyone who joins gives
every dime they have.
It's a haven, all right, for
anybody with money in the bank
and no brain in their skull.
I swear, it.. It.. It.. It staggers me.
Millennium after millennium, no matter
how many of these charlatans are unmasked..
People keep shoveling gold into
the pockets of the next crook
who claims to speak in the name of
some nonexistent Santa Claus in the sky.
It's unbelievable.
I thought you'd be interested.
Do you want to tag along?
Try and stop me.
Hi. Are you here for Kyle?
He'll be talking to everybody
in just a couple of minutes.
We're with the FBI.
The FBI? Is there something wrong?
We'd like to talk to
whoever's in charge.
Well, nobody's really in charge.
Um, this is Tom and Sandy's house,
but they're in with Kyle right now.
Could this wait till he's finished?
He really likes to tell us what God said
to him while it's still fresh in his head.
Any chance we could listen to
the word of God while we wait?
Everyone is welcome.
Behave yourself, Daniel.
It's wonderful to see all of you here.
So many new faces here today.
I'm Tom Shelby, and, uh,
this is my wife, Sandy.
Hi, everybody.
And, uh..
These are the two boys I was
lucky enough to get in the
package deal when I married her..
Greg and Kyle.
Uh, now, as much as I'd
like to believe otherwise,
I know you didn't come
to hear me flap my jaw,
so I'm gonna shut up and
turn the floor over to Kyle.
Hmm.
Thanks, Tom. Um..
God picks the craziest times to tap
me on the shoulder and start talking.
Today, it was while I was doing the
dishes, and I want to apologize to my Mom
for the pitcher I dropped
when I checked out.
Today, God talked to me about doubt.
And how important it is for
us not to be scared of it.
He said he gave us doubt
so that we'd always be
trying to figure out
how things really work,
you know, and how we
can make them better.
Now, there are people in
this room who have no doubt.
And that is a beautiful thing.
But God also talked to me about how being
too sure of anything can be dangerous.
And there is somebody
here who has only doubt..
Who doesn't believe at all.
But I'm really glad he's here.
Jared was such a beautiful person.
When was the last time you saw him?
About 6:00 just yesterday morning.
He.. He went out on his jog.
And you didn't wonder why he
didn't come home last night?
No. Everybody here is
free to come and go.
- Okay.
- I was worried, actually.
He said he'd been seeing his old friends
from K-town, where he used to score.
I.. I was scared that he
might be going back to drugs.
Did he mention any of
these old friends by name?
Mm. No.
Shane.
- Who?
- Shane Flannery.
Um he used to live here.
Well, turned out, he
was kind of a fanatic.
He didn't think we were
doing enough to protect Kyle.
He thought we were letting
in the scum of the Earth..
Addicts and prostitutes
and all kinds of sinners.
That's who comes in
need of God's healing.
Shane threatened to burn
us all alive in the house.
Jared asked him to leave, and when
he refused, Jared threw him out.
Yeah, and when he left, he was ranting
about Jared paying for his sins.
Okay. Well, we'll
certainly look into it.
Jared Baker signed over his
entire trust fund to you.
Half a million dollars.
What'd you do with the money?
Everything we take in
goes to the shelter,
the food bank, or the
school in Afghanistan.
Did Jared ever question how you
were spending his inheritance?
I.. I don't know what
you're insinuating.
If you're implying that we
had something to do with..
Tom, it's okay.
People give us their money because of
the first thing God ever said to me.
"I only ask for one thing.. Everything".
"But in exchange, I give everything".
I came here with nothing..
Just a coke habit and a lot of fear..
And these people took
me in like a daughter.
And God kept his promise.
He gave me everything.
Even the man that I'm going to marry.
You need to find Shane Flannery.
If he did kill Jared Baker,
he might kill somebody else.
Yes. Shane Flannery.
Uh-huh. I'm e-mailing a
photo and a description.
I want every man on it we can spare.
Great.
I'm gonna stick around.
I want to talk to Kyle.
About what?
I'm just curious about something.
Kyle?
Do you have a minute?
Sure.
How did you know that
I was a nonbeliever?
Did, uh, God tell you that?
I could just see it in your face.
It takes work not to believe
in God, and the effort shows.
I think it takes a lot more effort
to believe in something you can't see.
Are you kidding?
How could anybody look
at something so perfect
and beautiful and delicious and think
that it got that way by accident?
Well, there's a scientific
answer to that, Kyle.
Earlier versions of the raspberry
weren't so beautiful and delicious,
so they couldn't attract enough
birds to spread their seeds around.
I know how evolution works.
I love Darwin.
He was the first person in history
to look behind the curtain and see
how God actually makes it all work.
When did God first start talking to you?
When I was 12.
But you're not fooling me.
I know you think I'm either totally
full of it or just plain crazy.
And so did my parents, at first.
W.. What does it feel like
when you're hearing God's voice?
It's beautiful.
Everything kind of disappears.
It's like I'm asleep and
awake at the same time.
Do you get headaches when that happens?
Feel nauseated?
Yeah. How did you know?
Just a hunch.
Well, anyway, it's totally worth it
because I also get this
amazing, like, euphoria.
Hmm.
Headaches, nausea, euphoria, voices..
These are classic symptoms
of temporal lobe epilepsy,
which could be caused by a tumor.
I.. I don't understand.
He has a check-up every year, and
his Doctor has never said anything.
Did you ever take him to a neurologist?
There was no reason to.
He's in perfect health.
I'm sorry, but he's not.
This kind of tumor can also press
on neighboring areas of the brain.
It can be life-threatening
if it's not treated,
of Kyle could have a
seizure while he's driving.
I'd like to bring him in for some tests.
And if they show what I think
they'll show, he may need surgery.
Well, I.. I could bring
him in tomorrow when..
Mom, wait.
Are you saying this condition is
what's making me hear God's voice?
It's not God, Kyle.
It's a neurological abnormality.
Well, if it is, God
must have given it to me
so he could have a way to talk to me.
I'm not getting rid of it.
This could be a fatal condition.
Being alive is a fatal condition.
- Kyle.
- I'm not doing it, Mom.
Mrs. Shelby, I understand
Kyle's commitment to his beliefs,
but he is still a minor. You
can compel him to get treatment.
Dr. Pierce, we'll
discuss what you've said.
We'll talk to Kyle about it.
But we are not gonna force him
to do anything against his will.
This is child abuse!
They're not forcing him to get tested
because they don't want the goose
to stop laying the golden eggs.
It's what I've always said.. Religion.
And, you know, if it's not
about blood or oppression,
it's about money in the bank.
That is a gross generalization,
not to mention totally offensive.
I mean, what about the Dalai Lama or..
Or Martin Luther King?
Or the Inquisition or
9/11 or Giordano Bruno?
- Who?
- Oh, they didn't teach you about him
in Sunday school? 1592..
Giordano Bruno makes
the wild, satanic claim
that the Earth revolves around the
sun, so the Holy Fathers pray to God
and are told that this
wicked man must die.
They clamp his tongue to the roof of
his mouth, and they burn him alive,
which must have been the right thing
to do because God told them to do it.
Look, yes, that is a horrible story, but
Haven House isn't burning people alive.
You made a snap diagnosis after
talking to that kid for five minutes.
You don't think that that might be
your prejudice against religion talking?
I.. I didn't make the condition up.
- It's what Joan of Arc had.
- What?
Joan of Arc had temporal lobe epilepsy.
It's why she thought that
Angels were talking to her.
Oh, did you examine her, too?
It's the conclusion
of medical historians
based on her description
of her own experience.
And we all know what happened to her.
Yes. She became a great
leader. She liberated France.
She was burned at the stake at age 19.
She was a deluded girl whose
illness led to her disaster.
She was a hero.
At a time when women had less power
than farm animals, she led an army.
I used to carry her
medal when I was a kid,
and I still light candles
in church for her on Sunday.
- You still go to church?
- Yes, Daniel, I do.
And I pray, too, if you want to know.
Why?
Because I believe in God.
It comforts me to talk
to him about my problems.
And does he answer you
back like he does with Kyle?
Okay. You know what? I do not have time
to get into a theological debate with you.
I need to find Shane Flannery.
Which is exactly what our friends
at Haven House want you to be doing.
How do you know that Jared Baker
didn't just get pissed off one day
that his entire trust fund
was going into their pockets,
so he tried to get it back,
and they offed him for it?
Because the I.R.S. is
all over places like that.
Oh, and nothing ever
gets past Uncle Sam.
All right, fine, if it would make you feel
better, I will put in a call to the I.R.S.
But my money is on Shane.
I was exactly where you are, Dr. Pierce.
I was positive a place raking in that
kind of cash had to be a scam but..
I've been tearing their books
apart at the seams for two years.
And I got to tell you, it's legit.
We're talking about millions of
dollars. Where is it all going?
Well, about 2% goes to administrative
expenses, which is as low
as it gets in nonprofit-land,
and some goes to local charities..
Food bank, meals on wheels, shelter.
Biggest chunk goes to
the school in Afghanistan.
- Moretti.
- Isn't it possible they're fooling you?
That.. That they're cooking the books?
I'd like to think, after 20 years in this
place, that I'm a pretty hard guy to fool.
CPD just found our suspect.
Thank you.
Mr. Flannery, did you threaten
to burn down Haven House,
send all its residents to hell?
I spoke the truth.
I said that God would bring the fire
of his vengeance down on that house.
Did you specifically
threaten to kill Jared Baker?
It was God who delivered
his judgment on that heretic.
Okay. Where were you
last Tuesday morning?
Across the street from Haven
House, guarding the chosen one..
I was there all night.
Can anyone verify that?
Only God, who will purify
all the sinners in that house
with the fires of his vengeance..
Starting with those who trample
on the seventh commandment.
Okay, I'm a little
rusty on my commandments,
but I think I remember
which one the seventh is.
Now, who in the house
was committing adultery?
That lying whore Nikki.
She's engaged to Kyle's brother,
so why was she rutting like
a sow with the dead man?
Okay, so, you're saying Nikki was
rutting like a sow with Jared Baker?
It was after midnight.
I saw the light go on in his window.
She came into his room
and took him in her arms.
Maybe Kyle's brother saw what I saw.
Maybe God entrusted him with
the fire of his vengeance.
He is not the killer.
Have you ever met a Holy Warrior
who shot his victim in the back?
Normally, they burn their
victims or crucify them
or ritually drain their blood.
She's chasing the wrong cat.
I was sent to help you
catch the right one.
What do you mean, "sent"? Who sent you?
God, of course.
Messenger of God.
French accent.
Late Medieval, homespun Tunic.
Great.
I'm hallucinating Joan of Arc.
Enchanté.
Evil is in the eye of the beholder.
Especially if that
beholder is Shane Flannery.
So, you admit that you were
in Jared's room that night?
Yes, but not for anything sinful.
Jared needed my help.
At 2:00 in the morning?
My room is right next door to his.
I woke up. I heard him crying.
I was worried, so I went
and knocked on his door.
Do you think that your fiancé might
have seen you knock on his door?
No. Greg.. Greg's room
is downstairs in the back.
Jared was in a terrible state.
He told me he had been
seeing his friends in K-town
and that he was worried he might slip.
So we prayed together. I held him.
He read that the wrong
way and made a pass at me.
I told him I would never betray
Greg, and I went back to my room.
Why didn't you tell
us any of this before?
I told you that I thought
Jared was having a rough time.
I didn't tell you the rest
because Greg loved Jared.
It would have only
upset him, and for what?
Hey. I heard you guys were back.
- Did you find Shane?
- Yes.
- But we don't think he did it.
- Daniel.
We're not really supposed to
discuss an open investigation.
Well, what were you
talking to Nikki about?
Does she know something?
Kyle, I..
Okay.
Dr. Pierce, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Not about the case.
I'll be in the car.
What's on your mind?
A while ago, God told me I wasn't
gonna be alive for very long.
I guess he's saying
the same thing you are.
You know I don't believe in God, Kyle.
But if a gut instinct is
telling you you're not well,
you should listen to
it and get treatment.
I'm not doing that.
I just want to know how
long I have so I can..
You know, make plans.
Your condition isn't always fatal.
And there's no way to
predict how long it'll take
any illness to cause someone's death.
So, science doesn't
have all the answers?
I suppose not.
That's okay.
Neither does God.
He spends most of his time trying to figure
out why we do the crazy things we do.
That's why he made brain
scientists like you..
To help him figure it all out.
Hey. Sorry to interrupt. I
need to get back to the office.
What's going on?
CPD found a witness in K-town
who said they saw a guy roughing
up Jared Baker a few days ago.
We're looking for him now.
Listen, um..
Call me anytime about your health or..
Just to talk.
Thanks.
I'll do that.
How could such an intelligent,
level-headed kid be so Medieval at heart?
Not to mention Kate.
Daniel, that man who's music you're
playing was a devout believer.
Bach lived 300 years ago.
Science was in the cradle.
Isn't science just another kind of faith
with its own scriptures
and its own dogmas?
Science is based on fact.
It must be exhausting to
be so cynical all the time.
It's not cynicism.. It's reality.
And, of course, we all know what
a firm grip you have on reality.
Oh, that's very funny.
I think you're jealous
of people with faith.
You wish you could find that
kind of solace and comfort.
Listen to that treble.
Hmm? Like a chicken
screaming for its life.
I've seen you looking longingly
at a satin-finish ebony grand
in the Steinway showroom downtown.
Yeah, well, that particular satin-finish
ebony grand costs as much as most cars.
Daniel, you just got
a check for $50,000.
You can buy anything you want with it.
That would be an insane indulgence.
You've done crazier things.
You really think I should buy it?
Hey, Doc. Kyle Jensen's
Mother is on the phone.
She sounds pretty upset.
Kyle runs up and down
those stairs 20 times a day.
He must have gone into one
of his trances and fallen.
Why would God choose a moment like that?
Mr. and Mrs. Shelby..
Kyle suffered a major
head trauma in the fall,
causing his brain to bleed.
In a way, the fall may have
been fortunate because the scan
revealed something we might not
have caught until it was too late.
Kyle has an invasive tumor
in his left temporal lobe.
It's possible the fall dislodged it,
which is what's causing
the severe bleeding.
Lord in heaven.
That's what you told us yesterday.
We should have listened
to you. We should have..
We should have brought him in for tests.
I need to operate immediately to
relieve the pressure from the bleeding.
If we can remove the tumor, we will.
Kyle made it clear that he
didn't want to do anything
that might cut him off from God.
You can't leave a dislodged
tumor inside your son's brain.
I'm just thinking of
what Kyle would want.
You might as well shoot him in the head!
Daniel.
Dr. Pierce is right.
I know Kyle may be angry with me,
but I am not going to lose my son.
We'll prep him for surgery.
Doctor, did..
Did Kyle have elevated
Prolactin levels when he came in?
No. They were normal, but
need to get started, so..
What was that about?
Elevated Prolactin would
mean that Kyle had a seizure
in the last couple of
hours, but he didn't.
So he didn't fall because
he went into a trance.
Maybe he figured out who killed Jared.
And someone pushed him.
Did any of you see Kyle fall?
I was in the den,
reading, and.. And, uh..
Heard a crash and ran into the foyer.
Jake and Tina came to my room
and told me what happened.
I was making dinner, and
I heard Tom yell for help.
When I saw him on the
ground, all that blood, I..
Excuse me.
Moretti.
Why's she asking all these questions?
Nobody in the house
would want to hurt Kyle.
Are you sure about that?
Daniel.
They found the guy who
beat up Jared in K-town.
- We got to go.
- What about Kyle?
Well, the family will call
us if there's any news.
No, I mean about protecting him.
Somebody tried to kill
him. They may try again.
You.. You got to put a guard on him.
Daniel, I'm not gonna be able
to get approval for a guard
on a hospital room 24/7 just because
we have an unsubstantiated theory.
Well, I'm staying.
All right.
Are you saying that
I killed Jared Baker?
Witnesses saw you two
get into a shoving match
a few days before he was murdered.
Look, I do outreach for the V.A.
And we get a lot of these vets
living on the street around here.
So, yeah, it pisses me off
when these jackasses come down
and try to scam these guys
out of their SDI checks.
Jared Baker was scamming veterans?
Passing out pamphlets, hawking some church
that's about donating every cent they got..
So I tossed his pamphlets and told
him to take his scam elsewhere.
And then when he didn't get
the message, you got physical.
After he took off, I felt
bad about the whole thing,
so I fished one of the pamphlets
out of the trash and took a look.
And guess what.. I was right.
It's all a big fake.. At least
the school in Afghanistan is.
That place does not exist.
How do you know that?
Picture in the pamphlet.
Schoolkids in front of a big lake?
School's supposed to be in Maimana.
I was stationed in Herat,
a stone's throw from there.
There's no lake in
that valley, just sand.
This picture?
Yeah.
See the writing on the blackboard?
That's Farsi.
In Maimana, they speak Arabic.
I called a bunch of guys
who served over there.
Nobody ever heard of
an international group
operating a school
anywhere near Maimana.
You report this to anyone?
Just Jared Baker.
Wait. Jared knew?
Next time he came down to K-town, I
told him exactly what I just told you.
How did he take it?
It shook him up. He said he
wanted to report it to somebody,
so I told him he should
start with the I.R.S.
The I.R.S. gave Haven House
a clean bill of health.
Last-minute vacation, Ethan?
We removed the tumor
and stopped the bleeding.
But there were complications.
Kyle suffered a ruptured aneurysm.
He's in a coma.
Oh, my God.
- Will he be all right?
- The situation doesn't look good.
Could he die?
I think you need to prepare
yourselves for that possibility.
I'm sorry.
- Can we see him?
- Sure. I'll take you in.
It is a pity..
N'est-ce pas?
They call you "the messenger," right?
Well, I want you to
deliver a message to God.
I thought you don't believe in him.
I don't.
But you do, so I want you to tell him
from me that I think he's an asshole
that is blasphemy, Daniel. It is a sin.
No. No. No.
A sin.. A sin is giving
a brain tumor to a..
To a kid who's never done
a bad thing in his life.
A sin is letting whoever killed Jared
Baker run free while that boy lies dying.
Does.. What does.. Does God enjoy this?
Watching mothers sobbing their eyes out?
What is that, his thing?
Is that entertaining to him?
What are we? Is that what we
are.. Some sort of entertainment?
Give him the message. T.. Tell
him. Go on. Tell him.. Tell him..
Tell him to go to hell.
That audit is accurate to
the best of my knowledge.
What about your knowledge of the seven
cash deposits made into your account,
each in the amount of
$9,900, just a squeak below
what the bank would
be required to report?
I won that money playing poker.
I see.
And with your poker
winnings, you decided to
buy yourself a one-way
ticket to the Maldives,
a country that just happens to have no
extradition treaty with The United States?
I always wanted to go there.
Jail is nothing like
the Maldives, Ethan.
There are no crystal-clear
waters, no palm trees,
no waiters fetching you
brightly colored drinks.
I want full immunity.
That's not gonna happen.
But if you give me the name of whoever
bribed you to falsify this audit,
I'll ask the Judge to let you plead
down to receiving improper benefits.
You'd get off with six months.
This offer expires in 10 seconds.
Nine..
Eight..
Three..
Okay, okay, okay.
I took a bribe.
Who from?
Mr. Shelby, could I speak
to you in the hallway?
What's this about?
It would be best if we spoke outside.
Anything you have to say, you
can say in front of my family.
I'm placing you under arrest
for the murder of Jared Baker.
- What are you talking about?
- That's insane!
- You have the right to remain silent.
- No, let go of him!
- Sandy, don't.
- I'm coming with you.
No. Stay here with Kyle.
I can stay here with
Kyle. Greg, take your Mom.
No, everybody stay here, please.
God knows the truth.
He'll set everything right.
Do you understand these rights
as they have been read to you?
So, how do you.. How
do you know Tom did it?
Picked up the I.R.S.
auditor on his way to the
airport with a one-way
ticket to the Maldives.
Said Tom bribed him for a clean audit.
You were right. Tom was
pocketing all the money.
Okay, but why kill Jared?
Well, Jared was on to the scam.
Tom found that out the
night before the murder.
Look, we got to get going. I'll
tell you all about it in the car.
W.. W.. You're sure that
no one else is in on it?
Until you're sure,
I'm staying with Kyle.
Why would I kill Jared? I loved him.
We got a warrant to search
your house, including your safe,
and we found records of the cash
payments you made to the I.R.S. auditor.
I swear to God I never
gave him anything.
He told us about how you did your research
on him when he first started the audit.
You knew that he had
alimony, gambling debts.
You knew that if you offered him a bribe
for a clean audit, that he'd take it.
He's lying.
We also found the incorporation
documents for the shell organization
that runs the fake
school in Afghanistan.
What are you talking
about? The school is real.
The State Department has no record
of a foreign charity
operating a school in Maimana.
We send them almost $1 million a year.
No, you send almost $1 million a year
to an account in your
name at the Bank of Kabul.
From Kabul, it's transferred to
the ever-popular Cayman Islands.
Now I know why you were so eager
to put us onto Shane Flannery.
No. I would never do that.
You were raking it in like crazy,
until Jared Baker found out
that the school was fake.
And he called Ethan over at the I.R.S.
Ethan called you and
said you had a problem.
And then, according to
Ethan, your exact words were..
"I'll take care of it".
I guess you did.
I need to find Tom a lawyer.
Sandy, let Greg make the calls.
You need to rest.
She's right, Mom. Let me take you home.
No. I can't leave Kyle.
I'll be right here. I'll call
you the second he wakes up.
I'll stay, too.
- Thank you, Nikki.
- Sure.
And thank you, Dr. Pierce.
Dr. Pierce, if it's all right..
I'd like some time alone..
To pray.
Of course she wants time alone..
Because as soon as you leave the room..
She is going to kill the boy.
Nikki, if it's all the same to you..
I'm gonna stay.
Look at her.
The soul of piety and devotion.
But doesn't it bother you
how eager she has been to
get everybody out of the room?
The boy was very curious as
to why you were talking to her.
Maybe he had asked too many questions..
And she pushed him.
And think..
Think of that tax man
flying off to the Maldives.
Of all the countries in the world,
why would he choose a
romantic tropical island?
Unless he wasn't planning
to go there alone.
Yes, she is very beautiful, no?
Just the perfect type of woman
a lonely tax man would
dream of running away with.
That's still not proof.
What?
N.. nothing.
It's hardly enough to get
her burned at the stake,
but it's more than
the British had on me.
Please, Dr. Pierce, I'd really
like some time alone with Kyle.
What are you going to do?
What? W.. What is that?
Why is it making that sound?
He's gone.
Wh.. What are you talking
about? No. He's breathing.
This monitors neuroelectrical activity.
Kyle's brain-dead.
Oh, my God.
I.. I.. I have to call his parents.
Oh, sorry. I must have, uh,
knocked this out by mistake.
- Moretti.
- Tom isn't the killer.
- It's Nikki.
- What?
She says she loves Kyle.
But when he died, she
didn't even look at him.
She just took off
like a bat out of hell.
Oh, my God. Kyle died?
No, no, no, no. That
was just pretend. Wha..
Daniel, what are you talking about?
It was all Nikki. Killing Jared,
pushing Kyle down the stairs.
She's been waiting to get him
alone so she can finish the job.
You've got to stop her
before she leaves the country.
Do you have any proof of this?
N.. N.. No, but..
Okay, then we need to put a tail on her,
find out where she's
headed in such a hurry.
Right.
Hey, need a hand with those?
I already told you the whole story.
The problem is that Nikki Atkins
is telling us a different version.
And in hers..
The Afghan scam, framing Tom
Shelby, murdering Jared Baker..
That was all you.
She says you blackmailed
her into going along with it.
You're making that up to trap me.
We picked her up at a bank
with two sacks full of cash.
Her next stop was the airport.
She had her boarding
pass all printed up.
Yeah, see, except she was
not going to the Maldives.
It was all her.
The scam, everything.
She killed Jared.
I met her when I started
the audit on Haven House.
I actually let myself believe..
It was about more than business.
Once she was sure that she had
me, she told me about her scam,
offered to cut me in 50/50 if
I made the audit come out clean.
How'd she get the con
going to begin with?
She heard about this place where
morons signed over fortunes and..
Didn't ask questions.
She showed up, pretending
to be a lost little lamb,
hooked up with the older brother
so she could be on the inside.
What about the school in
Afghanistan? Where'd that come from?
She scanned some pictures
from National Geographic,
put together a website, and
e-mailed Tom, asking for his help.
Seemed like we pulled it off.
Until Jared Baker started asking
questions about the school in Afghanistan.
Yeah, after I talked to Jared,
I called up Nikki, and I
told her we had a problem.
Next day, Jared turns up dead.
I called her, and I said,
"what the hell is going on?
No one's supposed to get hurt".
She told me to keep quiet
and to get out of town.
So I went home, and I got my bags.
You guys picked me up.
And that is the entire story. I swear.
Just one problem.. It's
your word against hers.
I might be an idiot,
but I am not stupid.
Check the lining in my suitcase.
There's a flash drive with
some sound files on it.
One thing you learn when
you work for the I.R.S.
Your whole life is the value
of keeping good records.
They aren't buying
that Shane killed Jared.
Oh, baby, calm down.
Okay. We're going to be all right.
I've got the room all booked on the
most beautiful beach in the Maldives.
Nikki, what's going on?
Who are you talking to?
Hey. I.. I got to go.
No, I think Kyle heard me. Okay.
I love you.
I'll see you at the airport.
Kyle wanted to know why
you were talking to us.
That's why he knocked on your door.
But he overheard too much, and that's
why you pushed him down the stairs.
Do you think I don't know that a
sound recording can be manipulated?
Do you even know that
you're doing Satan's work?
Please, God, I pray that you will
forgive these people for their blindness.
I pray that you will
show them the truth.
While you're at it, you might
want to also pray for a Judge
who doesn't believe
in the death penalty.
It's a miracle, really.
Kyle's awake and eating chocolate
pudding like there's no tomorrow.
How much tissue damage?
Some swelling.
He'll need to take it easy for a while,
but he should make a good recovery.
That message you sent God
must have done the trick.
Sometimes he needs a kick in the pants.
People make amazing
recoveries all the time
with no help from
some nonexistent deity.
If he doesn't exist, then why
would you send him a message?
Because I'm a stark, raving lunatic.
Look, we are closing Haven House.
But we're keeping the broken promise,
opening a school in Afghanistan.
I know it's what God wants.
You're still hearing a voice
even after the operation?
Not an actual voice
in my head like before.
But I still hear God every second..
The way anybody can if they just listen.
Here.
Maybe this will buy a few
books for the new school.
Wow!
That's a lot of books.
Does this mean you believe in God now?
Absolutely not.
But I believe in you.
I got something for you, too.
Kyle, what kind of present is that?
I think Dr. Pierce will appreciate it.
Subs created by: David Coleman.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player
www.tvsubtitles.net