[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
EXCUSE ME.
I ONLY DO ELEVATORS
FOR YOU, KATE.
THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
OKAY. JUST TRUST ME
AND FOLLOW MY LEAD.
WHAT -- ARE YOU TRYING TO
STRANGLE ME?
I JUST WANT YOU
TO MAKE A GOOD IMPRESSION.
WHO EXACTLY
AM I TRYING TO IMPRESS?
NEW BOSS.
SHE'S A REAL BALL-BUSTER --
THINK MARGARET THATCHER
WITH A GUN AND BETTER HAIR,
BUT SHE'S ALSO BRILLIANT,
AND SHE MIGHT BE
THE FIRST FEMALE DIRECTOR
IN THE HISTORY OF THE FBI.
I WOULD LIKE IT
IF SHE TOOK AN INTEREST IN ME,
SO PLEASE JUST BE YOUR NORMAL,
BRILLIANT SELF,
BUT NOT TOO WACKY,
WHAT DO YOU MEAN WACKY?
DON'T.
AH, DR. DANIEL PIERCE,
THIS IS SPECIAL AGENT
IN CHARGE IRENE REARDON
AND JUSTICE KAREN TRENT
OF THE SEVENTH CIRCUIT COURT
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
Irene:
FOR THE TIME BEING.
IN STRICT CONFIDENCE,
I CAN TELL YOU
JUDGE TRENT IS ON THE SHORT LIST
FOR SOLICITOR GENERAL.
FORMAL VETTING BEGINS NEXT WEEK,
BUT ON PRELIMINARY BACKGROUND,
JUDGE TRENT HAS INFORMED US
SHE'S BEEN
RECEIVING DISTURBING LETTERS.
SO WE'RE OPENING
A FORMAL INVESTIGATION.
I KEEP TELLING THEM
THIS ISN'T REALLY NECESSARY.
I'M SURE
HE'S HARMLESS.
BRADY McGRAW.
ARRESTED LAST WINTER
FOR TRESPASSING
ON THE NAVAL STATION
GREAT LAKES
AND CHARGED
WITH DOMESTIC TERRORISM.
HIS BEHAVIOR SEEMED OFF,
SO I ORDERED A PSYCH EVAL.
HE WAS DIAGNOSED
PARANOID SCHIZOPHRENIC.
GIVEN HIS CONDITION,
I SENTENCED HIM TO TREATMENT
INSTEAD OF JAIL.
I'M IMPRESSED.
I WISH MORE JUDGES
HAD SUCH AN ENLIGHTENED VIEW
OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
WELL, HE'S REPAYING THE JUDGE'S
ENLIGHTENMENT BY STALKING HER.
WHICH IS
WHERE YOU COME IN.
AH.
HYPERGRAPHIA.
INTENSE COMPULSION TO WRITE.
DOSTOEVSKY HAD IT.
WELL, THAT'S HARDLY
"THE BROTHERS KARAMAZOV."
[ CHUCKLES ]
THE BUREAU NEEDS
AN EXPERT THREAT ASSESSMENT,
AND AGENT MORETTI TELLS ME
YOU'RE THE MAN TO HELP US
TAKE BRADY OFF THE STREETS.
MAYBE I'M MISSING SOMETHING.
HAS HE COMMITTED A CRIME?
IF YOU DETERMINE
THAT BRADY IS A THREAT, HE HAS.
ARE YOU LOOKING
FOR MY PROFESSIONAL OPINION
OR A RUBBER STAMP?
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE SAFETY
OF A FEDERAL JUDGE, DR. PIERCE.
I'M SURE
YOU'LL DO THE RIGHT THING.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
BRADY McGRAW?
AGENT MORETTI, FBI.
Brady: GO AWAY.
JUDGE TRENT
ASKED US TO COME.
Are you enemies
of Ellebra?
NO. NO, BRADY.
WE'RE FRIENDS.
COME IN, QUICK,
BEFORE THEY SEE YOU. QUICK!
[ SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ]
WHO ARE
THE ENEMIES OF ELLEBRA?
THE TURLOCKS.
THEY'RE ALWAYS AFTER ME,
BUT WE'RE SAFE IN HERE.
MAYBE THEY SAW YOU COMING.
I'M GONNA ACTIVATE THE JAMMERS
TO BLOCK THEIR PROBES
SO THAT THEY CAN'T HEAR US.
THEY GET STATIC.
IT HURTS THEIR EARS,
BUT THEY DESERVE IT BECAUSE
THEY'RE ALWAYS SPYING ON ME.
[ STATIC ]
THAT'S
A BEAUTIFUL PAINTING.
NO. YOU CAN'T LOOK AT THIS.
YOU DON'T HAVE PROPER CLEARANCE.
IT LOOKS
JUST LIKE JUDGE TRENT.
NO. IT'S NOT HER.
IT'S OKAY.
WE UNDERSTAND.
YOU HAVE TO
PROTECT HER IDENTITY.
YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
YOU CAN TRUST US, BRADY.
JUST LIKE
YOU TRUST THE HEALER.
SH-SH-SHE'S
THE ONLY OTHER ONE I'VE TOLD.
H-HOW DID YOU
LEARN THE JUDGE'S SECRET?
DID SHE TELL YOU?
I RECEIVED A CODED MESSAGE
FROM ELLEBRA.
IT'S HER HOME PLANET.
THEY TOLD ME
THAT SHE'D BEEN SENT HERE
TO AVENGE ALL INJUSTICE
IN OUR WORLD.
HER REAL NAME
IS NEMESIS.
YES.
SO SHE'S AN ENEMY.
NO.
NO, SHE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
SHE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
I'LL EXPLAIN.
UM, THE GREEK PERSONIFICATION
OF -- OF JUSTICE
WASN'T A BLINDFOLDED VIRGIN
WITH SCALES.
IT WAS NEMESIS,
A FIERCE WARRIOR,
WHO EXACTED VENGEANCE WITH
HER SWORD OF JUSTICE, RIGHT?
YES.
THIS IS THE SWORD OF ELLEBRA.
THEY'VE ENTRUSTED IT WITH ME,
TO HELP THE JUDGE
ON HER MISSION.
WHAT MISSION?
TO SAVE EARTH.
THE ELLEBRANS HAVE HAD PEACE
FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS,
AND NOW THEY WANT TO HELP US
EVOLVE OUT OF WAR AND VIOLENCE.
SO THEY SENT NEMESIS
TO AVENGE ALL WRONG
AND VANQUISH ALL EVILDOERS.
AND I'M DOING
EVERYTHING THAT I CAN
TO HELP HER
COMPLETE THE MISSION.
LIKE
WRITING HER LETTERS.
YES.
SHE'S ALL ALONE ON --
ON AN ALIEN PLANET.
I WANTED HER TO KNOW
THAT I WAS HER FRIEND.
THAT'S GOOD, BRADY,
BUT YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT JUDGE TRENT WASN'T
COMFORTED BY YOUR LETTERS.
SHE WAS FRIGHTENED.
NO.
I NEVER MEANT TO SCARE HER.
I JUST WANTED HER TO KNOW
THAT I WAS ON HER SIDE.
SAVING THE WORLD
IS A LONELY JOB.
BRADY, ARE YOU --
ARE YOU SEEING A DOCTOR?
YOU'RE JUST
LIKE ALL THE REST.
YOU PRETEND TO UNDERSTAND,
BUT YOU JUST WANT TO LOCK ME UP,
SHOVE ME DOWN,
AND PUT PILLS IN MY THROAT.
NO. NO, I WOULD NEVER
DO THAT TO YOU, BRADY.
BUT YOU'RE CARRYING A VERY
HEAVY BURDEN ALL BY YOURSELF.
AND MEDICATION
CAN BE HELPFUL.
THERE ARE NEW PILLS
WITH FEWER SIDE EFFECTS.
IF I TAKE PILLS,
THE SIGNALS GET ALL SCRAMBLED,
I CAN'T RECEIVE MESSAGES,
ELLEBRA VANISHES.
AND THEN I'M ALL ALONE.
Daniel: BRADY McGRAW SEES YOU
AS THE SAVIOR OF THE PLANET.
HE THINKS
YOU'RE A SUPERHERO WITH --
WITH A DOUBLE IDENTITY LITERALLY
SENT HERE TO SAVE EARTH.
SOUNDS LIKE I'M CLARK KENT,
FROM ELLEBRA INSTEAD OF KRYPTON.
Daniel:
SCHIZOPHRENICS
OFTEN CONFLATE POP CULTURE
INTO THEIR DELUSIONS.
SO, WHAT, THIS --
THIS KOOK IS LEX LUTHOR?
NO, NO. NOT AT ALL.
NO, ON THE CONTRARY,
HE SEES HIMSELF AS --
AS YOUR WIFE'S PROTECTOR.
HE'D RATHER DIE
THAN HAVE HARM COME TO HER.
THAT'S A RELIEF, RIGHT?
MAYBE NOW EVERYONE CAN RELAX.
LOOK, I'M A REAL-ESTATE
DEVELOPER, NOT A COP,
BUT I'VE GOT A PRETTY GOOD
[BLEEP] DETECTOR.
AND RIGHT NOW,
IT'S RINGING OFF THE HOOK.
A DISTURBED GUY
HAS DELUSIONS ABOUT MY WIFE,
HE'S RANTING ABOUT SWORDS,
AND YOU WANT TO
LEAVE HIM OUT ON THE STREET?
THAT'S THE LAW, HONEY.
IF HE HASN'T COMMITTED A CRIME,
HE CAN'T BE LOCKED UP.
THEN HE SHOULD BE
HOSPITALIZED.
YOU CAN'T FORCE BRADY
INTO TREATMENT
JUST BECAUSE
HE MAKES YOU UNCOMFORTABLE.
HE'S GOT RIGHTS, INCLUDING
THE RIGHT NOT TO BE MEDICATED
OR COMMITTED
AGAINST HIS WILL.
Kate: IF IT WOULD
MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER,
I COULD HAVE THE MARSHALS'
SERVICE PUT A CAR OUTSIDE,
JUST FOR A FEW DAYS.
[ SCOFFS ]
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
NO. I -- DO YOU REMEMBER
THE O'BANNION TRIAL?
[ CHUCKLES ]
THE IRISH MOB SUPPOSEDLY
HAD A CONTRACT OUT ON ME,
AND I SUDDENLY
HAD A PACK OF FEDERAL AGENTS
TROTTING BEHIND ME
ON MY MORNING RUN.
I FELT LIKE AN IDIOT.
THANKS, BUT NO THANKS.
I JUST WANT TO
GET ON WITH MY LIFE.
[ SIGHS ] I WISH
I COULD HAVE HELPED BRADY.
YOU STOPPED THE FEDS
FROM LOCKING HIM UP.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A WIN.
HE NEEDS THERAPY,
MEDICATION.
POT, MEET KETTLE.
I'M NOT A HYPOCRITE,
NATALIE.
I NEVER SAID THAT MEDICATION
CAN'T BE A LIFESAVER.
FOR EVERYONE BUT YOU.
I'M FINE.
I'VE GOT MY ROUTINES,
I'VE GOT LEWICKI.
METHINKS THE NEUROPSYCHIATRIST
DOTH PROTEST TOO MUCH.
I AM COMPLETELY FUNCTIONAL.
BRADY'S LOST IN HIS DELUSIONS.
YOU HALLUCINATE.
YEAH, AND AS
YOU'RE ALWAYS POINTING OUT,
SOMETIMES MY HALLUCINATIONS HELP
ME ACCESS MY UNCONSCIOUS MIND.
IT'S COME IN HANDY LATELY.
IT ALSO PREVENTS YOU
FROM LEADING A NORMAL LIFE...
...FROM
MAKING REAL FRIENDS.
WELL, MAYBE
I LIKE THE FRIENDS I GOT.
[ Kate: DANIEL. ]
DAVID TRENT
CAME HOME TONIGHT
AND FOUND HIS WIFE
STABBED TO DEATH.
THERE'S
NO FORENSIC EVIDENCE YET,
BUT THE WORKING ASSUMPTION
IS THAT BRADY McGRAW DID IT.
I NEED TO
SEE THAT CRIME SCENE.
Kate: I'M DON'T KNOW
IF THIS IS A GOOD IDEA.
THEY SAID
IT'S A BLOODY MESS INSIDE.
I NEED TO SEE IT.
THERE MAY BE EVIDENCE
THAT EXONERATES BRADY.
THIS ISMR. TRENT --
YOU SAID
HE WOULDI-I --RT HER.
YOU TOLD HER SHE WAS SAFE,
AND NOW SHE'S DEAD!
GET HIM OUT OF HERE,
AGENT MORETTI.
I MIGHT --
MAYBE I CAN HELP.
YOU'VE DONE ENOUGH FOR ONE DAY.
GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
IF I CAN JUST --
[ SIGHS ]
Kate:
I HEARD THE BRIEFING.
THE TASK FORCE
HASN'T FOUND BRADY McGRAW
OR ANY FORENSIC EVIDENCE
AGAINST HIM.
THANKS FOR THE UPDATE,
BUT I'M WELL AWARE OF
WHERE THIS INVESTIGATION STANDS.
I'D LIKE YOUR PERMISSION
TO PURSUE OTHER SUSPECTS.
OKAY,
YOU'VE GOT MY ATTENTION.
WHAT OTHER SUSPECTS?
SHE MADE
A LOT OF ENEMIES.
SHE SENTENCED HALF
OF THE SINALOA CARTEL TO DEATH.
SHE APPROVED
THE REZONING OF CABRINI-GREEN
INTO COMMERCIAL DEVELOPMENT
INSTEAD OF LOW-INCOME HOUSING --
[BLEEP]
A LOT PEOPLE OFF.
JUST LAST YEAR, THE IRISH MOB
PUT A BOUNTY ON HER HEAD.
AGENT MORETTI,
I APPRECIATE YOUR INITIATIVE,
BUT JUDGE TRENT
WAS BRUTALLY STABBED TO DEATH
IN HER OWN HOME.
IT HARDLY LOOKS LIKE
A PROFESSIONAL HIT.
WHAT IT DOES LOOK LIKE
IS THE WORK OF A DISTURBED MAN
WHOM DR. PIERCE
CLAIMED WAS NOT A THREAT.
BUT IT IS POSSIBLE
THAT BRADY'S NOT THE KILLER.
YOUR PET EXPERT
SCREWED THE POOCH.
BECAUSE OF HIM,
JUDGE TRENT IS DEAD!
BECAUSE OF THAT,
I JUST GOT AN EARFUL
FROM THE DIRECTOR HIMSELF,
AFTER HE GOT AN EARFUL
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
NOT EXACTLY
THE IMPRESSION I WANTED TO MAKE
IN MY FIRST WEEK
IN THIS JOB.
NOT EXACTLY THE IMPRESSION
I WANTED TO MAKE ON YOU, EITHER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THEN YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
WHY I'M GOING TO MUDDLE THROUGH
THIS INVESTIGATION
WITHOUT
YOUR INVALUABLE ASSISTANCE.
YES, MA'AM.
CRAZY CRIME --
MUST BE A CRAZY KILLER.
NO WAY A SANE PERSON
WOULD DO SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
SO IT'S GOT TO BE
A SCHIZOPHRENIC.
YOU'RE OVER-IDENTIFYING
WITH BRADY.
YEAH, THAT'S
'CAUSE HE'S WRONGLY ACCUSED.
DANIEL, JUST BECAUSE
YOU'VE NEVER BEEN VIOLENT
DOESN'T MEAN THE SAME IS TRUE
OF ALL SCHIZOPHRENICS.
WELL, ALL OF BRADY'S DELUSIONS
ABOUT THE JUDGE WERE POSITIVE.
HE VENERATED THE WOMAN.
HE HAD NO REASON TO HURT HER.
AND THERE'S NO EVIDENCE
THAT HE DID.
WELL, IF YOU'RE SO SURE
THAT HE'S INNOCENT,
WOULDN'T FINDING HIM
AND EXONERATING HIM
BE BETTER THAN RANTING TO ME
ABOUT THE INJUSTICE OF IT ALL?
YES.
EXCEPT FOR THE FACT
THAT I'M PERSONA NON GRATA
AT THE FBI
AT THE MOMENT.
BESIDES,
HOW WOULD I FIND HIM
WHEN 100 FEDERAL AGENTS
AND THE CHICAGO P.D. CAN'T?
BECAUSE YOU CAN UNDERSTAND HIM
IN A WAY THAT NO COP CAN.
WHERE DO YOU FIND ANSWERS
TO PROBLEMS YOU CAN'T SOLVE?
You are not
supposed to be here.
I think I know
how to find Brady.
DANIEL, WE WERE
KICKED OFF THE CASE.
THE KEY IS UNDERSTANDING
HIS DELUSIONS.
REMEMBER "THE HEALER"?
HE TRUSTED HER.
HE CONFIDED IN HER.
IF WE CAN FIGURE OUT WHO SHE IS,
MAYBE SHE CAN HELP US FIND HIM.
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
SHE IS FROM THE PLANET ELLEBRA.
SO, WAIT? YOU WANT ME
TO TRACK DOWN AN ALIEN?
NO, IN BRADY'S MIND, JUDGE TRENT
WAS AN ALIEN, BUT SHE'S REAL.
THE HEALER MUST BE, TOO.
SO, WHERE SHOULD START?
THE HUBBLE TELESCOPE?
THE JUDGE ORDERED HIM
INTO PSYCHIATRIC CARE.
"THE HEALER"
MAY BE ONE OF HIS DOCTORS.
AGENTS TALKED TO BRADY'S
SHRINK AT CEDAR HEIGHTS.
HE HAS NO IDEA
WHERE HE IS.
OKAY, SO, THERE'S LOTS
OF CAREGIVERS IN A HOSPITAL --
ORDERLIES, NURSES,
SOCIAL WORKERS.
WE CAN'T
JUST MARCH INTO THE HOSPITAL
AND START INTERVIEWING
500 EMPLOYEES.
WHAT PLANET ARE YOU FROM,
AND WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH THE REAL KATE MORETTI?
Ellen: WHAT DOES THE FBI WANT
WITH BRADY?
WELL, WE'RE TRYING TO
LOCATE HIM.
WHY?
WHAT DO YOU THINK HE DID?
THEY THINK HE STABBED
A FEDERAL JUDGE.
OH, THERE'S NO WAY.
BRADY'S GENTLE.
AND HE'S FREAKED OUT
BY THE SIGHT OF BLOOD.
YOU CAN'T EVEN
GET NEAR HIM WITH A SYRINGE
UNLESS HE HAS
A VALIUM IN HIM.
HE'S ALWAYS
BEEN LIKE THAT.
SOUNDS LIKE
YOU KNOW HIM PRETTY WELL.
HE'S KIND OF
A FREQUENT FLYER AROUND HERE.
HE'S BEEN IN AND OUT
OF TREATMENT A DOZEN TIMES
SINCE HE WAS 17.
HE'S A SWEET KID
WHEN HE'S ON HIS MEDS.
WELL, APPARENTLY,
HE'S NOT ON THEM NOW.
I KNOW.
I SPOKE WITH HIM LAST WEEK.
YOU KEPT IN TOUCH
AFTER HE WAS DISCHARGED.
HE DOESN'T
HAVE ANYONE ELSE.
BOTH HIS PARENTS ARE DEAD,
AND HE SCARES NEW PEOPLE OFF
WITH HIS DELUSIONS ABOUT ALIENS.
HE'S LUCKY
TO HAVE A FRIEND LIKE YOU.
SOME FRIEND I WAS.
I KNEW HE WAS DECOMPENSATING,
AND I COULDN'T CONVINCE HIM
TO GET BACK ON HIS MEDS
OR ADMIT HIMSELF.
I WISH
I COULD HAVE HELPED.
YOU CAN HELP HIM NOW.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU MEAN I CAN HELP YOU.
YOU WANT ME TO TURN HIM IN.
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE HE IS?
IF I DID,
I PROBABLY WOULDN'T TELL YOU.
I'VE SEEN HOW COPS
TREAT THE MENTALLY ILL.
ONE TIME BRADY
WAS BROUGHT IN BY CPD,
THEY PEPPER-SPRAYED HIM
FOR NO REASON.
ELLEN, I'M NOT A COP.
I'M A PHYSICIAN.
I KNOW HOW TO
BRING BRADY IN SAFELY.
AND ONCE WE DO THAT,
IT MAY BE POSSIBLE
TO GET HIM MANDATED
BACK INTO TREATMENT.
NO JAIL?
NOT IF I CAN HELP IT.
THERE'S AN ABANDONED WAREHOUSE
OFF TORRENCE AVENUE.
I PICKED HIM UP THERE ONCE
WHEN HE CALLED ME FOR HELP.
HE SAID
IT'S A PORTAL TO ELLEBRA.
WHEN WE GET THERE, YOU HAVE TO
LET ME TAKE THE LEAD.
DANIEL, WE CAN'T
GO PICK HIM UP ON OUR OWN.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE IT'S ONE THING
FOR ME TO INTERVIEW
A BUNCH OF HOSPITAL EMPLOYEES.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
A FUGITIVE HERE,
MAYBE ARMED,
MAYBE DANGEROUS.
HE'S NOT DANGEROUS.
I KNOW YOU THINK THAT,
BUT IF YOU'RE WRONG
AND I HAVEN'T FOLLOW PROCEDURE,
IF I DON'T
HI KNOW, I KNOW.--
YOU'LL GET IN EVEN BIGGER
TROUBLE WITH YOUR NEW BOSS.
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY
WAS IF ANYTHING HAPPENED TO YOU,
IT'D BE MY FAULT.
I'D NEVER FORGIVE MYSELF.
Irene: YOU CONDUCT A ROGUE
INVESTIGATION WITH A CIVILIAN,
AFTER I SPECIFICALLY
ORDERED YOU NOT TO,
AND NOW YOU WALTZ IN HERE
AND ANNOUNCE YOU THINK YOU KNOW
WHERE BRADY McGRAW IS.
YES.
YOU'VE GOT BRASS ONES,
AGENT MORETTI.
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT.
HOW SURE ARE YOU
THAT BRADY McGRAW
IS AT THIS WAREHOUSE?
SCHIZOPHRENICS ARE CREATURES
OF HABIT AND RITUAL.
AT A TIME OF STRESS,
HE'D RETREAT TO THE FAMILIAR.
WELL,
THANK YOU, DR. PIERCE.
YOU HAVE TO
LET ME BRING HIM IN.
YOU'RE NOT
A TRAINED FIELD AGENT.
BRADY McGRAW
IS MENTALLY ILL.
MY TRAINING
IS EXACTLY THE KIND YOU NEED.
JUST DON'T SCREW UP AGAIN.
BRADY?
IT'S DOCTOR PIERCE.
BRADY: Go away.
You shouldn't be here.
BRADY, PLEASE COME OUT.
WE NEED TO TALK.
Who are they?
THEY'RE --
THEY'RE FEDERAL AGENTS.
THEY'RE HERE
TO PROTECT YOU.
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
TRUST ME, BRADY.
NO ONE WANTS TO
SEE YOU GET HURT.
WEAPON!
YOU LIED TO ME?
BRADY, NO!
[ SCREAMING ]
OH, GOD!
WE ALREADY HAVE A TEAM OF AGENTS
IINTERROGATING HIM..
HE'S ILL.
HE WON'T TALK TO THEM.
ON THE CONTRARY,
HE'S TALKING A GREAT DEAL.
IN FACT,
HE'S MADE A FULL CONFESSION.
I APPRECIATE YOUR HELP
LOCATING BRADY.
I REALLY DO.
BUT YOUR ROLE IN THIS CASE
IS FINISHED.
TH-- IT JUST -- THAT DOESN'T --
A CONFESSION DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
UNLESS BRADY
ACTUALLY DID IT.
NO, NO, NO.
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
OH, BELIEVE IT, DR. PIERCE.
THE MURDER WEAPON.
COMPLETE WITH BLOODY
FINGERPRINTS ON THE HANDLE,
WHICH WILL
MATCH BRADY McGRAW'S.
YOU --
YOU CAN'T BE SURE.
HE'S THE ONE WHO TOLD US
WHERE THE KNIFE WAS HIDDEN.
Brady:
I STABBED HER, OVER AND OVER,
AND I DIDN'T STOP
UNTIL SHE WAS DEAD.
OF COURSE HE CONFESSED.
IT'S CALLED
IMAGINATION INFLATION.
YOU TELL A SCHIZOPHRENIC
THE SAME STORY ENOUGH TIMES
AND HE STARTS
TO BELIEVE IT.
THOSE AGENTS
TOLD HIM OVER AND OVER AGAIN
THAT THEY KNOW
HE DID IT.
DANIEL, IT WAS
A BY-THE-BOOK INTERROGATION,
BRADY WAS OFFERED FOOD,
WATER.
HE WAS NEVER YELLED AT
OR THREATENED.
HE SHOULD HAVE
HAD AN ATTORNEY PRESENT.
THEY MIRANDIZED HIM TWICE.
HE DENIED REPRESENTATION.
WELL, OF COURSE,
BECAUSE HE SAID,
"THE ONLY LAW
IS THE LAW OF ELLEBRA."
THE COURT WILL APPOINT A LAWYER
AT ARRAIGNMENT.
I'M SURE THE ISSUE OF BRADY'S
COMPETENCE WILL BE RAISED.
THAT'S GREAT.
AN OVERWORKED,
UNDERPAID PUBLIC DEFENDER,
WHO PROBABLY WON'T HAVE ENOUGH
TIME TO READ THE CASE FILE
BEFORE
PLEADING BRADY OUT.
DANIEL, ENOUGH.
THE BLOODY FINGERPRINTS ON
THE MURDER WEAPON ARE BRADY'S.
THE JUDGE'S BLOOD
WAS ON HIS CLOTHES.
THERE HAS TO BE
ANOTHER EXPLANATION.
LISTEN, I REALIZE THAT
THIS IS HARD FOR YOU TO ACCEPT,
BUT BRADY DID IT.
[ SIGHS ]
[ PIANO PLAYING ]
Nemesis:
THAT'S PRETTY GLOOMY.
HOW ABOUT SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE UP-TEMPO?
YOU'RE NOT REAL.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN MY
HALLUCINATION -- YOU'RE BRADY'S.
WHAT'S A SHARED DELUSION
AMONG FRIENDS?
AND BRADY NEEDS A FRIEND
RIGHT NOW.
HE'S ALONE IN JAIL,
SLOWLY LOSING
WHAT'S LEFT OF HIS SANITY.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
I'M OFF THE CASE.
SUPERHEROES
NEVER GIVE UP.
WE HAVE TO
SAVE THE WORLD EVERY TIME.
YEAH, WELL,
I'M NO SUPERHERO.
YOU MAY NOT
HAVE X-RAY VISION
OR THE ABILITY TO LEAP TALL
BUILDINGS IN A SINGLE BOUND,
BUT YOU HAVE SOME
PRETTY IMPRESSIVE CREDENTIALS.
Daniel:
I'M DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
I KNOW
EXACTLY WHO YOU ARE.
I'M JUST A LITTLE UNCLEAR
AS TO WHAT THE FBI's PET SHRINK
IS DOING
AT THE PUBLIC DEFENDERS' OFFICE.
YOUR CLIENT
IS ACUTELY MENTALLY ILL.
UNTIL HE GETS A COURT-ORDERED
FORENSIC MENTAL HEALTH EXAM,
HE'S SANE
IN THE EYES OF THE LAW.
I'VE MADE A REQUEST
TO THE JUDGE
TO HAVE
A PSYCHIATRIST APPOINTED.
I'LL DO IT.
YOU'LL DO WHAT?
EVALUATE BRADY,
TESTIFY ON HIS BEHALF.
I'M SURE YOU'RE QUALIFIED,
BUT THERE'S
A SLIGHT CONFLICT OF INTEREST.
YOU'RE STILL
ON THE FBI's PAYROLL.
I TOLD THEM BRADY DIDN'T DO IT.
THEY IGNORED MY EXPERT OPINION.
NOW I'M OFFERING IT TO YOU...
FREE OF CHARGE.
FBI's OWN EXPERT
TESTIFYING AGAINST THEM?
HMM, I MEAN,
THAT'S THE KIND OF FIREWORKS
I WOULD LOVE TO SET OFF
AT TRIAL.
THERE MAY NOT BE A TRIAL.
IF I CERTIFY THAT BRADY WAS TOO
ILL TO UNDERSTAND HIS RIGHTS,
YOU MIGHT
GET THE CONFESSION THROWN OUT.
HOW SOON CAN YOU SEE HIM?
I HEARD THE CALL.
YOU WERE HEARING VOICES?
CALL, FALL,
BALL, WALL.
WHAT DID THE VOICES SAY,
BRADY?
THE SECRET FREQUENCY --
CODE OMEGA.
WHAT WAS THE MESSAGE?
I am called to be
the sword of justice.
Vengeance is mine,
saith the Lord.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
BRADY -- I KNOW IT'S HARD,
BRADY, BUT TRY TO FOCUS.
CAN YOU REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED
THE NIGHT JUDGE TRENT DIED?
I CAN'T.
THE TURLOCK.
THEY'RE IN MY HEAD.
THEY ARE SILENCING ME
WITH THEIR GAMMA RAY.
STAY WITH ME.
SHE WAS STABBED, BRADY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT THAT?
NOT THE SWORD OF JUSTICE,
THE DAGGER OF ISHTARION.
BLACK OBSIDIAN,
VENGEANCE OF THE NIGHT SHADOWS,
THE HERO'S BLOOD
RUNNETH LIKE A RIVER.
WHAT HAPPENED, BRADY?
THERE WAS BLOOD.
RED RED, DEAD DEAD.
SHE FELL ON HER HEAD DEAD.
[ GASPS ]
GET OUT OF MY MIND!
WHO ARE YOU TALKING TO?
THEY'RE BLOCKING
THE FREQUENCIES!
WAITSTOP, STOP, STOP!RADY!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE -- YOU'RE SAFE.
[ Crying ] I'M SORRY.
WHAT ARE YOU SORRY ABOUT?
I KILLED HER.
DOC,
YOU NEED TO SNAP OUT OF IT.
YOU NEED TO
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
YOU HAVEN'T LEFT THE HOUSE
IN THREE DAYS.
I CAN'T
CANCEL ANY MORE CLASSES.
DEAN HALEY'S NOT GONNA BUY
THE STOMACH VIRUS STORY FOREVER.
AND I'VE GOT
A LOT OF MESSAGES FOR YOU.
KATE'S BEEN CALLING,
AND THE PUBLIC DEFENDER.
HE SAYS BRADY'S DOING BETTER
IN THE HOSPITAL,
STABILIZING
ON THE MEDICATION.
YOU HELPED BRADY, DOC.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO HELP YOURSELF.
LOOK,
I'M HERE IF YOU NEED ME.
Natalie:
MAX IS RIGHT.
YOU DID HELP BRADY.
IF I'D GOT HIM
INTO THERAPY SOONER,
THAT JUDGE
WOULD STILL BE ALIVE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
HAD HIM COMMITTED.
GEE,
THANKS FOR THE PEP TALK.
I'M NOT GONNA SUGAR-COAT IT.
IT'S A HORRIBLE SITUATION.
YOU HERE IT COMES. IT.
MAYBE SOMEONE ELSE
SHOULD BE MEDICATED
MEDS, MEDS, MEDS, MEDS, MEDS.
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH, BLAH.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
DO YOU WANT ME TO BE ON MEDS?
THAT'LL
ALL MAKE YOU HAPPY?
FINE.
I CAN DO THAT.
MEDS ALL AROUND.
I'M A DOCTOR.
LEWICKI!
I WANT
THAT PRESCRIPTION FILLED.
OKAY.
GOOD FOR YOU, DOC.
I'LL PICK IT UP RIGHT NOW.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
IT'S A START.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHAT DO -- WHAT MORE
DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
ME? NOTHING.
BRADY'S
A DIFFERENT STORY.
HE'S STABILIZED NOW,
WHICH MEANS THE REALITY
OF WHAT HE DID TO JUDGE TRENT
IS PROBABLY HITTING HIM.
MAYBE HE NEEDS A FRIEND.
[ SIGHS ]
Brady: I CAN'T
HEAR THE VOICES ANYMORE.
I GUESS
THE MEDS ARE WORKING.
BUT I CAN'T STOP THINKING ABOUT
WHAT I DID TO THE JUDGE.
I SHOULD HAVE
GOT YOU HELP SOONER.
YOU TRIED.
I WAS TOO SICK
TO LISTEN.
I WISH I HAD.
YOU WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT?
IT SOUNDS SO STUPID NOW.
I KNOW THE VOICES
WERE IN MY HEAD.
BUT THEY SOUNDED SO REAL.
AND THEY TOLD ME
THAT THE JUDGE WAS IN DANGER,
THAT SHE
NEEDED MY PROTECTION.
SO YOU WENT
TO THE HOUSE.
YES.
AND I TOOK MY SWORD,
LIKE THE VOICES TOLD ME,
AND IT WAS LIKE
I WAS OUT OF MY BODY,
LIKE I WAS ON THE CEILING
LOOKING DOWN.
AND I SAW MYSELF
JUST STABBING HER OVER AND OVER.
AND THERE WAS
SO MUCH BLOOD.
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
I'M KNEELING BESIDE HER,
AND I PULLED THE KNIFE
FROM OUT OF HER,
AND I TRIED TO
STOP THE BLEEDING,
BUT IT WAS TOO LATE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY I DID IT.
I DIDN'T WANT TO
HURT HER.
YOU WERE SICK, BRADY.
YOU -- YOU DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT YOU WERE DOING.
Nemesis:
AIN'T THAT THE TRUTH.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
DR. PIERCE,
ARE YOU -- ARE YOU OKAY?
IRONIC, ISN'T IT?
HE CAN'T SEE ME.
HE'S TAKING HIS MEDS.
DELUSIONS AND HALLUCINATIONS
WILL TRY TO MISLEAD US, BRADY.
YES, THEY WILL.
BUT LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
DO YOU EVER THINK
YOU'RE HAVING A HALLUCINATION
AND IT TURNS OUT TO BE REAL?
BRADY,
YOU SAID YOU TOOK THE SWORD
WITH YOU TO THE JUDGE'S HOUSE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
BUT YOU DIDN'T
KILL HER WITH IT.
NO, I --
I USED THE KNIFE.
WHERE DID YOU
GET THE KNIFE?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
Daniel: BRADY HAS
THE SWORD OF ELLEBRA,
A WEAPON
HE COMPLETELY FETISHIZES.
HE TAKES IT
TO THE JUDGE'S HOUSE,
AND THEN HE KILLS HER
WITH SOME RANDOM KNIFE?
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT?
BRADY REMEMBERS PULLING THE
KNIFE OUT OF THE JUDGE'S CHEST
AND TRYING TO SAVE HER
FROM HIS OWN PERSPECTIVE,
BECAUSE THAT'S
WHAT HE ACTUALLY DID.
BUT HE CAN ONLY REMEMBER
THE MURDER ITSELF
AS IF HE WAS
WATCHING IT HAPPEN FROM --
FROM OUTSIDE HIS BODY,
LIKE A FLY ON THE WALL.
THAT'S BECAUSE
HE DIDN'T REALLY STAB HER.
IT'S WHAT I WAS SAYING.
I WAS RIGHT.
IT'S IMAGINATION INFLATION.
THE AGENTS
INTERROGATING BRADY
TOLD HIM HE STABBED THE JUDGE
WITH A KNIFE,
SO THAT'S THE FALSE MEMORY
THAT HE FORMS,
BUT HE DIDN'T
REALLY DO IT.
THEN WHAT THE [BLEEP]
WAS HE DOING IN THAT HOUSE?
HE WAS HEARING VOICES
TELLING HIM TO GO THERE,
BUT WHAT IF THE VOICES
WEREN'T HALLUCINATIONS?
WHAT IF THEY WERE REAL MESSAGES
FROM THE KILLER,
SETTING BRADY UP
AS THE FALL GUY?
HE'S SCHIZOPHRENIC.
HE'S THE PERFECT PATSY.
DID ANYBODY CHECK HIS
PHONE RECORDS OR HIS E-MAIL?
NO, THE CASE WAS CLOSED
AFTER BRADY CONFESSED.
YOU SEE, I -- I --
MAYBE BRADY IS BEING SET UP.
[ SIGHS ]
WELL, IF YOU'RE RIGHT,
THE REAL KILLER WOULD BE SOMEONE
WHO KNEW ABOUT BRADY'S FIXATION
WITH THE JUDGE.
HER HUSBAND.
HER HUSBAND! HE READ THE LETTERS
THAT SHE GOT FROM BRADY.
HE WAS THERE
WHEN WE BRIEFED THE JUDGE.
MNH-MNH, DAVID TRENT
WAS GIVING A SPEECH
IN FRONT OF 200 PEOPLE
AT THE TIME
OF THE MURDER.
THE PERFECT ALIBI
IF YOU'VE HIRED SOMEBODY
TO KILL YOUR WIFE.
I SUPPOSE SO,
BUT WHAT WAS HIS MOTIVE?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE -- HE--
HE WANTED INSURANCE MONEY.
HE WAS HAVING AN AFFAIR.
I DON'T HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS.
I JUST KNOW WE NEED TO
SEE THOSE PHONE RECORDS.
Irene: YOU'RE BURNING
THE MIDNIGHT OIL, AGENT MORETTI.
ANYTHING
I SHOULD KNOW ABOUT?
I'M JUST WORKING UP
SOME NEW THEORIES
ON THE JUDGE TRENT CASE.
THAT CASE IS CLOSED, AND I DON'T
WANT YOU TRYING TO REOPEN IT.
DR. PIERCE
THINKS IT'S POSSIBLE THAT BRA--
HOW WELL DO YOU KNOW
PRETTY WELL.
I WAS HIS STUDENT,
AND WE'VE WORKED A LOT TOGETHER
OVER THE PAST FEW YEARS.
AND HOW ABOUT
HIS PERSONAL LIFE?
HE'S A PRIVATE PERSON.
DID YOU KNOW HE HAS
A HISTORY OF MENTAL ILLNESS?
YES.
YES, BUT HIS CONDITION
IS STABLE,
AND HIS MEDICAL HISTORY
IS CONFIDENTIAL.
SO HOW DID YOU
KNOW ABOUT IT?
IT'S MY RESPONSIBILITY
TO ENSURE
THAT THE PEOPLE WHO WORK FOR
THIS OFFICE ARE FIT TO DO SO.
DR. PIERCE IREALLY?
AND WAS HE FINE
LAST YEAR?
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
BUT YOU WOULDN'T KNOW,
WOULD YOU?
BECAUSE
YOU WERE IN WASHINGTON.
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
WHY DON'T YOU ASK HIM?
HEY.
DID -- DID YOU GET
THE PHONE RECORDS?
NO. WE'VE GOT SOMETHING ELSE
TO TALK ABOUT FIRST.
WHEN I LEFT FOR D.C.,
YOU QUIT YOUR CONSULTING GIG
WITH THE BUREAU.
YEAH, SO?
WHEN I ASKED YOU WHY, YOU NEVER
GAVE ME A STRAIGHT ANSWER.
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO
WITH BRADY?
TELL ME, DANIEL --
WHY DID YOU QUIT?
WOW. WHAT IS -- WHAT IS THIS?
AN INQUISITION?
I FOUND OUT
YOU STOPPED TEACHING, TOO.
OH, YOU DID?
SO YOU'RE CHECKING UP ON ME?
WELL, L-LET ME
SAVE YOU THE TROUBLE.
I TOOK A SABBATICAL
TO WRITE A BOOK.
MUST BE THE FIRST ONE YOU EVER
WROTE THAT DIDN'T GET PUBLISHED.
TELL ME --
WHERE WERE YOU REALLY?
I-I-IT --
TH-THAT'S NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
CUT THE [BLEEP] DANIEL.
I NEED YOU TO TELL ME THE TRUTH.
REXFORD
PSYCHIATRIC HOSPITAL.
I, UH...
I WASN'T DOING VERY WELL.
I REALIZED I NEEDED HELP,
SO I GOT IT.
THEY MEDICATED ME.
THAT'S WHERE I MET MAX.
IN THE HOSPITAL.
HE WAS AN ORDERLY.
HE WAS SMART.
DIDN'T PUT UP
WITH ANY OF MY CRAP.
WHEN I GOT STABILIZED, I DIDN'T
WANT TO STAY ON THE MEDS,
BUT I KNEW I NEEDED SOMEONE
I COULD TRUST
TO KEEP AN EYE ON ME,
MAKE ME STICK TO MY SCHEDULE,
MY DIET.
I PROMISED HIM
IF HE CAME BACK TO CHICAGO
I'D GET HIM
A TEACHER'S ASSISTANTSHIP
SO HE COULD
FINISH GRAD SCHOOL.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
I DIDN'T WANT YOU
TO THINK OF ME LIKE THAT.
YOU KNOW, CRAZY.
I WOULDN'T.
YEAH, YOU WOULD.
THAT'S WHY
I DON'T TALK ABOUT MY DIAGNOSIS,
BECAUSE
THEN IT BECOMES WHO I AM.
DANIEL,
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
HOW'D YOU FIND OUT?
REARDON.
SHE RAN A BACKGROUND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BIG BROTHER AT HIS FINEST,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
I'M SORRY
I GOT YOU IN TROUBLE.
YOU THINK I CARE ABOUT THAT,
DANIEL?
I CARE ABOUT YOU.
OKAY, WELL,
IF WE'RE DONE
WITH EMBARRASSING
PERSONAL REVELATIONS 101,
CAN WE GET BACK TO WORK?
I'VE GOT A FRIEND IN I.T.B.
SHE OWES ME A FAVOR.
SHE, UH, SLIPPED ME
BRADY McGRAW'S PHONE RECORDS.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
HE WAS GETTING PHONE CALLS
ON THE DAY OF THE MURDER --
REAL ONES.
FROM DAVID TRENT?
DON'T KNOW.
WHO BOUGHT IT?
NOT SURE, BUT MY FRIEND'S
PINGING THE PHONE AS WE SPEAK.
SOMETIMES BIG BROTHER
AIN'T SO BAD.
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYS ]
Pete: HELLO?
HELLO?
[ SIGHS ]
WHISKEY. UH, NEAT.
BAD DAY?
YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
WELL, MAYBE
I CAN MAKE IT BETTER.
OH, REALLY?
[ LAUGHS ]
WHERE'S YOUR CAR?
KatLOOKING PRETTY.AD.
OH, SERIOUSLY?
FBI.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
I THOUGHT WE WERE GONNA
GO TO YOUR PLACE.
[ Laughing ]
IN YOUR DREAMS.
[ GROANS ]
NICE WORK, MATA HARI.
WHAT NOW?
REARDON DIDN'T WANT ME
DIGGING BACK INTO THIS,
SO I CAN'T
BRING A SUSPECT TO THE OFFICE
UNTIL I'VE GOT
SOMETHING CONCRETE.
SO,
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
SOMEWHERE
WITH A LITTLE AMBIANCE.
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
THIS ISN'T -- THIS IS NOT LEGAL.
DO I LOOK LIKE
I CARE ABOUT LEGAL?!
I WASN'T LYING TO YOU ABOUT
THE LOUSY DAY THAT I'VE HAD.
MY BOSS IS A RAGING [BLEEP]
I PROBABLY LOST MY JOB.
THAT'S WHY YOU ARE HANDCUFFED
IN THIS DUMP,
INSTEAD OF A NICE,
CLEAN INTERROGATION ROOM.
I DIDN'T KILL THAT JUDGE.
BUT YOU DID CALL BRADY MCGRAW.
THE PHONE RECORDS PROVE IT.
MAKING A PHONE CALL
IS NOT A CRIME.
CONSPIRACY
TO COMMIT MURDER IS.
YOU TOLD BRADY
TO GO TO THAT HOUSE.
THAT MAKES YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
[ SIGHS ]
IT WASN'T MY IDEA.
I KNOW.
IT WAS DAVID TRENT'S.
WHO THE [BLEEP]
IS DAVID TRENT?
THEN WHO TOLD YOU
TO CALL BRADY?
I'M NOT MESSING
AROUND HERE, PETE!
I -- PLEASE.
I CAN'T SAY ANYTHING.
[ SIGHS ]
HE'D -- HE'D KILL ME.
OR THE GOVERNMENT WILL.
IT'S UP TO YOU.
OKAY.
I DIDN'T KNOW
ANYBODY WAS GONNA GET WHACKED.
I SWEAR.
HE JUST TOLD ME
TO CALL THIS CRAZY NUT,
TALK ABOUT ALL THIS WEIRD STUFF
LIKE SWORDS AND ALIENS,
AND GET HIM TO THE HOUSE.
THAT'S IT.
WHO TOLD YOU
TO CALL BRADY?
[ SIGHS ]
BOBBY LONERGAN.
I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT IS.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE,
AGENT MORETTI?
MEET BOBBY LONERGAN.
YOU'RE NEW TO CHICAGO,
SO YOU MAY NOT KNOW THIS,
BUT HE'S ONE OF THE TOP GUYS
IN THE O'BANNION ORGANIZATION.
REMEMBER WHEN I ASKED
FOR YOUR PERMISSION
TO PURSUE OTHER SUSPECTS?
I TOLD YOU
THAT THE IRISH MOB
HAD A CONTRACT OUT
ON THE JUDGE LAST YEAR.
I ALSO REMEMBER
DENYING YOUR REQUEST.
OH, OKAY.
UH, I CAN CUT HIM LOOSE,
BUT JUST SO YOU KNOW,
I'VE GOT A WITNESS
WHO SAYS THAT LONERGAN HERE
SET UP THE JUDGE'S MURDER.
Bobby: I HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH JUDGE TRENT'S DEATH.
THAT'S NOT
WHAT PETE DOLAN SAYS.
PETE DOLAN'S A THUG
WHO'LL TELL TALL TALES
ON ANYONE WHO BUYS HIM A DRINK.
HE SEEMED PRETTY SOBER
WHEN HE GAVE YOU UP.
REALLY?
WELL, HIS SAINTED MOTHER'S
PRAYERS HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
I'LL CALL HER
WHEN I GET HOME.
YOU'RE NOT GOING HOME.
AND THE ONLY PERSON
YOU SHOULD CALL IS A LAWYER.
I ALREADY TOLD YOU
I DON'T NEED ONE.
I HAVE DONE NOTHING WRONG.
I AM A LEGITIMATE BUSINESSMAN.
RIGHT.
IF BY BUSINESS, YOU MEAN RUNNING
AN ORGANIZED CRIME SYNDICATE.
[ LAUGHS ]
THE JUDGE PUT AWAY FOUR
OF YOUR CRONIES ON RICO CHARGES.
YOU FOUND OUT
SHE HAD A STALKER,
SO YOU THOUGHT YOU'D USE HIM AS
A PATSY TO GET A LITTLE PAYBACK.
ANY CRIMINAL AFFILIATIONS
I MAY HAVE HAD IN THE PAST --
THEY WERE MERELY
YOUTHFUL INDISCRETIONS.
I'M A REAL-ESTATE
INVESTOR NOW.
WAIT HERE A MOMENT,
MR. LONERGAN.
SURE.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
WE'VE GOT THE RIGHT GUY.
BUT THE WRONG MOTIVE.
Kate: THANK YOU FOR COMING IN,
MR. TRENT.
YOU MIND TELLING ME
WHAT I'M DOING HERE?
WE JUST WANTED YOU TO KNOW
THAT WE'VE APPREHENDED THE MAN
RESPONSIBLE
FOR YOUR WIFE'S MURDER.
YOU DIDN'T NEED TO
DRAG ME ALL THE WAY DOWNTOWN
TO TELL ME THAT.
I WAS INFORMED THE MINUTE THAT
BRADY McGRAW WAS IN CUSTODY.
Daniel:
BRADY'S INNOCENT.
YOU'VE GOT SOME GALL,
INTERRUPTING ME WHILE
I'M PLANNING MY WIFE'S FUNERAL
TO START THAT CRAP AGAIN.
Kate: WE DIDN'T MEAN TO
UPSET YOU, MR. TRENT.
WE JUST WANTED YOU TO KNOW
THAT IT WAS BOBBY LONERGAN
WHO ARRANGED
FOR YOUR WIFE'S DEATH.
WHO?
HE'S THE PRINCIPAL OWNER
OF KENMARE EQUITY GROUP.
ACCORDING TO
YOUR S.E.C. FILINGS,
KENMARE TOOK
A $2 MILLION DOLLAR STAKE
IN YOUR REAL-ESTATE COMPANY
LAST YEAR.
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
BUT I NEVER DEALT DIRECTLY
WITH THIS, UH, LONERGAN,
YOU SAY HIS NAME WAS?
YEAH, BUT, YOU SEE, REAL ESTATE
ISN'T THE ONLY BUSINESS
THAT MR. LONERGAN IS IN.
HE'S ALSO A SHOT-CALLER
FOR THE IRISH MOB,
THE SAME ORGANIZATION THAT
THREATENED YOUR WIFE LAST YEAR.
THEY KILLED HER?
I'M SORRY I BLAMED YOU.
I UNDERSTAND WHY YOU DID.
YOU FILED FOR BANKRUPTCY
LAST YEAR CORRECT?
YES, BUT I DON'T --
I DON'T SEE WHAT --
AND THEN YOU WITHDREW
THE PETITION
WHEN AFTER MR. LONERGAN
GAVE YOU THE $2 MIL.
I NEEDED A CAPITAL INFUSION,
AND I GOT ONE.
SURE, OF COURSE, BUT THE WEEK
AFTER HE MADE THE INVESTMENT,
MR. LONERGAN BOUGHT UP
A BUNCH OF THE WORTHLESS LAND
AROUND THE OLD
CABRINI-GREEN HOUSING PROJECT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT ANY OF THIS
HAS TO DO WITH MY WIFE'S DEATH.
RIGHT AFTER
LONERGAN BOUGHT THAT LAND,
YOUR WIFE MADE A RULING
THAT APPROVED THE REZONING
OF THAT LAND FOR COMMERCIAL USE.
LONERGAN
MADE MILLIONS OVERNIGHT.
WITH A LITTLE HELP
FROM YOU. LUCKY.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU TIPPED HIM OFF
ABOUT YOUR WIFE'S RULING.
THAT $2 MILLION WASN'T AN
INVESTMENT, IT WAS A KICKBACK.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
WE HAVE MR. LONERGAN
IN CUSTODY.
MURDER FOR HIRE
IS A DEATH-PENALTY OFFENSE.
NOW, ONE OF YOU'S GONNA
TURN STATE'S EVIDENCE.
THE OTHER'S
GONNA GET THE NEEDLE.
JUST DEPENDS
ON WHO TALKS FIRST.
[ SIGHS ]
ONE NIGHT,
AFTER A FEW GLASSES OF WINE,
KAREN TOLD ME
ABOUT A RULING SHE WAS MAKING
IN THE CABRINI-GREEN
REZONING APPEAL.
HMM.
AND THE NEXT MORNING,
SHE REALIZED
SHE HAD BEEN INDISCREET,
AND SHE ASKED ME
NOT TO TELL ANYONE.
BUT YOUR BUSINESS
WAS IN TROUBLE,
AND HERE WAS AN OPPORTUNITY
TO MAKE A LITTLE MONEY.
I HAD A DOZEN EMPLOYEES
WHO WERE GONNA LOSE THEIR JOB
IF I WENT UNDER.
SO I SOLD THE INFORMATION
TO LONERGAN.
I DIDN'T SEE
THE HARM IT WOULD DO.
BUT THEN YOUR WIFE WAS TAPPED
FOR SOLICITOR GENERAL.
AND IF I CAN FIND THE MONEY
TRAIL BETWEEN YOU AND LONERGAN,
IT CERTAINLY
WOULD HAVE COME UP
DURING THE
BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION
FOR YOUR WIFE'S
CONFIRMATION.
YOU GO TO JAIL,
AND HER CAREER WOULD BE RUINED.
LONERGAN CAME TO ME.
AND HE SAID THAT
I NEEDED TO TAKE CARE OF IT,
SO I WENT TO KAREN.
TURN DOWN THE NOMINATION.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WE GOT A GOOD LIFE
HERE IN CHICAGO.
IT'S SOLICITOR GENERAL,
DAVID.
I'VE WORKED MY WHOLE LIFE
FOR THIS.
Kate: DID YOU TELL HER WHY
YOU WANTED HER TO TURN IT DOWN?
I KNEW SHE COULD NEVER
LIVE WITH THE DISHONESTY,
AND THAT SHE WOULD WITHDRAW
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION
AND -- AND -- AND -- AND
TELL ME TO TURN MYSELF IN.
I DIDN'T WANT
HER CAREER DESTROYED.
SO YOU JUST HAD HER KILLED
INSTEAD?
NO! NO!
I NEVER WANTED THAT!
I WENT TO LONERGAN.
I NEED MORE TIME TO CONVINCE HER
TO TURN DOWN THE NOMINATION.
IT'S TOO LATE.
WE CAN'T RISK THIS COMING OUT,
DAVID.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT ELSE TO DO.
JUST NEED TO BE CREATIVE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
ALL JUDGES MAKE ENEMIES.
I'M SURE YOUR WIFE
HAS MORE THAN JUST A FEW.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I'M SAYING
SHE NEEDS TO GO.
THE ONLY QUESTION IS WHETHER SHE
GOES ALONE OR YOU GO WITH HER.
SO YOU TOLD HIM
ABOUT BRADY McGRAW.
YOU KNEW HIS DELUSIONS WOULD
MAKE HIM THE PERFECT FALL GUY.
I WANTED YOU
TO ARREST BRADY.
THAT WAY, LONERGAN'S PLAN
WOULDN'T WORK,
AND I'D HAVE HAD MORE TIME
TO CHANGE KAREN'S MIND.
Kate: AND THEN
WHEN THAT DIDN'T HAPPEN,
YOU REALIZED
YOU NEEDED AN ALIBI,
AND LONERGAN
GOT HIS STOOGE
TO LURE BRADY TO THE HOUSE
WITH THE CALLS.
IT WAS A GREAT PLAN.
AND IT WORKED OUT EVEN BETTER
THAN YOU COULD HAVE IMAGINED
WHEN THE POOR GUY ACTUALLY
CONFESSED TO THE MURDER.
IT WAS ALMOST
THE PERFECT CRIME.
Daniel:
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
I'M A LITTLE SCARED.
TO LEAVE THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN MAKE IT.
YOU WILL.
THANKS.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE.
ACTUALLY, I DO.
I WAS DIAGNOSED
WHEN I WAS 22.
SO YOU'RE ON MEDS, TOO?
THERE'S NO
ONE-SIZE-FITS-ALL TREATMENT.
BUT WORK HELPS.
AND, UH, FRIENDS.
THE PERSON I CARED ABOUT MOST
WASN'T EVEN REAL.
BUT I STILL MISS HER.
Max: HEY, DOC.
DEAN HALEY CALLED.
WANTED TO KNOW HOW
THE STOMACH FLU'S TREATING YOU.
TELL HIM
I'VE MADE A FULL RECOVERY.
I ALREADY DID.
YOU'VE GOT BACK-TO-BACK MAKE-UP
CLASSES STARTING AT 10:00
AND A FACULTY MEETING
OVER LUNCH.
OH, AND I PICKED UP
YOUR PRESCRIPTION.
IT'S RIGHT THERE
ON THE TABLE.
GOOD FOR YOU, DOC.
GOOD NIGHT, MAX.
AIN'T NO SUNSHINE
WHEN SHE'S GONE
IT'S NOT WARM
WHEN SHE'S AWAY
AIN'T NO SUNSHINE
WHEN SHE'S GONE
SHE'S ALWAYS GONE TOO LONG
ANYTIME SHE GOES AWAY
WONDER THIS TIME
WHERE SHE'S GONE
I WONDER
IF SHE'S GONE TO STAY