[ Equipment Beeping ]
- [ Metal Clanks ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Man ]
A real beauty, ain't she? Yes, sir.
Tell you what.
You buy this ship, treat her proper...
- she'll be with you for the rest of your life.
- [ Door Clanks Open ]
Well?
You paid money for this, sir?
On purpose?
Wha-- Come on, seriously, Zoe,
what do you think?
Honestly, sir?
I think you got robbed.
Robbed? Wha--
What do you mean?
- It's a piece of fei-oo.
- Fei-oo?
Uh, okay, she won't be winning
any beauty contests anytime soon...
but she is solid.
Ship like this, be with you
till the day you die.
- Because it's a death trap.
- That's not--
You are very much lacking
in imagination.
- I imagine that's so, sir.
- Come on. You haven't even seen most of it.
Let me show you the rest,
and try to see past what she is...
- and on to what she can be.
- What's that, sir?
- Freedom is what.
- I meant what's that?
Oh. Yeah,just step around that. I think
something must have been living in here.
I tell you, Zoe, we get a mechanic,
get her up and running again...
hire a good pilot, maybe a cook--
Live like real people.
A small crew-- They must feel the need
to be free. Take jobs as they come.
They never have to be under
the heel of nobody ever again.
No matter how long the arm
of the Alliance might get...
we'll just get ourselves
a little further.
- "Get her running again"?
- Yeah.
- So not running now?
- Not so much.
- Ah.
- But she will.
I already know what I'm gonna call her.
Got a name all picked out.
[ Grunts ]
[ Straining ]
[ Liquid Splashing ]
~ Take my love, take my land ~
~ Take me where I cannot stand ~
~ I don't care, I'm still free ~
~ You can't take the sky from me ~
~ Take me out to the black ~
~ Tell them I ain't comin'back ~
~ Burn the land and boil the sea ~
~ You can't take the sky from me ~
~ There's no place I can be ~
~ Since I've found serenity ~
~ But you can't take the sky from me ~~
[ Sniffling ]
[ Groans ]
[ Laughter ]
No!
[ Laughing ]
That is not true. No.
- [ Book ] I swear it is.
- [ Laughing Continues ]
[ Inara ]
Surely one of you must have told him.
No! Not one of the brethren
had the heart to say anything.
- He was so proud.
- [ Laughing Resumes ]
Of what?
What was he proud of?
Who he?
- Looked rather natty, truth be told, you know.
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- What was natty? I wanna
hear about the natty thing.
- Ah.
Shepherd Book was just
tellin'us funny stories...
about his life at the monastery.
- Monastic humor. I miss out on all the fun.
- [ Chuckling ]
And all the food too, apparently.
Just who do you think
you're married to, hmm?
- Voila! [ Laughs ]
- I love my wife.
- So we got a course set?
- We do.
Took a little creative navigating, but we
should make it all the way to Greenleaf...
without running afoul
of any Alliance patrols.
- Or a single living soul, for that matter.
- Good. Way it should be.
Course, what should be
an 18-hour trip's gonna take us...
the better part of a week
by this route.
Oh, we're in no rush.
I like an easy, languorous journey.
Oh, gee, I wonder
what that would be like.
Let me help you
with that.
- It's your turn.
- My turn?
Well, Shepherd told us
a funny story about being a preacher.
Now you tell us a funny story
about being a doctor.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Oh, a funny story.
Yeah, 'cause sick people
are "high-larious."
Well, they--
they can be. Uh--
[ Chuckles ] Well, uh,
in-in fact, I-I remember this time...
Uh, I was working the E.R.,
and this, uh, this, uh...
this fellow-- this, uh,
you know, upright sort of citizen...
he-he comes in and he's,
you know, complaining about--
Uh, Inara, she's gotta have
some funny whorin' stories, I'd wager.
[ Sarcastic Chuckle ]
Oh, do I ever.
Funny and sexy.
You have no idea.
- And you never will.
- [ Men Chuckling ]
I don't discuss my clients.
Aw, come on, Inara. Who'd know?
You. A Companion
doesn't kiss and tell.
So there is kissin'?
Hey, Doc, uh, I think Kaylee
may need your help after all.
Care to make
the first incision, Dr. Tam?
- [ All Chuckling ]
- Happy Birthday, Simon.
[ All Congratulating ]
- Whoo!
- This is, uh--
How did--
How'd you know?
- River, did you?
- "Day" is a vestigial mode...
of time measurement
based on solar cycles.
It's not applicable.
I didn't get you anything.
Seems a fresh warrant for your arrest
came up over the cortex.
Had your birth date
attached right to it.
- [ Inhales ] Really?
- I hope you like it.
Couldn't get ahold of no flour,
so it's mostly protein.
In fact, it's pretty much
what we just had for dinner.
- [ Laughing ]
- But I tried to get...
the frosting
as chocolatey-tasting as possible, so--
Thank you.
- I'm really, I'm very--
very deeply moved. Thank you.
- Well...
deeply move yourself to blow out
them candles, so we can try a slice.
- [ Laughing ]
- Come on, Doc. Give a good blow.
[ Rumbling, Whirring ]
- [ Accelerating Whir ]
- What the hell was that?
Maybe just a hiccup.
I'll go check it out.
- I'll take a look at the helm.
- Fire.
- Okay, right. [ Inhales ]
- [ Rumbling Resumes ]
- [ Cries Out ]
- [ Grunts, Groans ]
- Zoe!
- Fire.
Fire!
[ Alarm Wailing ]
Zoe, baby.
You've got to talk to me, baby.
Seal off everything that leads
below decks. Do it now.
[ Alarm Wailing,
Equipment Twittering ]
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Silence ]
- She gonna be okay?
- I need my med kit.
Not this way. We've got fire.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Zoe's been badly hurt.
- I need my medical supplies.
- Sorry, Doc, nobody leaves.
- Everything's sealed up tight.
- If you don't let me through, she could die.
I let you through, we all die.
[ Beeping, Whistling ]
- [ Klaxon Blares ]
- [ Steam Hissing ]
[ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Airlock Sealing ]
[ Klaxon Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Labored Breathing ]
[ Groans ]
- [ Wash ] It's okay. You're gonna be--
- She's going into shock.
- I need to bring her vitals back up.
- [ Mal ] How bad is it?
- She gonna be all right?
- There's no sign of burning.
It must be internal.
- I'll have to do a scan.
- Baby. Zoe, can you hear me?
Zoe.
Come on, sweetheart.
Zoe. Come on, talk, baby.
Look at me, sweet--
Kaylee.
Kaylee, look at me.
I need you up in the engine room
figurin' out what caused this.
She ain't movin'.
- Serenity's not movin'.
- I know it.
Which is why we need to suss out what it was
happened, so we can get her goin' again, right?
- Think you can do that?
- Yes, Captain.
That's a good girl.
Come on, baby. You're strong,
strongest person I ever met.
- You can do this!
- She gonna make it?
- Please. I need to work.
- Wash.
Wash, I need you on the bridge.
- Zoe's hurt.
- And the doctor is gonna do
everything he can.
Meantime, I got to have you on the bridge.
We need to know how bad it is.
How bad? It's bad, okay, sir?
My wife may be dying here,
so my feeling is it's pretty damn bad.
- Wash--
- I'm not leaving her side, Mal!
Don't ask me again.
I wasn't askin'.
I was tellin'.
[ Speaking Chinese ]
You're gonna get to that bridge,
and you're gonna get us back on our feet.
Yeah.
This is all very doable.
Shouldn't be a problem at all.
A few modifications. Get some
real maneuverability out of this boat.
- You'll be surprised.
- So you'll take the job then?
Might do, might do.
Think I'm startin' to get a feel here.
Good. Well, take your time.
Make yourself at home.
Just, uh, fiddle around
with the dials there. We'll be nearby.
- Great, ain't he?
- I don't like him.
- What?
- Just somethin' about him bothers me.
- What? What about him bothers you?
- I'm not sure.
- It's... somethin'.
- Well, your "somethin'" comes up against...
a list of recommendations
as long as my leg.
Tanaka raves about this guy.
Renshaw's been tryin'
to get him on his crew for a month.
- And we need us a pilot.
- I understand, sir. He bothers me.
Look, we finally got ourselves
a genius mechanic.
It's about time we hired someone
to fly this damn thing.
"Genius"? No one's
ever called me that before.
Shiny.
He just bothers me.
- [ Constant Tone ]
- Her heart stopped.
Maybe someone
should get her husband.
No.
What do you need, Doc?
Uh, that drawer. Right there.
- That's the one.
-[ Inara ] What is it?
- Pure adrenaline.
- [ Gasps, Weeps ]
[ Bellows ]
[ Exhales, Inhales Sharply ]
[ Rapid Breaths ]
[ Yells ]
[ Strained Groan ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
Cap?
Is Zoe gonna be okay?
You let the doctor worry about Zoe.
Come on.
Tell me what you know.
Catalyzer on the port compression coil blew.
It's where the trouble started.
Okay, I need that
in captain dummy-talk, Kaylee.
- We're dead in the water.
- Can you fix it?
- I could try.
- Ju-Just get us to limpin'. That's all I need.
- What? What is it?
- Well, it's worse than just the coil.
How can it be worse?
Main life support's down on account
of the engine being dead.
- Right. But we got auxiliary life support.
- No, we don't.
Ain't even on.
Explosion must've knocked it out.
- So what are we breathin'?
- Whatever got pumped into the atmo...
before the explosion
shut it all down.
Most of that oxygen got ate up
by the fire on its way out the door.
- Well, whatever's left is what we got.
- How long?
A couple of hours, maybe.
We'll start to feel it...
and then we won't feel
nothin'at all.
How is she?
She's still unconscious...
but her vitals are strong.
She won't know it, but as long as her condition
remains like this, she'll outlive us all.
She's using less oxygen.
[ Sighs ]
I always thought the name...
Serenity had...
a vaguely funereal sound to it.
I love this ship.
I have from
the first moment I saw it.
I just don't want to die on it.
I don't want to die at all.
Suffocation's not exactly
the most dignified way to go.
[ Inhales Deeply ]
The human body will--
Please, I don't really require
a clinical description right now.
I'm sorry.
I just, uh--
It was my birthday.
[ Sighs ]
Don't be afraid.
That's what it says:
"Don't be afraid."
Yes.
But you are afraid.
You're afraid we're
going to run out of air.
That we'll die gasping.
But we won't.
That's not going to happen.
We'll freeze to death first.
You get that beacon sent?
- Yeah, it's sent.
- Good.
- Pointless--
- What was that?
Nothing, sir. It's a brilliant plan.
I'm sure we'll all be saved.
I'm getting a little weary
of this attitude, Wash.
[ Chuckling ]
Are you? Well, I'm so very sorry, sir.
I guess the news that we're all gonna be purple
and bloated and fetal in a few hours...
- has made me a little snippy.
- It's possible someone might
pick up that signal.
No, Mal, it's not possible.
No one's gonna pick up the damn signal.
You wanted us flying under the radar,
remember? Well, that's where we are.
- Out of range of anyone or anything.
- Then make it go further.
- I-- What?
- Make the signal go further.
- I can't make it go further.
- Not if you sit around here
and whinge about it, no.
- What do you expect me to do?
- Whatever you have to.
And if you can't do it from here here,
then get a suit on and go outside and--
- And what? Wave my arms around?
- Wave your arms around.
Jump up and down.
Divert the navsats to the transmitter.
- Whatever.
- Divert the-- Right!
Because teenage pranks are fun
when you're about to die.
- It'd give the beacon a boost, wouldn't it?
- Yes, Mal.
It would boost the signal. But even if
some passerby did happen to receive...
- all it would do is muck up their navigation.
- Could be that's true.
Damn right it's true!
They'd be forced to stop...
and dig out our signal before
they could even go anyplace.
- Well, maybe I should do that then!
- Maybe you should!
- Okay!
- Good!
- Fine!
- Hey.
What do you two
think you're doin'?
Fightin' at a time like this.
You'll use up all the air.
- [ Alarm Blaring ]
- [ Woman Over P.A.] Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
[ Message Repeats In Chinese ]
Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
[ P.A. Continues, Indistinct ]
Bester?
- What's this I hear about yet another delay?
- [ Moaning, Grunting ]
Supposed to have this engine
fixed and us up and--
- What in the name of-- [ Speaking Chinese ]
- [ Grunting ]
Bester?
- [ Woman Moaning ]
- Bester.
- Bester!
- [ Clattering ]
- What?
- You do realize we've been
parked on this rock...
- a week longer than we planned?
- Yeah.
But, uh, there's--
there's stuff to do.
As for example that job
we got waiting for us on Pacquin.
When we landed, you said you needed
a few days to get us space-worthy again...
and is there something
wrong with your bunk?
Why?
Oh, no, Captain. She likes engines.
[ Whispers ] They make her hot.
[ Chuckles ]
Bester. Get your prairie harpy
off my boat and put us back in the air.
Okay, but c-can't.
- What do you mean, ''can't''?
- No can do, Cap.
- Secondary grav boot's shot.
- [ Kaylee ] No it ain't.
Ain't nothin' wrong with your grav boot.
Grav boot's just fine.
Hello.
She doesn't--
That's not what it-- No, it ain't.
Sure it is.
Grav boot ain't your trouble.
I seen the trouble plain as day when I was
down there on my back before.
Your reg couple's bad.
The red--
The what?
The reg couple.
Right here. See?
- No.
- This.
- I'm pointin' right at it.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Hey.
- Here.
Hand me that, will you?
Don't serve much of a purpose anyway.
Just tends to gum up
the works when it gets tacked.
So I figure why even have one?
Better to just take your G-line...
plug it straight
into the port pin-lock...
- and that should, uh--
- [ Motor Whirring ]
There.
- What'd you do?
- She fixed it.
- Well, it wasn't really broke.
- Where'd you learn how to do that, miss?
Just do it, that's all.
My daddy says I got natural talent.
- I'll say you do at that.
- Don't we need this?
- You work for your daddy?
- Well, when he got work.
Which ain't too often lately.
You got much experience
with a vessel like this?
I never even been up in one before.
- Wanna?
- You mean--
- Sure.
- For how long?
Long as you like.
Long as you can keep her in the sky.
- You offering me a job?
- Wh-What?
- Believe I just did.
- I just gotta ask my folks.
Don't leave without me.
Mal! What do you need
two mechanics for?
I really don't.
Kaylee?
Kaylee, what're you doing?
I'm sorry, Captain. I'm real sorry.
I should've kept better care of her.
Usually she lets me know
when somethin's wrong.
Maybe she did. I just wasn't
payin'attention or--
Kaylee, I cannot be having
this from you right now.
We got work to do.
Dong ma?
Catalyzer's broke.
Gonna need a new one.
There is no new one.
You gotta make do with what you got.
- It's broke.
- Come on.
This the part?
It don't hardly seem like nothin'.
All right. Where's it go?
Here. But it don't fit no more.
Well, you gotta figure
a way to make it fit.
Sometimes
a thing gets broke, can't be fixed.
Without this, engine don't turn?
Engine don't turn. Life support
won't function. We don't breathe.
You wanna keep breathin',
don't you?
So do I.
- [ Alarm Blaring ]
- [ Woman Over P.A.] Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
- [ Message Repeats In Chinese ]
- [ Shallow Breaths ]
- Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
- [ Metal Clanking ]
[ Message Repeats in Chinese ]
[ Part Clattering ]
Well, as you're all keenly aware...
we've run into a bit of a situation.
Engine's down, life support's
on the fritz, and I got...
nine people here
all wantin' to breathe.
Truth is...
ain't got a whole lot
of options at this juncture.
So...
instead of focusing on what we don't got,
time to talk about what it is we do.
And what we got
are two shuttles--
short range, won't go far.
But each got heat,
and they each got air.
Last longer than
what's left on Serenity.
- Long enough to reach someplace?
- No.
So, where will we go then?
Far as you can get.
We send both shuttles off
in opposite directions--
betters the chances of someone
getting seen, maybe picked up.
Shepherd Book, Kaylee, Jayne...
you'll ride with Inara in her shuttle.
Doc, you and your sis will ride
with Wash and Zoe, seeing as how...
Zoe still needs some doctorin'.
- What about you?
- Four people per shuttle.
That's the arrangement.
Evens the odds.
I'm staying with Serenity.
- Captain--
- We sent out a beacon.
Even managed to boost it a little.
If by some chance we get a response,
someone's gonna have to be here to answer.
Let's get those shuttles prepped.
Wash, shuttles are that way.
I know. But like you said,
someone might answer the beacon.
And when they do, I want to make
sure that you can call everyone back.
Won't take but a minute.
Jayne,you get shuttle number two ready.
I'll see to Inara's.
Friends, get movin'.
Take only what you need.
- Mal.
- If you fly smart, don't push too hard...
shuttle life support
should last you a good long while.
Mal, this isn't the ancient sea. You
don't have to go down with your ship!
She ain't goin' down.
She ain't goin' anywhere.
Jayne'll be worth something
if you run into trouble...
but don't trust him
and don't let him take over.
You're paid up through the end
of the month. It's still your ship.
- Mal.
- And as far as your security deposit goes...
that I might have to owe you.
Well, here she is.
- Nice, ain't she?
- Smallish.
Well, not overly.
How much room do you really need
for what you do anyway?
I got a surveyor and his wife
interested in renting it.
They're just waiting to hear back.
- What's her range?
- Standard short.
She'll break atmo
from a wide orbit...
get you where you need to go,
bring you back home again.
She's space-worthy,
just like the rest of Serenity is.
No need to sound
so defensive, Captain.
I prefer something
with a few miles on it.
Were we to enter into this
arrangement, Captain Reynolds...
there are a few things I would require from
you-- the foremost being complete autonomy.
The shuttle would be my home.
No crew member, including yourself...
- would be allowed entrance
without my express invitation.
- You'd get your privacy.
Andjust so we're clear, under no
circumstances will I be servicing you...
or anyone who is
under your employ.
- I'll post a sign.
- That won't be necessary.
The other thing I would insist upon
is some measure of assurance...
that when I make
an appointment with a client...
I'm in a position
to keep that appointment.
So far as such assurances
are possible on a vessel of this type.
That's an awful lot
of caveats and addendums there, miss.
As I stated,
I just want to be clear.
Well, I'll be sure to take all that into
consideration while I review the applications.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're gonna rent this shuttle to me.
- Am I?
- Yes.
And for one quarter less
than your asking price.
- Is that a fact?
- It is.
And you figure
you'll be getting this discount...
- why, exactly?
- You want me.
You want me on your ship.
- Do I?
- Yes.
Because I can bring
something that your surveyor...
or any of the other fish
you might have on-line can't--
- a certain respectability.
- Respecta--
And based on what little
I've seen of your operation...
I suspect that's
something you could use.
Fine.
Let me ask you this.
If you're so respectable,
why are you even here?
I mean, I've heard tell of
fancy ladies such as yourself...
shipping out with
big luxury liners and the like, but...
a registered Companion
on a boat like this?
- What are you running from?
- I'm not running from anything.
If it's Alliance trouble you got,
you might want to consider another ship.
Some on board here fought
for the independents.
The Alliance has
no quarrel with me.
- I supported unification.
- Did ya?
Well, I don't suppose
you're the only whore that did.
Oh, one further addendum.
That's the last time
you get to call me ''whore.''
Absolutely.
Never again.
Keep everything set as low as possible.
Don't waste what you got.
Let me do that.
You never could operate this thing.
- [ Switch Clicking ]
- [ Beeping, Whirring ]
And try not to talk.
Talking uses up air.
- Ain't no need for it.
- Mal!
Come with us.
Can't.
Four to a shuttle, Inara.
- Four.
- One more, you know
it can't make a difference.
- Not now.
- I'm not leaving Serenity.
Mal, you don't
have to die alone.
Everybody dies alone.
- Everything's set and ready.
- Good.
I linked the nav systems
of both shuttles into the helm here.
When your miracle gets here, you just pound
this button once. It'll call back both shuttles.
Go see to your wife.
I went ahead and closed off
all below-deck vents...
diverted what's left to the bridge.
Ain't much. My advice is seal off everything
tight behind you on your way back up.
Might buy you some time.
And I prepped a suit for you.
It's hanging in the foredeck.
- So when the time comes--
- I won't be needing it, but thanks.
Okay.
Well.
[ Shuttle Engines Whirring ]
[ Static Hissing ]
[ Man On Radio ] Firefly--
[ Indistinct ]
Receiv-- distress.
Firefly Serenity--
[ Garbled, Indistinct ]
[ Interference, Static ]
[ Static Hissing ]
I'm sorry for your troubles,
Captain. They sound many.
But you do understand,
I can't invite you aboard my vessel.
- I don't know you.
- I ain't askin' for a ride, Captain.
- Just a little push is all.
- Right. Your mechanical trouble.
- Your compression coil, you say?
- It was the catalyzer.
Not even the coil. Catalyzer's
a nothin'part, Captain.
It's nothin' till you don't got one,
then it appears to be everything.
Well, it is possible we might
have something that could do you.
We just come from a big salvage
mission off Ita Moon.
- I'd appreciate it.
- Trouble is...
how can I know for certain
your story's true?
Ambush could be waiting for me
and my people on the other side.
You can plainly see my shuttles
have been launched,just like I said.
And by now you've scanned me.
You know I've got no life support.
I don't expect to see
any weapons when we board.
And I do expect to see
that engine part before I open the door.
I feel like maybe
we can do business.
[ Air Rushing ]
[ Weapons Cocking ]
Check him. Search the ship.
Start with the cockpit
and work your way down.
- Is this what you meant by "ambush"?
- I'm just verifying your story.
You find anybody on board
not supposed to be, you shoot 'em.
I thought we were gonna
be reasonable about this.
Reason. He's gonna
talk to us about reason now.
[ Snickers ]
Yeah. That's a joke.
- Which one you figure tracked us?
- The ugly one, sir.
Could you be more specific?
- Do we look reasonable to you?
- Well, looks can be deceiving.
Not as deceiving
as a lowdown... dirty... deceiver.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Well said.
- Wasn't that well said, Zoe?
- Had a kind of poetry to it, sir.
You want I should
shoot 'em now, Marco?
Wait till they tell us
where they put the stuff.
That's a good idea.
Good idea.
Tell us where the stuff!s at,
so I can shoot ya.
Point of interest.
Offerin' to shoot us might not work so well
as an incentive as you might imagine.
Anyway, we've hidden it.
So, you kill us,
you'll never find it.
- Found you easy enough.
- Yeah, you did, didn't you?
How much they payin' you?
- Huh?
- I mean, let's say you did kill us...
or didn't,
there could be torture, whatever.
But somehow, you found the goods.
What would your cut be?
Seven percent, straight off the top.
Seven. Oh.
- What?
- Hmm? Nothin'.
Not a thing. No, I just--
- Does that seem low to you?
- It does, sir.
- That ain't low.
- Stop it!
- Seven percent's standard.
- [ Laughs ] Okay.
- Zoe. I'm payin' you too much.
- Why? What does she get?
- Knock it off.
- Look, forget I said anything.
I'm sure you're treated very well.
You get the perks, got your own room--
No?
You share a bunk?
- With that one.
- [ Chuckles ] Really.
- Jayne, this ain't funny.
- Yeah, I ain't laughin'.
You move on over to this side, we'll not only
show you where the stuff s at...
we'll see to it
you get your fair share.
- Not no sad seven.
- Private room?
- Jayne.
- Your own room, full run
of the kitchen-- whole shot.
Jayne, I ain't askin'.
[ Groaning ]
Shut up.
- [ Groaning Continues ]
- How big a room?
Ship's clear, Captain.
- You check the engine room?
- It's like he said, catalyzer's blown.
That's all he needs.
You know, anything that's worth anything
is really right here in this cargo bay.
So you take a look around,
decide what you think is fair.
Already decided.
- We're taking your ship.
- [ Labored Breathing ]
Billy, get this plugged in.
Jesse, call Stern over here.
You and him are gonna
pilot this pile of go-se out ofhere.
- [ Pistol Cocking ]
- We'll get it as far as--
Jesse, don't call Stern.
Billy, leave the catalyzer.
Do as he says.
[ Shuddering ]
Take your people and go.
You would've done the same.
We can already see I haven't.
Now get the hell off my ship.
[ Door Mechanism Whirring ]
-[ Klaxon Blaring ]
-[ Woman Over P.A., Speaking Chinese ]
Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
[ Message Repeats In Chinese ]
Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
[ Message Repeats in Chinese ]
- [ Grunting, Straining ]
- Life support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
[ Rapid Breathing ]
[ Accelerating Whir ]
[ Wheezing ]
[ Panting ]
[ Clattering ]
- [ Man ] Real beauty, ain't she?
- [ Kaylee ] Serenity's not moving.
- [ Inara ] Mal, come with us.
- [ Wash ] When your miracle gets here...
-pound this button once--
it'll call back both shuttles.
- Everybody dies alone.
- [ Wash ] I'll run up and scrape up a piece.
- [ Zoe ] You'd do that for me?
- I'd do anything for you. You know that.
- [ Muttering ]
[ Man ]
Oh,you're a pretty baby.
[ Inara ] I think it's something
he should see when he wakes up.
- [Jayne ] He's seen blood before, lots of it.
- Welcome back, sir.
[ Groggily ]
I go someplace?
Very nearly.
- I thought we lost you.
- I've been right here.
- Wash, you okay?
- Yeah, Mal, I'm fine.
- You got a thing in your arm.
- Yeah!
Try not to speak. You're heavily medicated,
and you lost a lot of blood.
[ Groans ]
I thought I ordered
you all off the ship?
- I call you back?
- No, Mal, you didn't.
I take full responsibility, Captain.
The decision saved your life.
- Won't happen again, sir.
- Good.
And thanks, I'm grateful.
It was my pleasure, sir.
Hey, we'd have been back first, except there's
somethin' wrong with Inara's shuttle.
She done somethin'to it, Mal.
It smells funny.
- I told you, that's incense.
- So you say.
- Hey, Captain.
- Hey.
You fixed the ship.
Good work.
- Thanks.
- All right.
I have to insist--
the captain needs to rest.
Yeah. I think the doc might
not be wrong about that one.
Just going to need a few--
You all gonna be here
when I wake up?
- We'll be here.
- Good.
That's good.
Yep. Real beauty, ain't she?
Yes sir, a right smart purchase, this vessel.
I'll tell you what.
You buy this ship, treat her proper...
she'll be with you
for the rest of your life.
Son? Hey, son!
[ Chuckles ]
You hear a word I've been sayin'?
Grr! Arrgh!
www.tvsubtitles.net