~ [ Woman Singing
In Foreign Language ]
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
Nandi! Nandi!
Get inside.
Go.
- We ain't open for business.
- Shut up, whore.
And you, we don't trade with
at all, Rance Burgess.
You're no longer welcome in this establishment.
You've been told that.
I've been told a great many things.
I'm here for what's mine.
Ain't nothin' here
belongs to you.
You don't get gone, we'll be
well within our rights to drop you.
The only rights you got
are the ones I give you.
- Find the girl!
- She ain't here.
Girl left this moon more than a month ago.
It was you chased her off.
[ Girl Screaming ]
Petaline!
It's a good thing
you haven't left with my baby.
- This baby ain't yours.
- So you keep saying.
- [ Gasps ]
- If this D.N.A. is a match...
with mine, know...
I will be back
for my baby.
- [ Whimpering ]
- And if I have to...
I'll cut it outta ya.
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, don't worry.
Shh. All right, now.
It'll all work out.
He'll do it too.
He'll do what he says.
- No, he won't. We won't allow it.
- How we gonna stop him, Nandi?
- We'll get help, that's how.
- Help?
There's not a soul on this moon
go up against Rance Burgess.
She's right.
Ain't nobody strong enough.
And even if there was,
who'd help us?
[ Cocks Gun ]
- [ Inara ] Hi.
- [ Yells ]
- Sorry. Didn't mean to startle.
- You didn't.
I was just, uh-- Bwahh.--
that's more like a--
It's a warrior-like--
Strikes fear into the hearts of--
You know, not altogether wise, sneakin' up
on a fella when he's handling his weapon.
I'm sure I've heard that said.
But perhaps the dining area...
- isn't the place for this sort of thing.
- What do you mean?
- It's the only place with a table big enough.
- Of course.
In that case...
every well-bred petty crook knows
that the small concealable weapons...
- always go to the far left of the place setting.
- [ Uncocks Gun ]
Got a distress call coming in.
Some folks asking for help.
Really? Folks asking for help
from us petty crooks.
- Well--
- Maybe I should take that right away.
Well, it's for her.
- Huh?
- The call's for Inara.
- I'll take it in my shuttle.
- All right. I'll send it back there to you.
This "distress" wouldn't happen to be
taking place in someone's pants, would it?
- [ Cocks Gun ]
- Bwahh.
~ Take my love, take my land ~
~ Take me where I cannot stand ~
~ I don't care, I'm still free ~
~ You can't take the sky from me ~
~ Take me out to the black ~
~ Tell them I ain't coming back ~
~ Burn the land and boil the sea ~
~ You can't take the sky from me ~
~ There's no place I can be ~
~ Since I've found serenity ~
~ But you can't take the sky from me ~
[ Nandi ]
And I got word you were in the area.
I'm imposing,
but I got no one else to ask.
It sounds like something
this crew can handle.
I can't guarantee they'll handle it
particularly well, but--
If they've got guns
and brains at all--
They've got guns.
Payment won't be a problem.
We just ain't equipped for this.
Nandi, it's gonna be all right.
The house will tell you
not to come.
I know they ordered you
to shun me when I left.
The house can-- [ Chinese ]
I would have waved you
long ago. It's just--
It doesn't matter.
[ Chuckles ] Who'd have thought
we'd both end up all the way out here?
- Who'd have thought?
- Let me know what your people say?
- Of course.
- I'll wait to hear from you.
- [ Speaking Chinese ]
- And you.
[ Monitor Beeps ]
I suppose you heard
most of that.
Only because
I was eavesdropping.
- Your friend sounds like she's in a peck of trouble.
- She is.
And there's no authority on that moon
she can go to. They're totally alone.
Some men might take
advantage of that.
One man.
And she's looking for someone
to come along and explain things to him?
That's essentially it, yes.
A whole house
full of Companions.
How are they fixed for payment?
They're not Companions.
They're whores.
Thought you didn't much care
for that word.
It applies. They're not registered
with the guild. They're--
- Independent?
- Yes.
If you agree to do this,
you'll be compensated.
I'll see to it.
I've put a little aside.
You can keep your money.
I won't be needing no payment.
Mal, thank you.
I'll contact Nandi at once.
But you will be paid.
I feel it's important that we keep
ours strictly a business arrangement.
- I'll speak with the crew.
- Good.
[ Zoe ]
Those who have a mind are welcome to join.
Those who'd just as soon stay
on the ship can do that too.
Hmm, don't much see the benefit
in gettin' involved...
in strangers' troubles without
a up-front price negotiated.
These people need assistance.
The benefit wouldn't necessarily be for you.
- That's what I'm saying.
- No one's gonna force you to go, Jayne.
As has been stated, this job
is strictly speculative.
Good. Don't know these folks.
Don't much care to.
- They're whores.
- I'm in.
Wash, plot a course.
- [Jayne ] That's the whorehouse?
- Yes.
How come it looks like
a frozen dinner pack?
[ Kaylee ]
Solar sheeting. Cheap power.
Hope the whores
are prettier than the house.
- Nandi, darling.
- It's so good to see you, mei-mei.
- You look wonderful.
- And you look exactly the same as the day I left.
- How do you do that out here?
- Sheer force of will.
- Nandi, this is Malcolm Reynolds.
- I appreciate your coming.
Well, any friend of Inara's is a strictly
businesslike relationship of mine.
This is my first mate, Zoe.
I'll introduce you to the rest later.
- They're good folk.
- Can I start getting sexed already?
- Well, that one's kind of horrific.
-[ Inara ] Can we talk business?
In here. The rest of you, there's food
and some liquor at the sideboard.
Make yourselves at home.
Look. They got boy whores.
Isn't that thoughtful?
I wonder if they service
girl folk at all?
- Let's not ask.
- Isn't there a pregnant woman I'm to examine?
[ Wash ] You'd really lie
with someone being paid for it?
Well, it's not like
anyone else is linin' up to...
- you know, examine me.
- [Jayne ] Whoo.
My John Thomas is about to pop off and fly
around the room, there's so much tasty in here.
Would be you'd get your most
poetical about your pecker.
- You'd be the doctor?
- Yes. This is Petaline.
- Yes, sir.
- She's feeling a might weak right now.
All right. Well, let's
get you lyin' down.
- Now that's a plan. Ooh!
- Shepherd?
No, thank you.
We were hoping
we might have a prayer meeting.
We ain't had one in months, except
what Emma here reads out on Sundays.
The last shepherd
to come by was springtime...
and he only read
the one passage.
And he took it out
in trade off both of us.
Everyone's got somebody.
Wash, tell me I'm pretty.
Were I unwed,
I would take you in a manly fashion.
- 'Cause I'm pretty?
- 'Cause you're pretty.
I take it reason
doesn't enter into this?
Not with Rance Burgess.
The man is a taker.
- You think the kid is his?
- I think it's Petaline's.
- But the blood test?
- Well, he did favor Petaline pretty exclusively.
But she had others.
Fifty-fifty, not that it matters.
The man ain't fit to raise a cactus plant.
His barren prairie shrew can't bear him an heir...
so he takes it into his head
to pull it outta us.
- That's not gonna happen.
- I see that's the case.
And you see the way we live here.
Go into town, it's the same.
Some places come up rustic 'cause
they ain't got more than the basics.
Rance Burgess has money enough
to build a city, a real community.
Keeps people living like this
so he can play cowboy.
Be the one with the best toys.
Turn this moon into a gorram theme park.
Someone stands up to him--
He means to burn me out.
Yeah, sounds like a fun guy.
I'd like to meet him.
- This won't be solved with talk.
- Well, I'm gonna fight a man,
it helps to size him up.
Well, he'll be at the theater tonight.
That's a certainty.
And so will I. Inara, think you can
stoop to bein' on my arm?
Will you wash it first?
[ Speaking Chinese ]
So, I told the boy, you take a clean
woman's virtue, you take the woman.
And that's for life.
And the boy said his vows right then.
- Took very little persuading on my part.
- [ All Laughing ]
[ Exaggerated Laughing ]
Oh, it's nice to know
there's some places left...
in the 'verse where
old-fashioned values still mean a thing.
- Isn't that right, dear?
- Hmm.
- I don't think I know you.
- Name's Malcolm. Malcolm Reynolds.
And might I just say,
she is quite a beauty.
Well, thank you. Ever had occasion
to handle one of these, Mr. Reynolds?
Silk trigger,
active return bolt laser.
Well, it's lighter than it looks.
Thought it would have more heft to it.
Oh, no, don't let that fool you. Won't find
technology like that short of Alliance.
And even their issues
don't yet have the auto-target adjust.
I had that crafted special.
Didn't think weapons
such as this were generally legal.
For private owner, I mean.
My husband makes a distinction between
legality and morality, Mr. Reynolds.
- I've said that myself.
- Bending one unjust law is a small thing...
when it comes
to protecting one's family.
I think I understand you.
And as you say,
she is a beauty.
She sure is. Of course,
I was referring to the lady. Ma'am.
[ Beeping ]
Yes.
- Well?
- Well what?
You said you wanted to look him in the eye.
You've done that.
- So, what's the plan?
- The plan is we get back to Serenity...
and we get off this rock
just as fast as we can.
And there can be
no mistake. Good.
- Rance?
- The D.N.A. matches.
The child is mine.
We run.
Math just don't add up.
Our weapons stores aren't exactly
overpowering at the moment...
and I don't much like
what we'd be up against.
Nothing worse than a monster
who thinks he's right with God.
Might turn Burgess away once,
but he'll keep comin'.
He won't stop till he gets
what he thinks is his.
- So we run.
- I understand, Captain Reynolds.
You have your people to think of,same as me.
And this ain't your fight.
I don't believe
you do understand, Nandi.
I said we run. We.
My people, your people...
and whatever bits of precious you got
in this house you can't bear to part with.
We load up Serenity,
and we leave Burgess in the dust.
Capt. Reynolds, it took me years to cut this
piece of territory out of other men's hands...
- to build this business up from nothing.
- Nandi.
It's who I am, and it's my home.
I'm not going anywhere.
He'll kill you. Kill every last one of them
if it comes to that.
- And he'll sleep well that night.
- Rance Burgess is just a man...
and I won't let any man
take what's mine.
I doubt you'd do different
in my position.
Well, lady, I must say...
you're my kind of stupid.
Oh, hell, he ain't expectin'
much of a fight.
Might be we catch him
with his drawers low.
He'll probably ride in
by daylight.
But I figure three-point watch,
say, four-hour shift...
just to be on the safe side.
Three point, four hour...
should do it.
- I'm fair handy with a hammer, Captain.
- That so, Shepherd?
Been following the footsteps
of a carpenter for some time now.
I think I can do something
about our fortifications.
Okay, then.
We start shootin'...
he'll most like try to burn us out,
save their sweat and bullets.
- Nandi, what's the water supply like here?
- Underground well.
Pump that draws it up is antiquated,
but it don't break down.
Kaylee, think you can swing
an upgrade for their waterworks?
I'll talk to Serenity,
see what she's got we might use.
- Good. We might wanna scrounge up--
- It's starting.
- And that it is, but time is on the enemy's side--
- Dr. Tan?
Oh, it's starting.
Okay, okay, it's starting.
All right, yeah.
Everybody, relax. Be calm.
Nobody panic.
Everything's gonna be okay. Be all right.
- I got this one, Captain.
- Thanks. Okay. Okay, then.
- [ Claps Hands ]
- Let's get to work, people.
[ Screaming ]
The girls and I
have been talking, Shepherd.
We've been discussing what we'd like said
over us if we should happen to fall.
No. I only bury
the dead, child.
No one here's gonna die.
There's people gonna die.
And with people dyin',
comes guts and screamin'.
That can bring on all sorts of screwed-up behavior
if a person ain't used to it.
When the time comes, most important thing,
keep your wits about you.
Clear?
All right.
Now, these are my favorites.
You're to keep them comin'
till there ain't no more to be had.
I shoot, I run out, you hand me
the next biggest one and so on.
- Is there an understanding here?
- Yes.
All righty, then.
Let's get to work.
All I'm saying is that we're living
pretty deep in the rough and tumble...
and I don't see that
changing anytime soon.
- Nor do I.
- Well, I'm not sure now is the best time...
to bring a tiny little
helpless person into our lives.
That excuse is getting
a little worn, honey.
It's not an excuse, dear.
It's subjective assessment.
I can't help
that it stays relevant.
I don't give a good go-around
about relevant, Wash, or objective.
And I ain't so afraid of losing something
that I ain't gonna try to have it.
You and I would make
one beautiful baby.
And I wanna meet
that child one day. Period.
- [ Gunshot ]
- [Jayne ] Nothin'. Y'all are pullin'...
not squeezin'
like I said.
Next one don't hit that board
is givin'up a special treat. Dong ma?
That man's gonna use up all our credit
before we've earned it.
Well, after you've saved our lives,
you can do some chores maybe.
- I'm a fair hand with a mop.
- So your legend tells.
Truth is, I expected a whole lot more of you
to be taking payment in our trade.
Well, we're not
a conglomeration.
Got a preacher, a married fella,
and the doctor--
Well, he'd have to relax
for 30 seconds to get his play.
That'd be more or less a miracle.
These are fetchin' little pieces.
Any of them work?
Oh, don't got many rounds for the chaplain
there, but the rest will be of use.
This is my favorite.
What's its history?
Violence and crime, sad to say.
What about you?
Similar.
No, I mean when are you planning
to avail yourself of some of our trade?
My girls is clean
and kind-spirited.
Well, I got the--
the job on my mind.
After, I'm sure I'll trade.
They're a fine bunch.
You ain't looked at one of them as long
or lovin' as you looked at those pistols.
You're not sly, are you?
'Cause I got my boys.
Sly? No.
I lean toward womenfolk.
Just... one thing at a time.
- Never liked complications.
- Oh, I'm certain of that.
Somethin' to be smilin' at?
I trained as a Companion, remember?
I read people pretty well.
Well, that's nice for you.
She's a hell of a woman,
ain't she? Inara.
Yeah, she's a cherry blossom.
No denyin'.
I expect you know her better than I do.
Comin' up together and all.
Imagine I do. She ever tell you
why she left Sihnon?
- Never asked.
- Yes, you did.
I don't know my own self.
I was gone long before.
And I'll tell you,
it was a shock, her leaving.
She was special.
There's 40 women in House Madrassa,
and you'd pick her out in a second.
Could have been house priestess
few years time.
- Is that right?
- Had her eyes on it too.
Very focused.
She's like you
more than a little.
And how exactly is that?
She hates complications.
They do crop up though,
don't they?
Such is life.
[ Exhales, Screams ]
No!
You're not completely dilated. This should be
pretty quick, but don't try to force it.
- The contractions are still preliminary.
- What's he saying?
- It's gonna be a little while, sweetie.
- Oh, but it hurts!
This child wants to be born.
I know it.
Can you get the green vial
from my bag?
We can dull the pain some.
How many babies
have you actually delivered?
As the primary?
This would be the first.
- You?
- My first too.
- Mine too.
- [ Petaline Groaning ]
- [ Groans ]
- It's gonna be a long night.
- You'll do great, Doctor.
- [ Groaning ]
Who do you think is in there?
It was the dulcimer.
The dulcimer drove you
out of Sihnon?
What, did you kill a dulcimer
in a terrible passion?
Actually, yes.
And now that dulcimer's family
is out to get even.
- I get it.
- [ Chuckles ]
I was at practice. You never stop practicing.
You know, not a true Companion.
Some baroque piece
and the instructor keeps saying...
"You're playing it,
not feeling it."
And the fifth time he said it, I took
the damn thing and smashed it into kindling.
- [ Laughs ]
- And that's when it occurred to me...
that a Companion's life might
just be a little too constricting.
So, I trucked out to the border,
learned to say "ain't,"
came to find work.
Found this place.
- It's a nice place.
- It was a dung heap...
run by a pig who had half the girls
strung out on drops.
There's no guild out here.
They let the men run the houses...
and they don't ask
for references.
We didn't get along.
And where's he at now?
Let's just say he ain't playing
the dulcimer anymore, either.
- [ Mal Chuckles ]
- [ Glasses Clink ]
Oh.
You are a remarkable woman...
you don't mind my saying.
Well, as long as it's you saying it
and not my fine rice wine.
Oh, it takes more than a few drinks
to render my judgment blurry.
What about you?
Am I gettin' any prettier?
By the minute.
I should check the barricades.
Make sure everyone's ready for--
Everyone's asleep.
Well, them as can...
night before a fight.
- Can you?
- What?
Sleep.
Um, Miss Nandi,
I have a confession to make.
Maybe I should get the shepherd.
Well, I ain't sinned yet.
I'd feel a little more than awkward
if he were here when I did.
You expect to accomplish
something sinful then, do you?
If I'm overstepping my bounds,
you let me know.
[ Speaking Chinese ]
Malcolm, I've been waiting for you
to kiss me since I showed you my guns.
You okay with this?
I'm just waiting to see
if I pass out.
Long story.
- I want you to bed me.
- I guess I mean to.
I ain't her.
Only people in this room
are you and me.
So, my child...
how long has it been
since your last confession?
- Longer than I care to say.
- You gonna remember where everything goes?
Let's just say
I plan to take it real slow.
So, the whore's got herself
a champion, has she?
This great man got a name?
Reynolds. Malcolm Reynolds.
Mm, yes. I've met the man.
How many has he got with him?
Just a few. And only
two real fighters besides hisself.
But they got the girls
stirrin'for a battle.
Oh. I certainly wasn't
expecting a battle.
[ Chuckles ] Seems the Heart of Gold's
got itself a few mercenaries.
- [ Men Laugh ]
- Guess we best call the whole thing off.
[ Chuckles ]
Earned yourself
quite a bag of silver, little kitten.
But I got a few more chores in mind
before you get it.
I'm ready.
Now, Chari here...
she understands
a whore's place, don't she?
But Nandi and those others,
they spit on our town.
They've no respect
for the sanctity of fatherhood...
or decency or family.
They have my child held hostage
to their decadent ways...
and that I will not abide.
We will show them what power is.
We will show them
what their position in this town is!
- [ Men Agreeing ]
- Let us all remember...
right here and now
what a woman is to a man.
[ Men Agreeing ]
Get on your knees.
[ Men Cheering, Whooping ]
- Um--
- Well--
I-I just had to
tell Nandi about...
um, about time to--
- Big fight today.
- Mal, please.
No, I-- No, I-- Well, I--
Uh, you know, I was up. I got I think insomnia.
So you took to bed
with Nandi. I'm glad.
- Glad?
- Yes.
She's a dear friend and probably
in need of some comfort about now.
- Well, uh--
- One of the virtues...
of not being puritanical about sex
is not feeling embarrassed afterwards.
You should look into it.
Well, I just didn't
want you thinkin'...
that I was taking advantage
of your friend.
She's well worth taking advantage of.
I sincerely hope you did.
So, you're okay.
Well, yeah, why--
why wouldn't you be?
I wouldn't say I'm entirely okay.
I'm a little appalled
at her taste.
[Jayne Sighs ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Mal On Radio ]
Wash,you there yet?
All but. Nice day
for a last stand, isn't it?
Nope. Plan to make
a healthy few stands after this one.
Just hoping for some air support
from your quarter, is all.
Couple of low flyovers,
engines tipped earthward at full blast.
Should give our guests somethin' other than
killin' you to think about.
[ Mal On Radio ]
What I like to hear. Out.
Malcolm seem a little funny
to you at breakfast this morning?
Come on, Kaylee.
We all know I'm the funny one.
You ladies and gentlemen
all locked and loaded?
- Locked and loaded. Got it.
- Yes, sir.
Good. Remember shoot the man,
not the horse.
A dead horse is cover.
A live horse, great pile of panic.
[Jayne On Radio ]
Oh, now, girl, that is just plain dirty.
Jayne, you are aware
your radio's transmittin'?
'Cause I don't feel particularly girlish
or dirty at the moment.
Oh. Ah, yeah,
just up here waiting, Captain.
Ready 100%.
[ Mal On Radio ]
Better be.
[ Screams ]
You're stronger than this thing, honey.
I can feel it in your grip.
Petaline, look at me.
This is just a moment in time.
- Step aside and let it happen.
- Mm-hmm.
- [ Groans ]
- How is she, Doctor?
She's at 10 centimeters.
Not long now.
[ Groaning ]
Inara, I thought
it was just him that--
Nandi, believe me, I'll be fine.
[ Petaline Groaning ]
[ Petaline Groans ]
[ Cocks Gun ]
Mornin'. How you doin'?
A mite tense.
I'd like you on the balcony with me.
You can see everyone there.
- If anything goes--
- You didn't give me the whole truth.
- About what?
- About her feelings for you.
- I really don't know what--
- [Jayne On Radio ] Mal, looks
like we got imminent violence.
Zoe, Jayne, you seein' this?
[Jayne On Radio ]
Gotta be 30 men out there.
[ Zoe On Radio ] Confirm that,
plus a mounted gun on that hovercraft.
[Jayne On Radio ]
What's that you said about runnin' for it?
Okay, folks, we got no shortage of ugly
ridin' in on us...
but that don't change the plan.
Anybody here goes down, you drag 'em
to the back and get back to shootin'.
Only way to help them
is to finish this.
[ Mal On Radio ] Wash, gonna be
trading injuries in under two minutes.
I'd like my sky
a little less empty.
- Copy that, Mal. We-- We--
- [ Gunshots ]
Open her up, Kozick!
- Cover!
- [ Gunfire ]
Jayne, I do believe that's our first hurdle.
Think you might--
[ Yells ]
- I think I might, Captain.
- Fire!
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Speaking Chinese ]
Go!
[ Mal On Radio ]
Wash, where the hell is my spaceship?
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Ruttin' lasers? Book! Zoe!
Second hurdle.
- [ Groans ]
- That's it, Petaline. One more push.
- [ Louder Groan ]
- That's the shoulders.
- [ Groans ]
- Good!
-[ Man ] Git. Git.
-[ Man Groaning ]
Jayne, I lost visual on Burgess.
[Jayne On Radio ]
Same here.
Take to right.
- Whoo-hoo!
- Hey. Hey. Get 'im.
Let's go.
Come on, let's get 'im.
- [ Laughs ]
- [ Man ] God!
Try the other side!
- Come on. Open up.
- Got you!
- You-- [ Chinese ]
- Open this door!
Nobody's going...
anywhere.
- It's--
- A boy. Healthy.
Good morning, Petaline.
How's my boy?
[ Crying ]
[ Petaline Screams ]
No.
Rance, most of your men
are either dead, dying or run off.
Oh, well, that don't matter none.
I got what I came here for.
Ain't leavin' here with it.
- This is my blood, woman.
- No, this is your blood.
Now,you hand that child over
nice and slow...
or I'll spill
more than you can spare.
[ Punch Lands ]
Hyah!
[ Gun Beeping ]
- You're gonna pay for what you took.
- She was just a whore.
Petaline, you bring
my baby out right now!
You hear me?
I wanna see my son.
Rance, this is Jonah.
- [Jonah Fussing ]
- Jonah, say hi to your daddy.
Say good-bye
to your daddy,Jonah.
Go on. Go on home!
You go with them.
[ Woman ]
~ Amazing grace ~
~ How sweet the sound ~
~ That saved ~
~ A wretch ~
~ Like me ~
~ I once was lost ~
~ But now am found ~
~ Was blind ~
~ But now I see ~
I think those girls
will do all right.
She taught them well.
Yeah.
I'm--
[ Clears Throat ]
I'm glad you were with her,
her last night.
- I am.
- Yeah, well, I ain't.
Hell, wish I never met her...
then I wouldn't have failed her.
That wasn't the way of it.
That's a kindness.
But nothing you say
will convince me different.
Well, I'm still glad.
So, you weren't before?
Inara.
I ain't lookin'
for anything from you.
I'm just, uh...
just feelin' kinda...
"truthsome" right now.
And, uh...
life's just too damn short
for ifs and maybes.
I learned something from Nandi.
Not just from what happened
but from her.
The family she made...
the strength of her love for them,
that's what kept them together.
When you live...
with that kind of strength...
you get tied to it.
You can't break away.
And you never want to.
There's something--
There's something I should
have done a long while ago.
And I'm sorry, for both of us,
that it took me this long.
I'm leaving.
Grr! Arrgh!
www.tvsubtitles.net