Didn't hardly have to convert
the ship, even.
Six in the corner.
Stronger locks, thicker doors. Keep
everybody where they're supposed to be.
Don't even need
more rations.
- [ Man ] Hey.
- [ Men Groaning ]
- Wait.
- Come on!
[ Moans ]
[ Groaning ]
- You made money, huh?
- Hand over fist, my friend.
Water planets need labor. Terra-forming
crews got a prodigious death rate.
Labor?
You mean, uh, slaves.
Well, they wasn't volunteers,
for damn sure.
That why you didn't have
to lay in more rations?
I didn't hear
no complaints.
[Jayne ]
How much money? Lots?
There's, uh, a chance you might
wanna head back to the ship.
I'm all right.
This is entertaining, actually.
- Yeah? What's entertaining?
- I like watching the game.
Plus the other situations.
The key seems to be...
- giving Jayne a heavy stick and standing back.
- Ha!
Still, might ought to clear out
before too much longer.
- Seems there's a thief about.
- Thief?
Yeah.
Took this right off him.
Now, they earned that with the sweat
of their slave-trading brows.
- Mal.
- Oh, terrible shame.
'Course, they won't discover it till
they go order their next round of drinks.
- Wei.
- Good drinker, that one.
Lovely place.
I'll tell my friends.
~ Take my love, take my land ~
~ Take me where
I cannot stand ~
~I don't care, I'm still free ~
~ You can't take the sky
from me ~
~ Take me out to the black ~
~ Tell them
I ain't comin'back ~
~ Burn the land
and boil the sea ~
~ You can't take the sky
from me ~
~ There's no place I can be ~
~ Since I've found serenity ~
~ But you can't
take the sky from me ~~
Seem to you we cleared out
of Santho in a hurry?
Seems to me
we do that a lot.
Heard tell, though,
we're gonna stay a while on Persephone.
- Shiny.
- Yeah?
Thought you get land crazy
that long in port.
Probably, but I've been sane
a long while now, and change is good.
Well, ain't that
a joyful sight.
- You gotta love a sunset.
- Startin' to get familiar too.
- Like a second home.
- Persephone ain't home.
Too many people we need to avoid.
Resupply...
look for work, move along.
We sniff the air.
We don't kiss the dirt.
Wasn't planning on
the dirt kissing, sir.
I wouldn't stand for it anyway, Captain,
jealous man like me.
- [ Beeping ]
- Closing in.
[ Zoe ]
Planet's coming up a might fast.
That's just 'cause
I'm goin' down too quick.
Likely crash and kill us all.
- Well, if that happens, let me know.
- Okay.
- Whoa! No, we're good.
- [ Rumbling ]
We're good. It's okay.
I understand your time
on our planet is limited...
and if you selected
my proposal to hear...
then the honor you do me
flatters my-- my honor.
And I hope--
Now there's the smile
made of sunlight.
Atherton.
How wonderful to see you.
Did you get my message?
I was extra appealing.
What a flattering invitation.
I had no idea I was arriving in time...
for the social event of the season.
So, you'll accompany me?
I ask, heart in my throat.
There's a certain offer
I'm still waiting to hear about.
- [ Knocking ]
- Yes, I imagine there is.
I'm delighted to say I'll be there.
- Now, I'm sorry, Atherton. I have to run.
- No, please. I understand.
I'll see you soon, baobei.
- Good afternoon, Captain.
- Morning.
We're downing in case
Wash don't kill us all.
Local time's gonna be in the a.m.,
10:00 or so.
Yes, I saw that.
Making plans?
Atherton Wing.
Now, he's a regular, ain't he?
- I've seen him before.
- Oh, I never did.
Not what I pictured. Young.
Must be rich too
to afford your rates.
I suppose.
He has engaged me for several days.
Days? One must have stamina.
Mmm. He does.
Well, fine.
Is he lettin'you out at all?
Actually, we're attending
a ball tomorrow night.
Tell me, do all the men there
pay for their dates...
or just young rich ones with stamina?
Most of the women there
will not be Companions...
if that's what you're asking.
Perhaps the other men
couldn't attract one.
Hmm. It sounds like...
the finest party I could imagine
gettin' paid to go to.
I don't suppose you'd find it up
to the standards of your outings.
More conversation and somewhat less petty
theft and getting hit with pool cues.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
I understand if you need
to go prepare...
for that
''It's 10:00 in the morning'' issue.
Yeah. Better go do that.
'Cause I think this is more
of, uh, an evening look.
Ooh. Look at the pretties!
What am I looking at,
the girls or the clothes?
- [Jayne ] The girls.
- The clothes, please.
Say, look at the fluffy one.
[ Zoe ]
Too much foofaraw.
If I'm gonna wear a dress,
I want something with some slink.
You want a slinky dress?
I can buy you a slinky dress.
Captain, can I have money
for a slinky dress?
- I'll chip in.
- I can hurt you.
The only place I seen something so nice
is some of the things Inara has.
Well, we'd best be movin'.
I guess she needs all that stuff,
the life she leads.
Well, sure. Sometimes the customers buy
her things. You know, some real rich men.
Come on. These ain't feathers
I'm totin' here, you know.
I like the ruffles.
Inara gets to wear whatever she wants.
What are you gonna do
in that rig?
Waltz around the engine room?
Be like a sheep walkin' on its hind legs.
[Jayne Laughs ]
See you on the ship, Captain.
Ohh.
What, is she mad or something?
[ Weapon Cocking, Whirring ]
- Badger.
- Captain Reynolds.
Heard you was in town. Thought
we might have a bit of a sit-down.
Prefer a bit of a "piss off."
I'm very sorry. Did I give you
the impression I was askin'?
Seems to me the last time there was
a chance for a little palaver...
we were all manner of unwelcome.
This ain't bad.
There's a trick to it.
Wood alcohol.
Now we're favored guests...
treated to the finest in beverages
that make you blind.
So what is it you need?
- Here. Excuse me.
- There's a local...
by the name of Warrick Harrow.
Got some property he wants
to sell off-planet. Fetch a high price.
The local powers
won't let him sell off-world.
It's a conundrum. What my man
Harrow needs himself is a smuggler.
- Willin' to cut you in on it.
- Why me?
You have access to ships.
You could do it yourself.
Won't deal with me direct.
He's takin' an irrational dislike.
What happened?
He see your face?
He's a quality gent.
Nose in the air like he never
[ Speaking Chinese ] .
Don't find me respectable.
But you--
You, I figure, got a chance.
You backed out of a deal last time,
left us hangin'.
- Hurt our feelings.
- You recall why that took place?
Had a problem
with your attitude is why.
Felt you was--
What's the word?
- Pretentious?
- Exactly.
You think you're better
than other people.
Just the ones I'm better than.
And now I'm thinkin'
that very quality...
is the one you're
placing value on today.
I place value on the fact
that stick up your pigu...
is about as large
as the one that Harrow's got.
How would you even set up a meet?
The man won't deal with you.
Know a place he'll be.
Safe place.
Usin' some new tech gun scans.
High class too. Won't let me in there.
You might slip in.
'Course, you couldn't buy an invite
with a diamond the size of a testicle.
I got my hands on a couple.
Of invites.
You want this meetin' or not?
- [ Chattering ]
- ~~[ Classical ]
Colonel Cyrus Mumsen and escort.
William and Lady Courtland.
Atherton Wing and Inara Serra.
Roberta, it's been too long.
[ Speaking Chinese ]
Half the men in this room
wish you were on their arm tonight.
Only half?
I must be losing...
my undefinable allure.
Oh, it's not that undefinable.
All of them wish
they were in your bed.
- I'm looking for the boy
with the shimmer wine.
- Oh, she blushes.
Not many in your line
of work do that.
You are a very singular woman,
and I find--
I find I admire you
more and more.
Kaylee. Kaylee.
I'm not speaking to you, Captain.
Got no need to speak.
Come on. Got a job for you.
~~[ Chamber ]
I'm trying to offer you something,
you know.
A life...
if you want it.
Atherton.
You can live here on Persephone
as my personal Companion.
You're a generous man.
That is not a yes.
It's not a no either.
You look gorgeous, dear.
You belong here, Inara,
not on a flying piece of go-se.
- You see that, don't you?
- Atherton, language.
What? Piece of go-se?
But it is a piece of go-se.
[ Man ]
Miss Kaywinnit Lee Frye and escort.
Kaylee?
Oh, go-se.
[ Mal ] Does, um--
Does this seem kind of tight?
It shows off your backside.
Did you see the chandelier?
It's hovering.
- What's the point of that, I wonder?
- Oh, mangos!
[ Mal ] I see how they did it.
I just ain't gettin'the why.
These girls have
the most beautiful dresses.
- And so do I. How about that?
- Yeah, well,just be careful.
We cheated Badger out of
good money to buy that frippery...
and you're supposed to
make me look respectable.
Yes, sir,
Captain Tight-pants.
Okay. I'm lookin'
for our guy Harrow.
And Inara. We should look for her, right?
Just to say hello at her.
Well, if we see her.
I think she's wearing gold.
Okay, help me find our man. He's
supposed to be older, kind of stocky.
- Wears a red sash crossways.
- Why does he do that?
Maybe he won the Miss Persephone
pageant.Just help me look.
Is that him?
That's the buffet table.
Well, how can we be sure
unless we question it?
Fine. Don't make yourself sick.
Xie-xie, Captain.
Ante up, gentlemen.
Dishes.
Dishes. Could do with less of them.
Garbage.
Tall card. Plum.
Plums are tall.
I'll take two.
Two.
- No tall card claim.
- Speakin' of garbage, I'll take three.
Three. Dealer forced
to claim the tall.
What do you suppose the captain
and Kaylee are doing now?
Septic vac.
Eatin'steaks off of plates
made of solid money, like as anything.
- I fold.
- [ Simon ] Me too.
- Tall cards 'round my neck like a weight.
- Take it, Shepherd.
Ah, that's a nice pile of things
I don't have to do.
It's the ones that'll take you.
They're the ones reaching and doing it.
- They're the ones keeping you--
- River?
- Is she hurt?
You'd better see to her.
That's a bad habit for a fugitive.
- Calm down.
- Do that in public, get herself hauled off.
- They're everywhere.
- Calm down.
- Hands go everywhere and [ Babbling ]--
- It's okay. Shh.
She didn't harm much.
We'll have a few mystery meals.
- Sometimes... afraid.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
And they come.
So are we gonna play cards
or screw around?
[ Moaning ]
Ahh.
I thought you wanted to spend
more time off-ship this visit.
Ohh.
Out there it seems like
it's all fancy parties.
- Mmm.
- I like our party better.
The dress code's easier,
and I know all the steps.
[ Chuckling ]
I'd say you do at that.
Oh.
- Mmm.
- Don't fall asleep now.
Sleepiness is weakness of character.
Ask anyone.
- It is not.
- You are acting captain.
Know what happens
if you fall asleep now?
Jayne slits my throat
and takes over.
- That's right.
- And we can't stop it.
Well, I wash my hands of it.
It's a hopeless case.
I'll read a nice poem at the funeral,
something with imagery.
You could lock the door and keep
the power-hungry maniac at bay.
I don't know. I'm starting
to like this poetry idea now.
Oh.
Here lies my beloved Zoe...
- my autumn flower.
- [ Slapping Flesh ]
Somewhat less attractive now that
she's all corpsified and gross.
[ Laughing ]
Oh, no!
~~[ Chamber ]
Aren't they something?
They're like butterflies or little pieces
of wrapping paper blowing around.
Hello.
Don't, um--
Have we been introduced?
Oh. I'm Kaylee.
Banning. And this is Dester,
Cabott and Zoe.
Don't you just love this party?
Everything's so fancy, and there's
some kind of hot cheese over there.
It's not as good as last year.
Oh, really?
What'd they have last year?
Standards.
Who made your dress, Kaylee?
Oh, do you like it? When I saw
the ruffles, I just couldn't resist.
You ought to see to your girl.
- Shu muh?
- Your girl.
She's not very good. She made you a dress
looks like you bought it in a store.
Oh. I didn't know.
Why, Banning Miller.
What a vision you are in your fine dress.
Must've taken a dozen slaves
a dozen days to get you into that getup.
'Course, your daddy tells me it takes
the space of a schoolboy's wink...
to get you out of it again.
Forgive my rudeness.
I cannot abide useless people.
Oh, no.
Thank you very much.
Beg your pardon,
but would you be Mr. Warrick Harrow?
Sir Warrick Harrow.
The sash.
The sash?
It indicates lord-hood.
And it's--
it's doing a great job.
Sir, my name's Malcom Reynolds.
I captain a ship named Serenity.
I mention this because
I've been led to understand...
-you want to move some property off-world.
- [ Inara ] Stop it.
[ Chuckling ]
Some property you want
to move off-world discreetly.
You're mistaken, sir.
I'm an honest man.
It seems to me
there's nothing dishonest...
about getting your goods
to people what need 'em.
Whom do you represent?
Represent isn't exactly the--
- Don't waste my time.
- Fellow called Badger.
I know him, and I think
he's a psychotic lowlife.
And I think calling him that is an insult
to the psychotic lowlife community.
But the deal is solid.
Sorry to interrupt. Sir Warrick,
I know you from the club, I believe.
Captain, this is Atherton Wing.
Atherton, Captain Mal Reynolds.
Pleased to meet ya. Inara, I didn't
realize you were going to this party.
- It's the only party.
- And I can see why.
How about that floating chandelier?
Almost outshines our girl here.
Ath-- Can I call you Ath?
Inara has spoken of you to me.
She made a point of your generosity.
Given that, I'm sure you won't mind
if I ask Inara the favor of a dance?
Of course.
- You're a brave man.
- I know what's mine.
This dance I think I actually know.
- Why are you here?
- Business. Same as you.
I was talking to a contact about a
smuggling job, and you came over to me.
- You were staring at me.
- I saw you is all.
You stand out.
In this company, Captain,
I believe you're the one who stands out.
Well, maybe I just want
to see a professional at work.
Is this the hardest part,
or does that come later?
You have no call trying
to make me ashamed of my job.
What I do is legal.
And how's that smuggling coming?
- My work's illegal, but at least it's honest.
- What?
Well, this-- the lie of it.
That man parading you around
on his arm as if he actually won you...
as if he loves you,
and everyone here going along with it.
These people like me,
and I like them.
- I like Atherton too, by the way.
- Well, sure.
What's not to like?
I'm liable to sleep with him myself.
And he likes me
whether you see it or not.
- Of course.
- He's made me an offer.
You may think he doesn't honor me,
but he wants me to live here.
I'd be his personal Companion.
I could belong here.
Call me pretentious,
but there is appeal in that.
You're right.
Got no call to stop you.
You've got the right
to a decent life.
- I see Kaylee's here.
- Cried Cinderella tears--
You should have seen her...
when I told her she could have
that layer cake she's wearing.
I think she looks adorable.
Yeah, but I never said it.
I'm not saying
the 80-04 is hard to repair.
- It just ain't worth it.
- It's a fine machine. You just keep it tuned.
[ Speaking Chinese ]
The extenders ain't braced.
I've been telling him
to buy an 80-10 for years.
Those 'tenders snap off, don't matter
how good the engine's cyclin'.
- Miss Kaylee, if I could request the honor--
- Wait a minute.
Let her talk.
She's talkin'.
By the way,
the 80-10's the same machine.
They just changed the plating,
hoped no one noticed.
[ All Laughing ]
Possible you're right.
This ain't my kind of party. Whoa, now.
Watch yourself.
No need for hands on.
Excuse me. She's not here with you,
Captain. She's mine.
Yours?
She don't belong to nobody.
Money changed hands,
which makes her mine tonight.
And no matter how you dress her up,
she's still--
- Turns out this is my kind of party.
- Oh, Mal.
What? The man was out of line.
- I accept.
- That's great. What?
- There has been a challenge.
- I hope you're prepared, Captain.
What, you all talkin' about a fight?
Well, that's fine.
- Let's get out of here.
- It's not a fistfight, Mal.
The duel will be met
tomorrow morning at Kaytree Pond.
Well, why wait?
Where's that guard?
He collected
a whole mess of pistols.
If you require it, any gentleman
here can give you use of a sword.
Use of a sw-- what?
- What's going on?
- I'm not rightly sure. What's going on?
Well, first off, you'll be put up in lodgings
for the night, so you don't disappear.
I wouldn't blame you, incidentally.
Wing may be a spoiled dandy,
but he's an expert swordsman.
He's killed a dozen men
with the long blade.
You're the only one
gave him a reason.
- Oh, this is a joke.
- [ Inara ] You'll need a second.
- What's that?
- I'll take on the job.
- He fights if you refuse.
Inara, come with me, please.
Now, you taking on this job...
being my second--
does this mean we're in business?
It means you're in mortal danger.
But you mussed up Atherton's face, and
that has endeared you to me somewhat.
You might even give him a fight...
before he guts you.
[ Atherton ]
Inara.
Up until the punching,
it was a real nice party.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Pounding ]
The captain's gone
and got himself in trouble.
- A duel?
- With swords?
The captain's a good fighter.
He must know how to handle a sword.
I think he knows
which end to hold.
All right, so wejust need to
figure out how to get him out of there.
We have until
the morning, correct?
- Do you know what lodging he's in?
- Oh!
This is embarrassing.
Some of you seem...
to be misapprehending
my purpose in being here.
You're here to make sure we don't
do what these men are keen on doing.
Penny for the smart lady.
Persephone's my home.
I gotta do business
with the people here.
I don't want it known I brought
someone in caused this kind of ruckus.
We'll just settle in
till this blows over...
- one way or the other.
- [ Weapon Cocking, Whirring ]
-Jayne, I wouldn't.
- Why not?
- [ Weapons Cocking ]
- Hi.
- Mal?
- [ Mal ] Whoa.
What are you doin' here?
Atherton's a heavy sleeper
night before a big day.
You know, he's got that killing
in the morning, then a haircut later.
Such a comfort having friends
visit at a time like this.
- [ Grunts ]
- I knew the accommodations would be nice.
Atherton doesn't skimp.
I don't suppose I like being kept
by him as much as others do.
So... how come
you're still attached to him?
Because it's my decision,
not yours.
Thought he made it pretty clear
he's got no regard for you.
You did manage to push him
into saying something, yes.
Made a nice justification
for the punch.
He insulted you. I hit him.
Seemed like the thing to do.
Why'd this get so complicated?
Well, it's about to get simpler.
There's a back door. The desk clerk
is on alert. He'll let us out.
Whoa, I'm not runnin' off. And I don't know
what you got in your head...
but I didn't do this to prove
some kind of point to you.
I actually thought I was defending your honor.
And I never back down from a fight.
Yes, you do.
You do all the time.
Well, yeah.
But I'm not backing down from this one.
He's an expert swordsman, Mal.
You had trouble with the pillar.
How will your death help my honor?
Well, see, I plan
on having it be his death.
That's why I need lessons.
I figure you know how,
bein' such an educated woman and all.
He said not to do anything.
He'll join us after he wins the duel.
[Jayne ]
And what if he don't win?
Doesn't hurt to have
a contingency plan, Kaylee.
I'm thinking since we're unarmed...
we should take them by surprise.
- All at once.
- [ Zoe ] Not necessarily.
We can lure one or two of'em away.
Say, infirmary.
Take 'em out, be on Badger
before he knows what happens.
[Jayne ]
Only if his attention is elsewhere.
What we need's a diversion.
I say Zoe gets naked.
- Nope.
- I could get naked.
- No!
- [ Zoe ] No.
- River, you can't be here.
- [ Indistinct ]
Come on!
- River! River, please.
- [ Badger ] Who's that, then?
Here, look at me.
What's your story, love?
She's just, uh--just a passenger.
Yeah? Why ain't she talkin'?
She got a secret?
- No, I'm--
- [ Cockney Accent ] Sure. I got a secret.
More than one.
Don't seem like that I tell 'em
to you now, do it?
Anyone off Titan colony knows better
than to talk to strangers.
You're talkin' loud enough
for the both of us, though, ain't ya?
I've met a dozen like you.
Skipped off-home early.
Minor graft jobs here and there.
Spent some time in the lockdown,
but less than you claim.
And you're, what, a petty thief
with delusions standing?
Sad little king of a sad little hill.
Nice to see someone
from the old homestead.
Not really.
Call me if anyone interesting
shows up.
I like her.
That there-- exactly the kind
of diversion we could've used.
Attack.
- [ Groans ]
- How did I avoid that?
By being fast like a freak?
No. Because you always
attack the same way...
swinging from the shoulder
like you're chopping wood.
You have to thrust with the point
sometimes or-or swing from the elbow.
- Swinging from the shoulder feels stronger.
- It's also slower, Mal.
You don't need strength
as much as speed.
We're fragile creatures.
It takes less than a pound
of pressure to cut skin.
You know that?
They teach you that in whore academy?
You have a strange sense
of nobility, Captain.
You'll lay a man out for implying I'm a whore,
but you keep calling me one to my face.
I might not show respect
to your job, but he didn't respect you.
That's the difference.
Inara, he doesn't even see you.
Well, I guess death will solve
the issue to everyone's satisfaction.
This [ Chinese ] duel is the result
of the rules of your society, not mine.
You are always breaking the rules,
no matter what society you're in.
You don't get along
with ordinary criminals either...
which is why you are constantly
getting in trouble.
You think following the rules
will buy you a nice life...
even if the rules make you a slave.
Don't take his offer.
What?
Don't do it.
Just in the case that it happens,
that means that he's the fellow who killed me...
and I don't like fellows
who kill me, not in general.
I said before that I didn't have call
to stop you, and that's true.
Anyways, don't.
I need to get back.
He'll be up early.
Right. He's got that big day.
Best be careful, Ath.
You know, these things are sharp.
- He thinks he's doing well, doesn't he?
- He's being toyed with.
- What's he doing?
- Don't fall for that!
Well, this isn't going
to take long, is it?
We're coming up on the end, miss.
You might not want to watch.
Atherton, wait!
I'll stay here, exclusive to you.
Just let him live.
[ Man ]
He's down.
You have to finish it, lad.
You have to finish it.
For a man to lay beaten and yet
breathing, it makes him a coward.
- It's humiliation.
- Sure.
It would be humiliating...
having to lie there while the better man
refuses to spill your blood.
Mercy is the mark of a great man.
- [ Groans ]
- Guess I'm just a good man.
- Well, I'm all right.
- [ Drops Sword ]
- [ Groaning ]
Inara? Inara!
You've lost her, lad.
Be gracious.
You set this up, whore...
after I bought and paid for you.
I should've uglied you up,
so no one else would want you.
See how I'm not punching him?
I think I've grown.
Well, get ready to starve.
I'll see to it
you never work again.
Actually, that's not how it works.
You see, you've earned yourself
a black mark in the client registry.
No Companion is going
to contract with you ever again.
You'll have to rely on your winning
personality to get women. God help you.
[ Groans ]
Ow, ow.
You didn't have
to wound that man.
Yeah, I know.
It was just funny.
You willing to fight that hard
to protect my property...
I'll have it in your hold
before midnight.
Mighty fine shindig.
Doc's filling the shepherd in
on the plan.
We're ready to move on your signal.
Doc is the diversion.
Did you ever see such a lazy crew?
- Captain!
- You're hurt.
- You get us a deal?
- I got a deal. Now get off my ship.
So, very much for
a lovely night then.
[ Whistles ]
- Ow!
- Are you badly hurt?
[ Groans ]
We was just about
to spring into action, Captain.
Complicated escape and rescue op.
I was gonna watch.
It was very exciting.
~~ [ Humming ]
~~ [ Classical ]
Thank you for the wine.
It's... very fresh.
To Kaylee and her inter-engine
fermentation system.
- Are you in pain?
- Absolutely.
- I got stabbed, you know, right here.
- I saw.
Don't care much for fancy parties.
- Too rough.
- It wasn't entirely a disaster.
- I got stabbed, right here.
- You also lined up exciting new crime.
It's good to have cargo.
Makes us a target for every other
scavenger out there, of course...
- but sometimes that's fun too.
- [ Chuckles ]
I am grateful, you know,
for the ill-conceived...
and highhanded attempt to defend
my honor, although I didn't want you to.
Gracious as that is...
as I look back... I probably should've
stayed out of your world.
My world?
If it is that.
I wasn't gonna stay, you know.
Yeah? Why's that?
Oh, someone needs to keep
Kaylee out of trouble.
And all my things are here.
Besides, why would I want
to leave serenity?
Can't think of a reason.
[ Lowing ]
Grr! Arrgh!
www.tvsubtitles.net