[twangy music]
# I'm going down to South Park #
# Gonna have myself a time #
All: # Friendly faces
everywhere #
# Humble folks
without temptation #
# Going down to South Park #
# Gonna leave my woes behind #
# Ample parking day or night #
# People spouting:
"Howdy neighbor." #
# Headed on up to South Park #
# Gonna see if I can't unwind #
[singing indistinctly]
# So come on down
to South Park #
# And meet some
friends of mine #
Hey, Stan, did you see that
rainbow this morning?
Yeah, it was huge.
Ugh, I hate those things.
Nobody hates rainbows.
Yeah, what's there to hate
about rainbows?
Well, you know, you'll just
be sitting there
minding your own business, and
they'll come marching in
and crawl up your leg and
start biting
the inside of your ass.
And you'll be all like, "Hey,
get out of my ass, you stupid
rainbows."
Cartman, what the hell are
you talking about?
I'm talking about rainbows.
I hate those friggin' things.
Rainbows are those arches of
color
that show up during a rainstorm.
Oh, rainbows.
Oh, yeah, I like those.
Those are cool.
What were you talking about?
Heh? Oh, nothing. Forget it.
No, what marches in, crawls
up your leg...
Nothing.
And bites the inside
of your ass?
Nothing.
Children, children, remember
the Save Our Fragile Planet
essay contest that you
children worked
so hard on last month?
One of our very own South Park
students has won
the national prize.
[all gasp]
Wow, I knew I would win.
Gosh, Mr. Garrison, this sure
is exciting.
That's right, Mr. Hat.
The winner of the national
Save Our Fragile Planet
contest is... Eric Cartman.
What?
Congratulations, Eric, on
writing
the award-winning paper.
Kick ass.
That's impossible.
Cartman doesn't know a rain
forest from a Pop-Tart.
Yeah, I do.
Pop-Tarts are frosted.
Out of over a million papers,
Eric's was chosen as the
grand prize winner.
Wow, what did you write
about, Cartman?
Oh, you know, this and that.
He doesn't even know
what he wrote about.
What was your paper about,
Wendy?
My paper was on the suffering
of bottle-nosed dolphins.
Well, you see, you shouldn't
have written
a paper about dolphins.
Dolphins are stupid.
Dude, dolphins are, like, the
second-smartest animal
on the planet.
[scoffs] Oh, right.
If they're so damn smart,
how come they get caught
in those fishing nets all the
time?
What?
Wait, wait, there's more.
It says here that Eric's trophy
will be presented to him by...
Kathie Lee Gifford?
Kathie Lee is coming to South
Park?
And the presentation will be
on national television.
Both: Television?
Kathie Lee Gifford.
I don't believe it.
Kathie Lee Gifford in South
Park.
Oh, my God.
This is our chance to make a
name for ourselves, to show
that we're not some pissant,
white-bread mountain town.
Better yet, it's a chance for
you to get some publicity.
Yes, if I can show just how
much I've turned South Park
around, I could become a
senator.
Maybe even a state senator.
Mayor, we should decorate the
town square.
Then we should have the chef
of the school cafeteria sing
a song and play up the ethnic
diversity of our town.
That's right.
He's a black guy, isn't he?
Black as the night itself,
Mayor.
Yes, and we can even have the
children of South Park
put on a little play.
Kathie Lee loves children.
If they're working in a
sweatshop, that is.
Oh!
Ouch.
[laughs]
Thank you.
You guys, guess what.
After I'm on television,
I'm gonna be totally famous.
Hitler was famous too.
Hello there, children.
Both: Hey, Chef.
How are my little crackers
today?
Good.
Did y'all hear about the news?
Kathie Lee Gifford is
coming to South Park.
Yeah, 'cause Cartman cheated
and won
the environmental essay contest.
Hey!
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
But the mayor just called and
asked me
to sing at the ceremony.
Wow, are you gonna do it?
Of course.
Kathie Lee is a beautiful,
sultry queen of sexual fantasy.
And if I sing to her, maybe I
can lure her into
a night of exotic delectation.
Yeah, that'd be cool.
[mumbling indistinctly]
Well, three times bigger than
Frank Gifford's, anyway.
Oh, I can't even concentrate
on grading papers
with all this excitement.
Why are you looking at me like
that, Mr. Hat?
Have you forgotten about all
the pain and suffering
that Kathie Lee Gifford caused
you?
Mr. Hat, that was a long time
ago, and...
And I was only a child.
We could've won that
talent show.
We could've been huge.
Knock-knock, Mr. Hat.
Who's there?
Orange.
Orange who?
Orange you glad
I didn't say banana?
Thank you.
Wow, Mr. Hat, looks like we
might win.
And now, our last talent show
finalist, Kathie Lee Epstein.
# If they could see me now,
that little gang of mine #
# I'm eating fancy chow
and drinking fancy wine #
# I'd like those stumble bums
to see for a fact #
# The kind of top-drawer
first-rate chums I attract #
# All I can say is wowee,
look at where I am #
# Tonight I landed pow
right in a pot of jam #
# What a setup, holy cow,
they'd never believe it #
# If my friends
could see me now #
[fireworks booming]
[cheers and applause]
It wasn't fair.
She had choreography.
How could we compete with that?
But now she's coming to
South Park,
and I know a way to
make it all better.
How?
[gasps]
No, Mr. Hat.
I couldn't...
kill Kathie Lee Gifford.
Children, as you all know,
Ms. Kathie Lee Gifford will be
in South Park to present
the award to some kid for an
essay.
That kid is me.
Whatever.
Now, I'm going to have you
luscious little youngsters
do a play about the history of
South Park.
That'll be wonderful, won't
it, Mr. Hat?
Kill her. Mr. Hat.
Mr. Garrison, I'm asking you
to direct our little play.
Oh, that's perfect.
You see, Mr. Hat, we don't have
to kill her.
We can just upstage her.
Mrs. Mayor,
you might want to
review the essays.
We think Cartman might
have cheated.
Who cares?
Now, kids, what's say we give
it our South Park best?
And who's
our little prizewinner again?
Me, Eric Cartman.
How about we get in shape, huh?
We want to look our best for
the TV cameras, don't we?
Yes, ma'am.
# I'm gonna be on television #
We don't believe for a
minute that you won that
contest fairly, fat boy.
Ugh, stop defending your
little girlfriend
for writing about
some stupid fish.
Dude, dolphins are
intelligent and friendly.
Intelligent and friendly on
rye bread with some mayonnaise.
Dolphins are way smarter
than you.
If they're so smart, why do
they live in igloos?
Dolphins don't live in igloos.
That's Eskimos.
Dolphins, Eskimos, who cares?
It's all a bunch of
tree-hugging hippie crap.
Tell me what you wrote about.
I can't.
I have to go home and get
in shape.
Yeah, right.
You'll go and sit in front
of the TV
and eat Cheesy Poofs,
ass-master.
Screw you, hippie.
We'll be right back to
"Jesus and Pals" after this.
Hey, do you need to get in
shape fast?
Wanna look your best?
Tired of the other guys
getting all the chicks?
Are you tired of
being a 90-pound weakling?
Yeah, I only weigh 90 pounds.
Then bulk up quick with
Weight Gain 4000.
Yes.
Over 4,000 grams
of saturated fat per serving,
its patented formula is designed
to enter the mouth and go
directly to the stomach,
where it is distributed to the
bloodstream.
Now available at stores
everywhere.
Get some today, and say it
with me, "Beefcake."
Beefcake.
Beefcake!
May cause irreversible damage
to the kidneys and liver.
Mom, can you get me some
Weight Gain 4000?
Okay, Eric, I'll get you some
at the store tomorrow.
But, Mom, I need it for
tomorrow.
But tomorrow is
grocery day, Eric.
Mom.
[whining]
Okay, okay.
Well, I guess I'll be going
to the store now, then.
# If they could see me now,
that little gang of mine #
# I'm eating fancy chow
and drinking... #
No! No!
Kill her.
No, Mr. Hat. I won't do it.
Kill.
That does it.
You're going in the
dresser drawer, Mr. Hat.
She'll make a fool of you again.
Well, you can just stay in that
drawer, negative Nancy.
Hey, dudes.
What the hell is wrong with
you, Cartman?
Haven't you noticed the
three feet of snow
on the ground?
Listen, I have a nice body,
and I want to show it off.
You got that?
What?
You've got to weigh 90 pounds.
I'm up to 94, thank
you very much.
[mumbling indistinctly]
Yeah, they're almost as big
as his mom's.
[laughter]
Laugh all you want.
I'll the one who's gonna be on
TV looking all buff.
What's that stuff?
Weight Gain 4000.
It's helping me bulk up.
Bulk up to what, fat-ass?
Super fat-ass?
Hey, I don't have to take
that kind of crap
from you scrawny weaklings.
[grunting]
Sweet, check me out.
I'm such a beefcake I can't
get through the door.
Come on, people.
We've got to turn
this place around.
Hang up the lights, string up
the banners,
castrate the cows.
[cows mooing]
Well, Mr. Garrison, how is the
little play going?
Huh? Oh, fine.
We were just about to
run it from the top.
Oh, please do.
I'm dying to see it.
Okay, all the little pioneers
on this side of the stage.
Good, and all the little Indians
go to the center of the stage.
Am I an Indian or a pioneer?
Do you have a feather on your
head?
Yes.
Then you're an Indian.
Oh.
Okay, Bebe, this is your line.
This is the story of South Park.
It begins over 100 years ago
when the noble and hearty Ute
Indians lived on the land.
[drums thumping]
Oh, don't they look adorable?
Then from the East came the
great white pioneers.
[together]
Ahh!
Oh, my God.
They did it
a lot better this morning.
They had more energy.
The pioneers met with the
Indians
and negotiated for
their fertile lands.
Mr. Garrison, we cannot have
our children
beating each other senseless
in front of Kathie Lee Gifford.
Well, what do you want?
This is how it happened
in those days.
Take that, you stupid Indian.
Ohh.
Mr. Garrison, this is not
appropriate.
Do you actually think that
Kathie Lee Gifford
would enjoy this?
To hell with Kathie Lee Gifford.
[all gasp]
[gasps]
Oh, my God. What have I said?
He said, "To hell with Kathie
Lee Gifford."
Mr. Garrison, I am dismissing
you from directing our play.
[crickets chirping]
It happened again, didn't it?
Now we do things my way.
I can't kill her, Mr. Hat.
You're gonna have to do it.
[cackling]
Whoa, Cartman, talk
about wide load.
Yeah, I'm really starting to
fill out nicely.
You're not filling out nicely.
You're fatter than ever.
I'm not fat.
I'm getting in shape.
Cartman, you're such a
fat-ass that when you walk
down the street, people go,
"God damn it.
That's a big fat-ass."
No, they don't, you
jealous weakling.
God damn,
that's a big fat-ass.
Hey!
Hi, guys.
Oh, look, another hippie.
Peace, Wendy.
Shut up, Cartman.
Oh.
# Two little hippies
sitting in a tree #
I'm gonna find Cartman's paper
and get to the bottom of this.
Can I help you?
Yes.
I need a gun.
Would this be for hunting or
protection or other?
Other.
Alrighty then.
May I suggest a Stratford
12-millimeter?
Go ahead.
Try it on.
That looks really nice on you.
The lacquered black
really matches your eyes.
You talking to me?
I don't know,
it's a little small.
Okay.
How about this?
You talking to me?
Hmm, no, I don't like this one
either.
Here's the same gun
with a wood finish.
You talking to me?
I don't see anybody else
around here,
so you must be talking to me.
I'll take it.
Hello?
"My essay, by Eric Cartman.
"When I wrote the following
pages,
"or rather the bulk of them,
I lived alone in the
woods on the shore of..."
[door clicks open]
Well, Mr. Hat, I guess old
Kathie Lee really will be
surprised when she gets here
tomorrow.
She beat us in the talent
show all those years ago.
And I think we owe her for that.
Ba-bang!
Oh, my God.
[upbeat twangy music]
##
Howdy, Mr. Garrison.
Nice gun.
Thank you.
Nice gun, Mr. Garrison.
Thanks.
Hello, Officer Barbrady.
Nice gun.
Thanks.
Is there somewhere in town
where I can get a good,
clear shot... or a view of Kathie
Lee?
Hmm, you know, I think the
book depository
would be a good bet.
[dramatic music]
Yes, that might do quite nicely.
Thank you, Officer Barbrady.
No problem.
Ha! Caught you red-handed!
No pictures of Kathie Lee.
Where is she?
This is sweet.
Camera crews are setting up,
and I'm looking totally ripped.
Beefcake. Beefcake!
I don't think they're gonna
be able to get
all of you in frame, Cartman.
You guys, we have to stop him.
Stop who?
Mr. Garrison.
He's going to try to
kill Kathie Lee Gifford.
Oh, no, you don't.
You're not gonna ruin my
moment of fame.
He's got a gun.
You gotta get over this whole
jealousy thing, all right?
Seriously, just face it.
I wrote a better paper than you.
It just so happens that I
have your paper,
and I know why you won.
There's something more
important right now.
Let's go.
Wendy, you've got to prioritize.
What's more important, being
on TV
or some stupid assassination?
Stan, I can't do it alone.
Please?
Uh-oh, we're losing him.
Here she comes.
[upbeat music]
##
Damn, I guess I'm not the
only person in America
who's thought of
killing Kathie Lee Gifford.
We love you, Kathie Lee.
I love you too.
Come on, you little bitch.
You've got to come out of your
precious bubble
sooner or later, missy.
It is with great pride and
honor that I'd like to welcome
Mrs. Kathie Lee Gifford to
South Park.
[cheers and applause]
And now our very own
South Park Elementary chef
will sing a special song in
honor of Mrs. Lee Gifford.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
You know, Kathie Lee, you are
a very special woman.
I don't mean special in a Mary
Tyler Moore way
or special in an extra-value
meal at Happy Burger way.
No, no, no, no, no.
I mean special,
like the song of the
hummingbird as it gets ready
to find that female hummingbird
and make sweet love to it all
night long.
Just two hummingbirds moaning
and groaning and
letting their bodies caress
and touch each other in ecstasy.
# Oh Kathie Lee #
# How I'd love to lay you down #
# And lick every inch
of your body #
# With my tongue #
What?
# Kathie Lee
you're my sexual fantasy #
What?
# How about you and me #
Thank you, Chef,
for that heartwarming song.
# Get it together
and make sweet love? #
Thank you, Chef.
Oh, oh.
God bless you, Kathie Lee.
Officer Barbrady,
Mr. Garrison is about to kill
Kathie Lee.
We have to find him.
What?
You mean the teacher?
Wait a minute.
Is there somewhere in town
where I can get a good, clear
shot...
Or a view of Kathie Lee?
Hmm, you know, I think the
book depository
would be a good bet.
I think the book depository
Book depository, depository,
book depository, depository.
Damn, he could be anywhere.
I'll send out an APB.
Wendy, look.
And now, here to
present the award
for the environmental essay to
our own Eric Kaufman...
Cartman, God damn it.
Is your favorite celebrity
and mine,
Kathie Lee Gifford.
[grunts]
Thank you.
I love you all.
Mr. Garrison, stop.
Leave us.
We must finish what
we have begun.
I know that she's hurt you.
She's hurt a lot of people.
You can't know.
You should've won
that talent show.
It is with a great honor and
pride that I present
the winner this trophy.
Eric, would you please come
up here?
Here it is, my big
moment of fame.
And then she finished it
all by throwing her voice
with two dummies at once.
I know that, Mr. Garrison,
but this isn't the answer.
It is too late for
me, young Wendy.
You see, I've learned
something today.
You can't win all the time.
And if you don't win, you
certainly can't hold it against
the person who did, because
that's the only way
you ever really lose.
You're... you're right.
Good.
Man, did she really throw her
voice with two dummies at once?
The bitch must die.
Ahh!
[gunshot]
[mumbles indistinctly]
Oh, my God.
They killed Kenny.
You bastard.
Gun!
Hey, come back.
We didn't even get to do
our play.
All: Aww.
I guess that's it, guys.
Wrap it up.
Hey, wait a minute.
When do I get to be on
television?
Forget it, kid.
No Kathie Lee, no
public interest.
But I won the environmental
essay contest.
You don't
deserve to win, Cartman,
and you know it.
I'm holding Cartman's
award-winning paper.
It's actually nothing more
than "Walden"
with Henry David Thoreau's
name crossed out
and Cartman's
name written in its place.
Who cares?
Yeah, Kathie Lee Gifford's gone.
What about not holding
anything against
the person who wins?
Well, not if it's Cartman.
Hey, where are you all going?
They don't even know what
"Walden" is.
I bet if "Walden" was a sitcom
you'd all know what it was.
Come on, Wendy.
Kyle's mom will make us
tuna fish sandwiches.
Oh, what the hell.
[sobbing] No, no.
Now I'll be stuck in
this Podunk town forever
with all these stupid, hick,
redneck, jobless,
truck-driving idiots.
Uh, Mayor, the mic is on.
Thought you could get
away with it, eh, Mr. Hat?
Well, I would have gotten
away with it
if it weren't
for those meddling kids.
You're lucky you missed
Kathie Lee Gifford
and that nobody got hurt.
We hope you can come
back to school real soon,
Mr. Garrison.
Well, children, I'd love to,
but the doctors say
that Mr. Hat needs more
therapy.
We can still get her.
I'm just so sorry that I ruined
everyone's chances
for being on TV.
Not Cartman.
He gets to be on TV anyway.
Really? On what?
Obesity, adiposity, corpulence.
Whatever word you use, it
represents one thing:
being a big fat-ass.
We have with us today live via
satellite Eric Cartman
from South Park,
who is now so obese, he can't
even get out of his house.
When is this gonna be on the
air?
Is there anything you'd like
to say to people out there?
Follow your dreams.
You can reach your goals.
I'm living proof.
Beefcake. Beefcake!
He needs to run his ass
around the block a few times.
Mmm, how about a little more
of that good loving, Chef?
Damn, woman.
I just gave you sweet
loving five minutes ago.
You trying to kill me?